<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>(Un)Happiness on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/unhappiness/</link><description>Recent content in (Un)Happiness on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/unhappiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Big Thing Being Bedridden with the Flu for a Week Made Me Realize</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:56:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past 7 days, my life was consumed by the flu. Technically, I was more couch-ridden than bedridden, but I was decidedly &lt;em>horizontal&lt;/em>. Luckily, I had a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bs61eifhyh-/">faithful guardian&lt;/a> who didn’t leave my side, so I survived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first time I’ve had the flu in as long as I can remember. I don’t get sick often. The last time I was even “take a day off work” sick was over a year ago (and I don’t even have to get a doctor’s note to call in — I have &lt;a href="https://patreon.com/killermann">lenient bosses&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday, as I was catching up on the &lt;a href="https://www.nbc.com/saturday-night-live/video/january-26-james-mcavoy/3867402">SNL I missed&lt;/a>, I realized I didn’t get most of the jokes because I hadn’t been keeping up with politics or the news (or even trying).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, something else hit me, as I started to dive back into work and catch up with life, that I can attribute entirely to the flu:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breaking the Chain of “Maybe”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a modern scourge upon us, and every get-together, plan, and social event is vulnerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know when it started, who’s to blame, or if it can be defeated, but I’ve begun vaccinating myself against it. And if you or your social circle have caught a case of the &lt;em>Maybes&lt;/em>, or you want to prevent an outbreak, here’s what you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step with any epidemic is understanding the problem: What is the Maybes, how does it spread, and why is it harmful?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Flowchart Will Change Your Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</guid><description>Hahaha — oh headlines. But seriously. You need no flowchart beyond this flowchart. View. Share. Love. Life.</description></item><item><title>My Guitar is My Pacifier. What’s yours?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 05:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, I wake up spooning my guitar. This comforts me, then I realize I could have destroyed it so it terrifies me, then I realize I didn’t destroy it so I’m comforted again. It’s a roller coaster. Other days, my guitar is the first thing I reach for in the morning. I’m still rubbing sleepies out of my eyes while I fingerpick a few notes and think about what I’m going to do with my day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I’m having a tumultuous day, or I’m feeling particularly down, or I feel like the world is broken, or if I run out of hummus ingredients, I’ll pick it up, pick some strings, and it will immediately pick me up. Sometimes I only need a few minutes, sometimes I need a couple of hours, but it always works. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guitar is my pacifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Should Watch the Movie “About Time”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 05:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hadn’t really heard much about &lt;em>About Time&lt;/em>, the newest Love-Actually-Notting-Hill-Brit-Rom-Com-warm-fuzzy delight. And, to be honest, while I love watching feel-good movies (because they, you know, make me &lt;a href="http://samkillermann.wpengine.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/" title="If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier">feel good&lt;/a>), I don’t generally have high expectations for them. They tend to be rather empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one is not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>The 3 Ingredients to a Happy Existence</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intentionality, Mindfulness, and Minimalism are all you need, beyond basic biological requirements (clean water, nutritious food, human touch, etc.), to live a happy existence. This is what I’ve come to believe. I’ll define what I mean by all three, and talk about their relationship to one another, but first I want to talk about “happiness.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t aspire toward being happy all the time, nor do I recommend it. I don’t think of happiness as existing at the opposite end of sadness, nor do I think that sadness is inherently bad. All emotions have value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think of happiness on a continuum with lack of happiness on the other end, sadness on a continuum with lack of sadness on the other end, and so forth. Experiencing happiness doesn’t necessarily make you less sad — The Barenaked Ladies kew this: “I’m the kind of guy who laughs at a funeral.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>