<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Update on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in Update on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>After 7 Years Doing this Work, I’m [Re-] Branding. Here’s how I’m making decisions.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got thrown into this. Two-fold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got thrown into the work I’ve been doing. And I got thrown into a situation that’s led me to question everything, rethink and restructure, and make decisions that feel like an overall “brand.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’m happy I’m here, one of the strongest forces that’s guiding what I do next is precisely avoiding how I got here: no more being thrown into stuff. Seem easy? Maybe. Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll get to that in a second, but first the back story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016, A Brief Review of Creativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 02:08:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 was, well, _quite _the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, I side with what appears to be the consensus that it was, if given only one descriptor, a dumpster fire. That said, it was also more than a dumpster fire, and I want to take a moment to reflect on some of the things I made this year — something I basically never do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that said, following is what I finished, published, and/or created in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet FacilitatingXYZ: A Free Online Resource for ALL Facilitators</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 13:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</guid><description>&lt;address>
&lt;strong>Updated September 12, 2016:&lt;/strong>&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;officially launched this project, after about 11 months in development, production, and ideation. Woohoo!
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz">FacilitatingXYZ&lt;/a> is everything I wish I had when I got started as a facilitator — and &lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz/manifesto">together&lt;/a>, we can build it into something that helps us continue to learn, develop, and grow. It’s a free online resource with videos, articles, downloads and (soon!) community to help all facilitators improve their craft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do, Reflect, Tweak, Do: From Thought/Day to Dear World</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first started this project several months ago, I was &lt;a href="http://samkillermann.wpengine.com/welcome/" title="Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day">pretty clear&lt;/a> about what my goal was with the writing here: in short, nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted a space to explore new ideas, to reflect, to write, to share, but without any particular “goal.” So much of the writing I do is extremely goal-oriented. I wanted to see what would happen if I created a space that was less structured. I wasn’t sure what I’d end up writing about, what shape this site would take, and was happy to follow my fingers on an adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was fun. I wrote a lot of things I’d’ve never written otherwise, found that I have thoughts about seemingly random things that others find value in reading. I only got a few pieces of hatemail compared to a pile of encouragemail — this was new. I started with only one real rule, but I broke it after about 100 days. I was planning on writing once a day, and when I started traveling a lot at the beginning of this year, I missed one day. And that’s the funny thing about &lt;a href="http://samkillermann.wpengine.com/protecting-good-habits/">habits&lt;/a> — one missed day is alarmingly similar to one missed month, then you’re only a hop &amp;amp; skip away from a &lt;em>never happening again ever.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After missing a few days, I experienced stress related to this project that I hadn’t experienced, and decided that it was time to take a break from it, reflect, and see if it still has a healthy place in my life. I’ve done that now, and I’m happy to say that it does. &lt;em>Kinda.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gone is &lt;em>Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day&lt;/em>. Welcome _Dear World, _a much more fitting title for what’s going to be happening here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50 Thoughts, New Site, Checking in on What I’ve Learned</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 05:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</guid><description>This will be my fifty-first post on this site. It’s been a fun fifty-one days of this experiment.
When I set out on this adventure I was hoping to accomplish several things, a couple in particular: to learn more about myself and get the ideas that rattle around in my head out into words.</description></item><item><title>2.5 Weeks and 15,000 Words in, How Am I Feeling About Thought / Day?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 05:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</guid><description>I’ve written a lot in these past few weeks of this new experiment. When I launched this site I shared a few of my reasons why, but I have also been aware from the start that I really didn’t know where this project would go, and I still don’t.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 19:26:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I created this because it’s been a long time coming, and I decided to stop letting time slip away.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People have asked again and again if I have a personal blog. I do not. Well, I _did _not. I do now. And I will keep it up for at least one year. 365 days. 12 months. And probably about 500,000 words.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>