<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Obstacles on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/obstacles/</link><description>Recent content in Obstacles on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:08:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/obstacles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Can Stop Saying “They Should Make A…”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something I see all the time on the internet is people saying “They should have a…” or “They should make a…” and then sharing some idea, platform, service, movement, or cause that the commenter wants, and believes “they” should create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, this made sense. The request was legitimate and necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were gatekeepers in every industry — from arts to activism to commerce to community-building — who were the “They.” It was They who had to approve our appeal to create a new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You couldn’t just make that thing, or build that platform, or create that movement, release that show, or host that community yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You needed Their permission. You needed Them to make it for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protecting Good Habits</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 05:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</guid><description>We’ve heard it a million times: “old habits die hard.” But that’s not true. Truly, “bad habits die hard.” I can attest to this, using this Thought/Day project as an example.
Up until last week, I was 81 for 81 days in a row of writing and publishing a thought each day.</description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>