<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reflection on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/reflection/</link><description>Recent content in Reflection on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:23:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Waking up in Nong Pladuk (on my way home to the US)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/waking-up-in-nong-pladuk-on-my-way-home-to-the-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/waking-up-in-nong-pladuk-on-my-way-home-to-the-us/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s 9am and a woman wearing an apron is leaning over me yelling in Thai, waking me up from a nap with an urgency no alarm clock could match. I’m panicked, not sure for a moment where I am, or what I did wrong, or maybe if I’m covered in spiders (millions of spiders?!) until I notice she’s hawking food — a tray of a dozen small, folded banana leaf bowls full of shrimp, fried noodles, and a few indiscernible vegetables — and I’m not about to die. There are zero spiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Mai,” I manage to grunt as I squint my eyes in the morning sun, one of the few Thai words I have on the tip of my tongue. &lt;em>No thank you&lt;/em>, my eyes say. And also, &lt;em>maybe don’t wake up a belleagured traveler by yelling in his face next time if you want him to buy your stuff?&lt;/em> I collect my bearings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The train is stopped in Nong Pladuk Junction. Steamy air fills the rail car. Nong Pladuk is the starting station of the infamous Thai-Burma railway, more commonly known as “Death Railway.” It stretches from here to Nanchanaburi, the town a few hours down the road from which I am returning to Bangkok. Nearly one-hundred thousand prisoners of war and forced laborers had their lives forfeited to the construction of the Thai-Burma back in the 1940s. It’s a dark place to wake up to on a sunny Monday morning. It plucks at the melancholy I’m feeling in my heart.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>