<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wondering on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/wondering/</link><description>Recent content in Wondering on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/wondering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Living in the Undefined</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</guid><description>It’s in our nature to define things. We like boxes, categories. A few thousand years ago, this was incredibly helpful. Don’t eat things that look like this: you will die. Eat things that look like this: they are delicious.
But nowadays, I find that my compulsion to define things is incredibly unhelpful.</description></item><item><title>I Miss Wondering</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier tonight, I turned the burner on high and while I was waiting for my rice to come to a full boil I had a thought: “I wonder if rice cooked in beer would be good.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, I would have likely wondered that for quite a while. It may have been on my mind while I ate my boring water-based rice. It may have popped into my mind tomorrow, or the next day, when I next saw rice or beer. Visions of beer-based rice recipes might have danced in my belly. I may have wondered about it for a week (or ten) before I finally giving in, cooking it, and exiting Wonderland for Knowville.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of that happened, because Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the water (boring) in the pot began boiling I already knew if “beer rice” was a thing, what it would taste like (delicious), exactly how to make it, and what types of recipes it would be good in (ALL OF THEM).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>