<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reflecting on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/reflecting/</link><description>Recent content in Reflecting on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/reflecting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overthinking Everything So You Don’t Have To</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a confession to make: I’m an Overthinker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ve always been this way, but my condition has worsened with age. And my chosen profession didn’t help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I overthink as a matter of work, often. And I always overthink my work. Not just the things I make themselves, but how to describe what I do, and what unites it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately, I’ve come to think that the best way to describe my job is “overthinking everything so you don’t have to.” That’s no surprise, I’m sure, if you’ve popped around this site, or read &lt;a href="https://www.indiebound.org/search/book?keys=author%3AKillermann%2C%20Sam">my books&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://samuelkillermann.com">seen anything else I’ve made&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, ironically, I’m also driven, fundamentally, to empower people to _not _need me, via my work. I always endeavor to remove myself from the picture. Making myself irrelevant is one of my primary goals in everything I make, and it’s often the question that leads to the improvements or further work: “How can I create something that is freely available to prevent a person from needing to hire me to do it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why, for example, I released my copyright on my work back in 2013: I didn’t want people to have to keep asking me to use it, license it, or reprint it. I removed myself from the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this creates a bit of a conundrum. No surprise: me finding a conundrum. That’s Overthinking 101.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been [over-]thinking about that conundrum a lot. And I’ve felt a growing urge to reconcile it, which brings us here. To the how-to I never suspected I would write: A list of ways that I overthink everything, for those of you who want to DIY (OIY?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is the process I generally follow as I overthink everything in my life and work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I apply it to everything I create, to the social justice and human rights advocacy I engage in, to how I organize and operate on a “business” level, and even to how I do things in my “personal” life (relationships, puppy training, cooking, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the not-so-secret sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I suggest you proceed with caution. Overthinking is addictive. &lt;em>I wonder why that is.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016, A Brief Review of Creativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 02:08:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 was, well, _quite _the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, I side with what appears to be the consensus that it was, if given only one descriptor, a dumpster fire. That said, it was also more than a dumpster fire, and I want to take a moment to reflect on some of the things I made this year — something I basically never do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that said, following is what I finished, published, and/or created in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Publishing A Book</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m writing from a rooftop in Austin, taking a break from my break — which was part Naomi Klein and part Real Ale — to share a reflection that just sunk in: I’m about to publish my first book, and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to be clear: this isn’t me publishing the first book I wrote (that happened a couple years ago, and still hasn’t sunk in); this is me, under the auspices of &lt;a href="http://impetus.pw">Impetus Books&lt;/a>, publishing my first book someone else wrote (in this case, I’m glowingly happy to say that someone else is Karen Rayne).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I Miss About Grad School</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 06:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</guid><description>Earlier tonight, my friend texted me “I’m over this whole constantly chasing the homework train business.”
She was talking about grad school, and sharing a sentiment I shared back when I was earning my master’s. But, a bit to my surprise, I replied, “I miss grad school.</description></item><item><title>I’m Not Going To Teach You Anything New</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 05:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</guid><description>That’s something one of my professors in grad school would lead off with in the first class of the semester. The class was about the effect of environments on people’s ability to learn, develop, and grow. After sixteen weeks, hours of discussion, papers, and reading an entire textbook, he was right.</description></item><item><title>Scrapping and Starting Fresh: The Hawthorne Effect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 05:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</guid><description>A couple months ago I ventured into the land of the podcast. A couple weeks ago I roped my friend Ian in and “Thought of the Week” became “The Hawthorne Effect.” The whole thing has been a huge learning process. After doing a number of different podcast approaches by myself, and trying a few different things out with Ian, he and I sat down tonight to reflect on what we think has worked, what hasn’t, and set a clear plan for what we’ll do in the future.</description></item><item><title>Why I’ve Never Been a Fan of “Self Help” Books</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 05:37:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</guid><description>I’ve only ever read one, maybe two, “self help” books (depending on how strict your definition is). Not for me. And I wouldn’t want to foist them on anyone else. Might seem odd, considering what I write here. That’s one of the reasons I’ve been so reluctant to write about the things I write about here: because I don’t like the idea of “self help” coming from another person.</description></item><item><title>The Three Rs of Saw Sharpening</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 04:48:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</guid><description>As I mentioned a couple days ago, I’ve got a bit of a break before I head back on the road for my next gig. This is important time for me, because it’s the time that I set aside every year to sharpen my saw.</description></item><item><title>The Most Wild Year of My Life Ended in One Moment</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-my-year-ended/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 04:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-my-year-ended/</guid><description>Earlier tonight I gave the opening keynote for the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference. It was an hour that I’ve spent the last 6 months mulling, refining, trashing, rebuilding, trashing, reconceiving, and then, tonight, finally talking. I’ve never given a talk like that — not even close.</description></item></channel></rss>