<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 23:34:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Hadn’t Funded My Work with Patreon</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 23:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</guid><description>&lt;p>For several years, my “day job” (the one paying my bills) has been performing comedy shows. Meanwhile, my hobby has been creating online resources, tools, and organizations for justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that’s a weird combo, you’re not alone. I’m with you: it’s hard to wrap my mind around the truth that the way I make money is comedy, then I use that money to &lt;em>pay to&lt;/em> do administrative-paperwork-email-non-profit-type stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, it’s the other way around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What’s even weirder? Switching things up — and starting to fund my online advocacy work directly, not via comedy shows — seems less likely to succeed than continuing to be a working comedian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes — I’ve heard of &lt;a href="https://patreon.com">Patreon&lt;/a>. People have told me about it hundreds of times, for years and years, every time I made that point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of the work I do is a great fit for Patreon. But I’ve been resistant to the idea of funding it that way. The reasons are a mix of ethics and personal discomforts, and are all tied directly to my work, and the change I hope it effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why haven’t I done it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You’re Not “Self-Employed”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past almost-decade, I’ve checked the “self-employed” box lots of times: when opening bank accounts, on lease applications for apartments, and it’s how the IRS sees me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s a lie. I’m not “self-employed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>After 7 Years Doing this Work, I’m [Re-] Branding. Here’s how I’m making decisions.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got thrown into this. Two-fold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got thrown into the work I’ve been doing. And I got thrown into a situation that’s led me to question everything, rethink and restructure, and make decisions that feel like an overall “brand.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’m happy I’m here, one of the strongest forces that’s guiding what I do next is precisely avoiding how I got here: no more being thrown into stuff. Seem easy? Maybe. Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll get to that in a second, but first the back story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016, A Brief Review of Creativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 02:08:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 was, well, _quite _the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, I side with what appears to be the consensus that it was, if given only one descriptor, a dumpster fire. That said, it was also more than a dumpster fire, and I want to take a moment to reflect on some of the things I made this year — something I basically never do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that said, following is what I finished, published, and/or created in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>InTolerance: Why I’m Writing A New Show About Prejudice, Faith, and Identity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 14:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</guid><description>In a few short days, I’ll be debuting a new show. To those who have followed my work, I understand that the topic (faith) and setting (a church) feel like they are coming out of left field. And that feeling couldn’t be more right — that’s why I’m doing this show.</description></item><item><title>How I Keep Track of 50 Projects at Once (&amp; Maintain Some Sanity)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 02:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</guid><description>I’m currently in the process of finishing two books, starting another, publishing two new sexuality models, three new live social justice comedy shows, running half a dozen volunteer-based initiatives, building I’m-not-even-sure-how-many websites, and the list goes on. It’s a lot. And as I type that, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>My First Live S.E.X. Show</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-sex-show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 14:19:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-sex-show/</guid><description>A couple months ago my friends Karen Rayne and Heather Ross approached me with an idea. I don’t remember the wording, but I don’t think it was anything less tongue-in-cheek than “Wanna do a sex show in Austin?”
Um. Yes.</description></item><item><title>I’m Sick With Career</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/sick-with-career/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 05:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/sick-with-career/</guid><description>When I came to Austin a few years ago I had nothing, at least relative to what I “have” now. I’ve achieved much and gained a lot in a short amount of time, which are all good things. Well, mostly good.</description></item><item><title>Remembering What You Do</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/remembering-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 04:59:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/remembering-what-you-do/</guid><description>What do you do?
No matter your answer, if you’re anything like me you probably have an iceberg-esque situation on your hands, with 10% of your time spent doing what you do and 90% of your time doing maintenance to allow that 10% to happen.</description></item><item><title>Many Lenses Construct Reality</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 04:19:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>We don’t live in the same world, you and I. But I’d love for you to try to show me yours, if I try to show you mine.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re an artist, you see line and shape wherever you look. You take note of the cues that create perspective, and imagine mixing the colors you see. You wonder how the reality you’re looking at might appear in pastels, oil, and acrylic, and how you might recreate that reality later, and how you might alter it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a comedian, you see humor between every line. Every word you hear, every thing you see, is passed through an algorithm in your head. [q:] Would that make people laugh on stage? [if no:] What do I need to change/tweak? [if yes:] Write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a photographer, you see light and the absence of light in everything. You know that everything you’re looking at, and everything you can’t see, is being translated to your eyes through myriad reflections and refractions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My List of 100 Dreams</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 06:03:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</guid><description>Have y’all heard of Laura Vanderkam’s “List of 100 Dreams” idea? I hadn’t, but I have now, and I love it.
To me, it feels like a bucket list, but better: the items don’t have to feel realistic, or things you can only do if you put the time aside.</description></item><item><title>How To Work on the Internet (In 5 Easy Steps)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I work on the internet. Even now, in The Year Two-Thousand Fourteen, I have to describe what I do with those five words. A talk I heard recently by Heather Corinna, another person who works &lt;a title="So Good." href="http://scarleteen.com" target="_blank">on the internet&lt;/a>, who spoke about working on the internet, was a reminder of this for me, as I found myself relating to everything she said. Five words still when it should really be two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“On the internet” means a ton of things to a ton of different people. “That’s so techy” or “my, how quickly things change!” often translates to me as “ARE YOU FROM THE FUTURE?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some people “on the internet” undoes the “I work” part: “Oh, neat, yeah, but what’s your real job?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my real job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We live in the future, people. There are no flying cars (&lt;a href="http://www.irishmirror.ie/news/world-news/terrafugia-flying-cars-could-sale-2998745" target="_blank">soon&lt;/a>! wanna go halfsies?), but there are shabbily-dressed people working on laptops in coffee shops. The future is here, and it’s unshaven. The only reason we’re still making the “on the internet” distinction is because of the [sometimes willful] ignorance about what the world looks like and how much things have changed in a short amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play catch up (please, do not think any of what I’m suggesting here is anywhere near the cutting edge), let me share with you a few starter steps for working on the internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBooker’s Creed</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my MacBook. There are many like it, but this one is mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook is my best friend. It is my life. I must master it as I must master my life.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook, without me, is still pretty shiny. Without my MacBook, I am useless and not at all shiny and can’t watch Netflix in bed (which I love). I must type words into Pages. I must type words into email correctly or autocorrect may ruin my life. I must send that email before I receive another email or email overload may ruin my life. I will…&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>