<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Media on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/social-media/</link><description>Recent content in Social Media on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rage du Jour</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</guid><description>&lt;p>How many things have you been mad about in the past week? How many meltdown-level shares have you seen in your social feeds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every day there’s something new that my entire social bubble is furious about (at least if feels that way). The &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the backlash for some stupid thing a politician did. Or the horrible take a celebrity had in response to a current event. Or a current event that isn’t getting the right coverage from the news. Or, sometimes, it’s rage about rage: the fact that people are mad about something become the thing other people are mad about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In special cases the rage will last more than a day. But that requires a really sticky subject. Something that can keep our focus amidst the barrage of incoming candidates of rageworthiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to stay genuinely mad about something for a long time. It takes energy, effort, fuel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s easy to get mad about a new thing if the conditions are right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on social media the conditions are prime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 Ways The Top Ten Most Mind Blowing Facts You Would Never Expect About Jennifer Lawrence Absolutely Kinda Restored Our Faith In Humanity And Crushed Our Souls</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 05:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Sorry, Internet, but my mind isn’t, has never been, and will likely remain unblown. But every time you trick me into clicking on one of your linkbaity lists or videos I die a &lt;/span>little inside. Because I want to care. I do care. A lot. But there’s only so much someone can _actually _care, let’s call it the Caring Tolerance™. I’m starting to worry that you’re abusing people’s attention and increasing our Caring Tolerance™ the way a college student treats their liver first semester.&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">&lt;br /> &lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t tell you how many times I’ve rage-read “my last” Buzzfeed article swearing I’d never go back to the site for anything but good ol’ fashioned America’s Funniest Home Videos style laughs. But then I see an article with “faith in humanity” in the title and my mouse hand moves faster than my brain. Then I’m back to rage-reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many times can I read THIS WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE and have it do absolutely nothing, before I start to think nothing will? Or, worse, how much empathy can I be coerced into experiencing by over-the-top, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gspElv1yvc">SPCA Sara McLachlan&lt;/a> wannabe videos on Upworthy before I can’t experience genuine empathy for the people in my immediate life (who aren’t soon-to-be-executed dogs, but still need love)?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>“Proud” and “Humbled”: I do not think it means what you think it means</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 21:19:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</guid><description>There’s an epidemic happening, people. It’s in my Facebook newsfeed and my Twitter tweetsfeed and my Google+ hahakiddingIdon’tcheckthatfeed. I believe it’s evolved from the fairly harmless confusion of their/they’re/there into the now dangerous misuse of “proud” and “humbled.”
The short version: people are saying they’re “proud” when they are really affirmingly excited, and they’re saying they’re “humbled” when they are really proud.</description></item></channel></rss>