<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/building-a-daily-meditation-habit/</link><description>Recent content in Building a Daily Meditation Habit on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/building-a-daily-meditation-habit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Falling Off the Daily Meditation Path</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven’t meditated in over a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve become increasingly aware of this every day that passes. It’s become so big in my day, that, right now, Not Meditating feels like all I’ve accomplished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, here I am writing this instead of doing the damn thing. What is wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that I’ll appreciate my time sitting — both while it’s happening (even if I know it’ll be more fitful than usual) and after. It’ll give my day more focus, give me a breath between the world and my reactions to it, and I’ll feel happier, healthier, calmer, and whole-er.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of meditating, when I haven’t been, are always more obvious to me in the negative: the list of things I’ve been doing, thinking, eating, etc. that were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mindful, but were instead short-sighted comforts that led to longer-term pains. The things I &lt;em>wouldn’t&lt;/em> be doing if I &lt;em>had been&lt;/em> meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my recent memory is full of such things. My body and mind are weighed down with their aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet here I am, still Not Meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that all that’s standing between me getting back on that path or me continuing to flounder is a few minutes on the cushion. I’ve known that every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet I didn’t. I still haven’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what’s getting in my way? If you’ve ever experienced this — or currently are — what’s getting in our way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="//wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="//tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I committed to writing on this site every day for 100 days in a row. Today, I’m committing to something similar and different: I’m going to start meditating every day, for at least the next 100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me explain why, and how I plan to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had an inconsistent meditation practice for about a decade now. At its best, I meditate every day for a streak of a week or two. At its worst, I meditate once a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here’s the thing: I know that meditation makes me happier, calmer, work better, think clearer — it makes me &lt;em>better.&lt;/em> Every time. I can even verify this for myself with some [obviously slanted] data: looking back at my journal, and comparing that against the records from the meditation app I use (Calm), I can see that on days I meditate I almost always finish every task I set out to do in the morning. I’m also more gracious, thoughtful, and patient in my responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the days I don’t meditate, well, I get by, but I’m a bit messier. And sometimes those days turn into weeks into months. That’s what’s happened these past few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the science backs this up, right? We all know this, if we exist even a little on the internet. Just google “&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=the+scientific+benefits+of+meditation">the scientific benefits of meditation&lt;/a>” and bask in the bazillion hits of glory.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>