<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 9:3:1 Learning Rule</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you’re trying to learn a new thing — a skill, talent, instrument, sport, language, anything — there are a million things that can derail you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard not to become fatigued, discouraged, frustrated, lose sight of your goal, or become distracted by a brighter light in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even assuming you get everything else right, and none of those detours push you off path, it’s still common to plateau early and stop making progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rule is to prevent that from happening: &lt;strong>say hello to the 9:3:1 Rule, a guide for how to allocate your time while learning a new thing.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rage du Jour</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</guid><description>&lt;p>How many things have you been mad about in the past week? How many meltdown-level shares have you seen in your social feeds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every day there’s something new that my entire social bubble is furious about (at least if feels that way). The &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the backlash for some stupid thing a politician did. Or the horrible take a celebrity had in response to a current event. Or a current event that isn’t getting the right coverage from the news. Or, sometimes, it’s rage about rage: the fact that people are mad about something become the thing other people are mad about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In special cases the rage will last more than a day. But that requires a really sticky subject. Something that can keep our focus amidst the barrage of incoming candidates of rageworthiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to stay genuinely mad about something for a long time. It takes energy, effort, fuel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s easy to get mad about a new thing if the conditions are right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on social media the conditions are prime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancel Debts Not People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elizabeth Warren has thrown her hat in on a bold idea that’s been in the air for a long time: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@teamwarren/im-calling-for-something-truly-transformational-universal-free-public-college-and-cancellation-of-a246cd0f910f">cancel student loan debt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not interest rate decreases, or refinancing, or other half-measures, but an all out cancelation of up to $50K in student loan debt for anyone whose income is $100K or less. Combined with universal free public higher education going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was first introduced to this idea back in the early 2010s the &lt;a href="https://rollingjubilee.org/">Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a>, a project by &lt;a href="https://strikedebt.org/">Strike Debt&lt;/a>, which has now evolved into &lt;a href="https://debtcollective.org/">The Debt Collective&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their project leveraged one of the most dysfunctional aspects of student loan debt: the fact that the debts get bundled and resold, over and over, for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling Jubilee raised $701,317 dollars (a few of which were mine, even as a broke post-grad student living under a pile of debt) and bought bundles of debt worth a total of $31,982,455.76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, instead of trying to collect those debts, they abolished them. Poof. Gone. No more debt for the people whose loans were part of those bundles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those numbers highlight how broken, and at this point imaginary, the entire debt-debtor relationship is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what world does $700K buy $31M?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Problem of Progressivism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>With more and more people talking about “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;oq=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.4775j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">the left cannibalizing itself&lt;/a>” and “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;oq=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2521j1j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">liberals eating their own&lt;/a>,” or how “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;oq=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5472j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">democrats need to unite to defeat Trump&lt;/a>,” we need to keep reminding ourselves and others about the problem of progressivism — instead of just beating the dead horse that is the problems &lt;em>within&lt;/em> progressivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start with the second one, because that’s what everyone won’t stop yelling about, and I’m afraid if I don’t do a little yelling you won’t hear me out on the part of this that I think is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here it is, me jumping on the dogpile: the left has some problems, and we’re getting in our own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that is true for the “right,” the “center,” liberals, progressives, leftists, Libertarians, Republicans, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally every political camp has problems. Any collection of humans with a count greater than 0 has problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, why is the trope of “liberals eat their own” so pervasive?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updated my /Now: Working on Social Justice, Minus Dogma + Facilitator Cards</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/now-april-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 23:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/now-april-2019/</guid><description>I updated samuelkillermann.com/now with the two main projects I’m working on right meow.
Read all about the the SJMD Course &amp;amp; Community and Facilitator Cards here. I explain what’s my goals are, how I’m (co-)creating them, and roughly when you can expect to see them in the world.</description></item><item><title>Public Libraries Shouldn’t Exist</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:37:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Usually, when I’m at home in Austin, I work in coffee shops. Today, I’m working from our gobsmackingly beautiful public library. And I can’t help but repeatedly ask myself “What would happen if someone pitched the idea of a public library today?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a broken record in my brain. An audio loop. It plays every time I turn a corner in this space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What would it sound like to argue for the idea of a public library in 2019?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When Ambition is Hiding</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consider a few alternatives. Let’s say I told you:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>I want to remove every unhealthy habit, food, and mindset from my life, and I&amp;#8217;m going to start tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>I&amp;#8217;m going to eat less sugar, starting tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When tomorrow comes, which one are you likely to hold me accountable to? Which might you help me excuse when I fall short? Which are you actually expecting me to do? Or even realistically try?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do a few more with those questions in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I say:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my country to 100% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my local school district to 50% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Or:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to end racism, globally.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to help local people of color, and other disenfranchised people, register to vote and get to the polls.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s plenty to get the point I’m going to make, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But first, here’s what I’m not about to say:&lt;/strong> that any of the As above — the lofty, admirable, pie-in-the-sky ambitions — are in any way bad, undesirable, or something I’m advocating against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want all of those things. I have, at different points in my life, said all of those things, in some way or another. And I don’t even like &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/">thinking of myself as ambitious&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here’s all I want to point out:&lt;/strong> sometime we set the bar so high because it gives us an excuse when we can’t clear it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Simple Things You Can Do to Curb Your Phone Addiction Right Now</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of us are addicted to our phones. If you’ve started to see why this might not be the best thing ever, and want to ween yourself off of that tantalizingly non-nourishing blue glow, you’re in good company. This is something I’ve been thinking about, and experimenting with, for a few years now. Following are three things you knock out in about 15 minutes, that will benefit you for weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I get into those, I want to be clear: I’m talking about the colloquial, not clinical, usage of the term “addiction.” In this post, I’m not staking my flag in the hill that “phone addiction” is (or isn’t) real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’m talking about here, as addiction, is the compulsive use of our phones. That we’re spending more time poking around our phones than we want to, picking them up and checking the screen before we realize we’re doing it, and that our phones aren’t adding quality to our lives, and might be distracting us from the things we’d actually care about enjoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m talking about how we’re &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/">already dating our phones&lt;/a>, and how &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">little red numbers are trying to rule our lives&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Creative March</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 23:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last few weeks have been marked by creativity. I love that feeling. I want to make it happen more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bill Gates is frequently quoted for saying, “Most people overestimate what they can do in one year and underestimate what they can do in ten years.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel this contrast more intensely on a smaller scale: &lt;strong>we overestimate what we can do in a day, and underestimate what we can do in a year.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s so easy for me to think of myself as a creative person — a writer, a doodler, a designer, a coder — even when I don’t create anything in a given day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I’m not really a writer when I’m not writing. I’m a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/">reader of political news&lt;/a>, or a dog walker, or a cook, or a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">compulsively rechecking my email because it triggers a dopamine response-er&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been “working on a book for three years” now, but I haven’t truly been &lt;em>working&lt;/em> on that book for three years. I’ve barely worked on it at all. A few minutes here, an hour there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creativity is an act, and one that is so easily sidelined by other actions — anything that feels safer, simpler, easier, or fulfills a shortsighted desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many people do you know who are “working” on things that never get any creative time dedicated to them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many projects are you “working” on that you haven’t sat down in front of for over a week? A month? A year? Ever?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week, I finished and published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/">a book&lt;/a>. The week before I co-created and published a massive &lt;a href="https://thesafezoneproject.com/introducing-safe-zone-train-the-trainer-retreat-guide/">Train-the-Trainer Retreat Guide&lt;/a>. The week before that I wrote a new comedy show. And in between all of that I’ve made major strides in starting two new (secret, for now) projects. And I’ve only checked my email two thousand times (a made up number down from what I assume is my normal two million times per month).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the weeks before that, I was mostly just slogging through administrative stuff. Checking in on old things, closing out 2018. Not really making progress on anything, with only a few essays and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">one edugraphic&lt;/a> to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of that got me reflecting on the ebbs and flows of my own creativity, and wanting to come up with some personal &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/challenge/">challenge&lt;/a> or strategy to get a better grasp on that part of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t want to spend most of my time on tasks that amount to nothing, but feel good in the moment (or at least don’t feel terrifying, like creativity often does).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to spend most of my time creating things that I share with the world, that are durable, that might exist when I’m gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As luck would have it, listening to &lt;a href="https://tim.blog/2019/02/18/jim-collins/">a podcast interview&lt;/a> today with &lt;a href="https://www.jimcollins.com">Jim Collins&lt;/a> gave me an exciting challenge that I’m going to start tonight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn For a Project, Not the Sake of Learning</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because I’m self-taught in most things I do — from programming to design to animation — a lot of my friends ask me for tips on how to learn a particular thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I want to learn how to make websites,” a friend will ask. “Where do you think I should start?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, I’ve given a lot of different responses. Pointing people to free online resources for learning, like &lt;a href="https://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/">Khan Academy&lt;/a>. Or telling them to join a local workshop or meet-up. Or both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not how I learned, but it’s easier to point someone to a resource than it is to give an autobiography for how I learned something myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, seeing that advice fail again and again prompted me to rethink my rationale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What would it look like, if I advised people to learn things how I’ve learned them?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Can Stop Saying “They Should Make A…”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something I see all the time on the internet is people saying “They should have a…” or “They should make a…” and then sharing some idea, platform, service, movement, or cause that the commenter wants, and believes “they” should create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, this made sense. The request was legitimate and necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were gatekeepers in every industry — from arts to activism to commerce to community-building — who were the “They.” It was They who had to approve our appeal to create a new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You couldn’t just make that thing, or build that platform, or create that movement, release that show, or host that community yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You needed Their permission. You needed Them to make it for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Big Thing Being Bedridden with the Flu for a Week Made Me Realize</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:56:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past 7 days, my life was consumed by the flu. Technically, I was more couch-ridden than bedridden, but I was decidedly &lt;em>horizontal&lt;/em>. Luckily, I had a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bs61eifhyh-/">faithful guardian&lt;/a> who didn’t leave my side, so I survived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first time I’ve had the flu in as long as I can remember. I don’t get sick often. The last time I was even “take a day off work” sick was over a year ago (and I don’t even have to get a doctor’s note to call in — I have &lt;a href="https://patreon.com/killermann">lenient bosses&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday, as I was catching up on the &lt;a href="https://www.nbc.com/saturday-night-live/video/january-26-james-mcavoy/3867402">SNL I missed&lt;/a>, I realized I didn’t get most of the jokes because I hadn’t been keeping up with politics or the news (or even trying).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, something else hit me, as I started to dive back into work and catch up with life, that I can attribute entirely to the flu:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Checklist to Work Through Before Creating Any New Website, Blog, or App</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:20:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you thinking about creating a website? Or a blog? Or an app? Do you want to be “in the cloud,” but you’re not really sure what that is? Have you been talking with colleagues about this idea, or received direction from your boss, and started figuring out how to do it yourself, or looking into hiring a designer/developer to build it for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great! Good on you. Making things is really exciting, and it’s really fun to hit the ground running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The natural next step you might make is to start price shopping around, looking for an agency or creative you can afford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not great! But no fault to you: this is what most people do next. And it’s something that results in a lot of wasted money in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you start designing or building something that you have in mind, and &lt;em>definitely&lt;/em> before you start paying someone else to, there are a few things you need to figure out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Hadn’t Funded My Work with Patreon</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 23:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</guid><description>&lt;p>For several years, my “day job” (the one paying my bills) has been performing comedy shows. Meanwhile, my hobby has been creating online resources, tools, and organizations for justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that’s a weird combo, you’re not alone. I’m with you: it’s hard to wrap my mind around the truth that the way I make money is comedy, then I use that money to &lt;em>pay to&lt;/em> do administrative-paperwork-email-non-profit-type stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, it’s the other way around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What’s even weirder? Switching things up — and starting to fund my online advocacy work directly, not via comedy shows — seems less likely to succeed than continuing to be a working comedian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes — I’ve heard of &lt;a href="https://patreon.com">Patreon&lt;/a>. People have told me about it hundreds of times, for years and years, every time I made that point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of the work I do is a great fit for Patreon. But I’ve been resistant to the idea of funding it that way. The reasons are a mix of ethics and personal discomforts, and are all tied directly to my work, and the change I hope it effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why haven’t I done it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You’re Not “Self-Employed”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past almost-decade, I’ve checked the “self-employed” box lots of times: when opening bank accounts, on lease applications for apartments, and it’s how the IRS sees me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s a lie. I’m not “self-employed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breaking the Chain of “Maybe”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a modern scourge upon us, and every get-together, plan, and social event is vulnerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know when it started, who’s to blame, or if it can be defeated, but I’ve begun vaccinating myself against it. And if you or your social circle have caught a case of the &lt;em>Maybes&lt;/em>, or you want to prevent an outbreak, here’s what you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step with any epidemic is understanding the problem: What is the Maybes, how does it spread, and why is it harmful?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Falling Off the Daily Meditation Path</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven’t meditated in over a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve become increasingly aware of this every day that passes. It’s become so big in my day, that, right now, Not Meditating feels like all I’ve accomplished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, here I am writing this instead of doing the damn thing. What is wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that I’ll appreciate my time sitting — both while it’s happening (even if I know it’ll be more fitful than usual) and after. It’ll give my day more focus, give me a breath between the world and my reactions to it, and I’ll feel happier, healthier, calmer, and whole-er.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of meditating, when I haven’t been, are always more obvious to me in the negative: the list of things I’ve been doing, thinking, eating, etc. that were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mindful, but were instead short-sighted comforts that led to longer-term pains. The things I &lt;em>wouldn’t&lt;/em> be doing if I &lt;em>had been&lt;/em> meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my recent memory is full of such things. My body and mind are weighed down with their aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet here I am, still Not Meditating. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that all that’s standing between me getting back on that path or me continuing to flounder is a few minutes on the cushion. I’ve known that every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet I didn’t. I still haven’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what’s getting in my way? If you’ve ever experienced this — or currently are — what’s getting in our way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Made A WordPress Site with a 100 Score on Google Pagespeed Insights</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-i-made-a-wordpress-site-with-a-100-score-on-google-pagespeed-insights/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:21:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-i-made-a-wordpress-site-with-a-100-score-on-google-pagespeed-insights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m really thrilled about this. As a poor person who creates tons of websites that have a ton of traffic but are totally free and make negative dollars, I feel like I’ve found the Holy Grail. But before I get into the details, two quick things:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One, &lt;strong>none of the following links are affiliates/sponsored&lt;/strong> (I don’t abide that sort of thing here).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two, &lt;strong>this path isn’t for everyone&lt;/strong>, but I’m going to lay it out for those of you who want to walk it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just wanted to get that out of the way, because I know that the excitement that’s bubbling out of me might be misread as a sales pitch or proselytizing. It’s not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We good? Good. Omg. Can I tell you how excited I am?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overthinking Everything So You Don’t Have To</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a confession to make: I’m an Overthinker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ve always been this way, but my condition has worsened with age. And my chosen profession didn’t help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I overthink as a matter of work, often. And I always overthink my work. Not just the things I make themselves, but how to describe what I do, and what unites it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately, I’ve come to think that the best way to describe my job is “overthinking everything so you don’t have to.” That’s no surprise, I’m sure, if you’ve popped around this site, or read &lt;a href="https://www.indiebound.org/search/book?keys=author%3AKillermann%2C%20Sam">my books&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://samuelkillermann.com">seen anything else I’ve made&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, ironically, I’m also driven, fundamentally, to empower people to _not _need me, via my work. I always endeavor to remove myself from the picture. Making myself irrelevant is one of my primary goals in everything I make, and it’s often the question that leads to the improvements or further work: “How can I create something that is freely available to prevent a person from needing to hire me to do it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why, for example, I released my copyright on my work back in 2013: I didn’t want people to have to keep asking me to use it, license it, or reprint it. I removed myself from the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this creates a bit of a conundrum. No surprise: me finding a conundrum. That’s Overthinking 101.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been [over-]thinking about that conundrum a lot. And I’ve felt a growing urge to reconcile it, which brings us here. To the how-to I never suspected I would write: A list of ways that I overthink everything, for those of you who want to DIY (OIY?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is the process I generally follow as I overthink everything in my life and work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I apply it to everything I create, to the social justice and human rights advocacy I engage in, to how I organize and operate on a “business” level, and even to how I do things in my “personal” life (relationships, puppy training, cooking, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the not-so-secret sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I suggest you proceed with caution. Overthinking is addictive. &lt;em>I wonder why that is.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Policing Voting vs. Nuance</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</guid><description>You can complain about politics if you don’t vote.
You’re not a bad human if you don’t vote.
You can still be my friend if you don’t vote.
And voting is an exceptional way to complain.
And it’s a perfect way to stake a claim in your humanity.</description></item><item><title>Funding Online Work in 2018</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/funding-online-work-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 23:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/funding-online-work-in-2018/</guid><description>I wrote an unusual blog post (and designed an accompanying infographic) on my main site, It’s Pronounced Metrosexual, where I disclosed the numbers on the number of people who have contributed to the site, and the number who hasn’t. It’s reflective of all of my work, and an interesting (I think) take on the reality of creating stuff for the internet.</description></item><item><title>Learning from Mistakes Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</guid><description>Mistakes don’t guarantee learning, but learning requires mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>After 7 Years Doing this Work, I’m [Re-] Branding. Here’s how I’m making decisions.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got thrown into this. Two-fold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got thrown into the work I’ve been doing. And I got thrown into a situation that’s led me to question everything, rethink and restructure, and make decisions that feel like an overall “brand.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’m happy I’m here, one of the strongest forces that’s guiding what I do next is precisely avoiding how I got here: no more being thrown into stuff. Seem easy? Maybe. Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll get to that in a second, but first the back story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Totally new site. Slightly new direction.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/totally-new-site-slightly-new-direction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 04:52:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/totally-new-site-slightly-new-direction/</guid><description>Howdy! Today marks two turning points: the design of this site has changed (from this to this), and the name has changed (from “Dear World” to “Sam Killermann’s Blog”).
From here on, in addition to things I’ve been writing about before (like happiness &amp;amp; technology), I’ll also be writing about how I DIY (do it myself) in all things social good &amp;amp; online platform related, and posting more personal updates about my work/life.</description></item><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 21:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</guid><description>&lt;p id="e3e7" class="graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf-after--figure">
Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I’m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word “lifestyle”). But this trip was different.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="28ff" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
In years past, the ideas I was presenting (i.e., social justice and anti-oppression concepts, centered around gender) were mostly received as new. And the questions aligned with that. But this year, a lot of the questions I was hearing weren’t responding to what I was saying on stage, as much as they were addressing things that were already bouncing around students’ minds before I got there. I just became the first “spokesperson” for social justice they were able to confront IRL.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5116" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
For example, in years past I got a lot of questions about things like “What do you mean gender and sexuality aren’t the same?” Or “What do you mean a woman can’t ‘oppress’ a man?”
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="b2a7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
But this year, a &lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em">bunch &lt;/em>of times (double digits) during Q&amp;As I was asked something that amounted to “So gender is a social construct, and so is race, so why are we accepting of &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner">Caitlyn Jenner&lt;/a> but not &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal">Rachel Dolezal&lt;/a>?” By high schoolers. In rural Texas Ontario.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5bb9" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
Hold that thought. I’ll return to it, but first I want to take a step back.</description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016, A Brief Review of Creativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 02:08:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 was, well, _quite _the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, I side with what appears to be the consensus that it was, if given only one descriptor, a dumpster fire. That said, it was also more than a dumpster fire, and I want to take a moment to reflect on some of the things I made this year — something I basically never do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that said, following is what I finished, published, and/or created in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Fix: Politics Not Reminiscent of Sports</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</guid><description>&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Political discourse is at a place where it’s hard — if not impossible — to see it as productive. Most times, it doesn’t even seem like folks who are arguing have a vision for anything being accomplished by that argument, other than hearing words yelled.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Facts have been weaponized and are lobbed as projectiles, not used as tools to build a bridge from one perspective to another. Opinions are worn like armor, used to protect ourselves from the bombardment of facts. We scream for our ideas to drown out the screams of others for theirs.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
If sports are modeled after war, as many people say, our political discourse has taken a form modeled after the way we talk about sports.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="//wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="//tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet FacilitatingXYZ: A Free Online Resource for ALL Facilitators</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 13:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</guid><description>&lt;address>
&lt;strong>Updated September 12, 2016:&lt;/strong>&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;officially launched this project, after about 11 months in development, production, and ideation. Woohoo!
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz">FacilitatingXYZ&lt;/a> is everything I wish I had when I got started as a facilitator — and &lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz/manifesto">together&lt;/a>, we can build it into something that helps us continue to learn, develop, and grow. It’s a free online resource with videos, articles, downloads and (soon!) community to help all facilitators improve their craft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I committed to writing on this site every day for 100 days in a row. Today, I’m committing to something similar and different: I’m going to start meditating every day, for at least the next 100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me explain why, and how I plan to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had an inconsistent meditation practice for about a decade now. At its best, I meditate every day for a streak of a week or two. At its worst, I meditate once a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here’s the thing: I know that meditation makes me happier, calmer, work better, think clearer — it makes me &lt;em>better.&lt;/em> Every time. I can even verify this for myself with some [obviously slanted] data: looking back at my journal, and comparing that against the records from the meditation app I use (Calm), I can see that on days I meditate I almost always finish every task I set out to do in the morning. I’m also more gracious, thoughtful, and patient in my responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the days I don’t meditate, well, I get by, but I’m a bit messier. And sometimes those days turn into weeks into months. That’s what’s happened these past few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the science backs this up, right? We all know this, if we exist even a little on the internet. Just google “&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=the+scientific+benefits+of+meditation">the scientific benefits of meditation&lt;/a>” and bask in the bazillion hits of glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Waking up in Nong Pladuk (on my way home to the US)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/waking-up-in-nong-pladuk-on-my-way-home-to-the-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 08:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/waking-up-in-nong-pladuk-on-my-way-home-to-the-us/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s 9am and a woman wearing an apron is leaning over me yelling in Thai, waking me up from a nap with an urgency no alarm clock could match. I’m panicked, not sure for a moment where I am, or what I did wrong, or maybe if I’m covered in spiders (millions of spiders?!) until I notice she’s hawking food — a tray of a dozen small, folded banana leaf bowls full of shrimp, fried noodles, and a few indiscernible vegetables — and I’m not about to die. There are zero spiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Mai,” I manage to grunt as I squint my eyes in the morning sun, one of the few Thai words I have on the tip of my tongue. &lt;em>No thank you&lt;/em>, my eyes say. And also, &lt;em>maybe don’t wake up a belleagured traveler by yelling in his face next time if you want him to buy your stuff?&lt;/em> I collect my bearings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The train is stopped in Nong Pladuk Junction. Steamy air fills the rail car. Nong Pladuk is the starting station of the infamous Thai-Burma railway, more commonly known as “Death Railway.” It stretches from here to Nanchanaburi, the town a few hours down the road from which I am returning to Bangkok. Nearly one-hundred thousand prisoners of war and forced laborers had their lives forfeited to the construction of the Thai-Burma back in the 1940s. It’s a dark place to wake up to on a sunny Monday morning. It plucks at the melancholy I’m feeling in my heart.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loving the Uncertainty of Travel: From Bangkok to Chiang Mai</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/loving-the-uncertainty-of-travel-from-bangkok-to-chiang-mai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 01:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/loving-the-uncertainty-of-travel-from-bangkok-to-chiang-mai/</guid><description>&lt;p>We pile our bags on a little side street in downtown Bangkok. It’s 8pm, the city’s lights are waking up, and busses fill the street. A double-decker bus drives by, inside on the top level a man is singing karaoke to the rest of the travelers. We’re waiting for bus #3, our nine-hour overnight ride to Chiang Mai, a rural town in northern Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can’t find our bus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mike and I are sitting on the stoop of a closed shop, the dozen pieces of luggage and gear scattered around us. We are drinking a beer and appreciating the calamity of the moment: unsure of where we’ll be in the moments that come, what it will feel like, and how we will be getting there. It’s one of the best things about traveling — the constant uncertainty, the focus on the moment, the near-to-nothing being granted — if you can learn to appreciate it. Admittedly, it’s an acquired taste. It’s my coffee. It’s my wine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some confusion and stress, we learn our bus has already arrived. It’s been waiting for us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We don’t know what to expect inside. The conditions of the bus, the seats, the air, the noise. We’re hoping to sleep, but first we’re hoping the seat recline functions. I can’t help but think back to the bus I rode from Cairo into the middle of the White Desert (the half-day of one-hundred degree sun, the broken air conditioning, the overcramped seating, the failing engine).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We pile into the bus and find that we have a private room in the front half of the lower level. Eight seats all to ourselves. I wouldn’t have hoped for anything better. The seats recline. It does get better. And there’s air conditioning. I could die happy on this bus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bus jerks into gear. A strange smell sweeps through our cabin. &lt;em>We might die on this bus.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Me + Thailand = August ’15</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m excited for Thailand. I’ve heard so many amazing things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spoken with people who have immersed themselves in the culture, and had opportunities to reflect on things that were previously invisible in their lives. I know a couple people who have gone and never returned. That says a lot about a place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve talked with activists who are doing tremendous things in the worlds of gender liberation, sex worker advocacy, and social justice education. I’ve learned so much from them already, from afar, from email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Publishing A Book</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m writing from a rooftop in Austin, taking a break from my break — which was part Naomi Klein and part Real Ale — to share a reflection that just sunk in: I’m about to publish my first book, and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to be clear: this isn’t me publishing the first book I wrote (that happened a couple years ago, and still hasn’t sunk in); this is me, under the auspices of &lt;a href="http://impetus.pw">Impetus Books&lt;/a>, publishing my first book someone else wrote (in this case, I’m glowingly happy to say that someone else is Karen Rayne).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m terrified. I’m a professional performer, but in 90 minutes I’ll be sitting down to my first ever singing lesson.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/singing-lesson-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 22:12:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/singing-lesson-anxiety/</guid><description>&lt;p>The lesson will be private. One-on-one. And the instructor, Mady, is, by all accounts, an incredibly delightful, non-intimidating person. I’ve performed on stages in front of 5000+ person crowds. I’ve spoken to hundreds of thousands of people around the US. I’ve done stand-up comedy on a stage in a country where the material I was performing could have landed me in jail, or worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why am I so nervous about this?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starstruck</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/starstruck/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 07:25:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/starstruck/</guid><description>I would have replied, but I didn’t know my voice would be so hard to find. You don’t get starstruck, I kept telling myself, but maybe I’d never seen a real star. She felt like a star. A sparkling, ancient light, as beautiful as it is mysterious, sincere but distant.</description></item><item><title>InTolerance: Why I’m Writing A New Show About Prejudice, Faith, and Identity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 14:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</guid><description>In a few short days, I’ll be debuting a new show. To those who have followed my work, I understand that the topic (faith) and setting (a church) feel like they are coming out of left field. And that feeling couldn’t be more right — that’s why I’m doing this show.</description></item><item><title>How I Rationalize Being So Hard on Myself, &amp; How I’m Going to Stop</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</guid><description>I’m my own worst critic. A lot of us are. I don’t like this about myself. A lot of us don’t. But I finally have a strategy to make it stop happening.
Of course we’re our own worst critics: we know better than anyone else our abilities, capacities, our “should”s — we know our potential, so we know when we fall short.</description></item><item><title>What I Miss About Grad School</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 06:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</guid><description>Earlier tonight, my friend texted me “I’m over this whole constantly chasing the homework train business.”
She was talking about grad school, and sharing a sentiment I shared back when I was earning my master’s. But, a bit to my surprise, I replied, “I miss grad school.</description></item><item><title>Gender Expression vs. Cueing, &amp; How Sometimes They’re One-in-the-Same</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</guid><description>Last week I gave three back-to-back shows at the Fashion Institute of Technology in New York. I was their “Diversity Speaker” for orientation, a product of some of the orientation leaders seeing me speak at a conference. I’ve said this a bunch: I loved doing those shows, and I heart FIT.</description></item><item><title>How I Keep Track of 50 Projects at Once (&amp; Maintain Some Sanity)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 02:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</guid><description>I’m currently in the process of finishing two books, starting another, publishing two new sexuality models, three new live social justice comedy shows, running half a dozen volunteer-based initiatives, building I’m-not-even-sure-how-many websites, and the list goes on. It’s a lot. And as I type that, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>My First Live S.E.X. Show</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-sex-show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 14:19:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-sex-show/</guid><description>A couple months ago my friends Karen Rayne and Heather Ross approached me with an idea. I don’t remember the wording, but I don’t think it was anything less tongue-in-cheek than “Wanna do a sex show in Austin?”
Um. Yes.</description></item><item><title>A Perfect Night in Dahab</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/perfect-night-in-dahab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 14:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/perfect-night-in-dahab/</guid><description>&lt;p>I arrived in Dahab in the middle of the night, the Red Sea choppy with a half-moon floating above in its own sea of stars. Even at 2am, I could see the silhouette of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia set against the constellations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I stood on the walking bridge near my hostel for more than a few minutes, watching the small waves lap the shore, listening to the gentle sounds, breathing the salty fresh air. A person walked by me on the bridge, “Perfect night,” he said with an accent I couldn’t place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Perfect night,” I replied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Into the Desert</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/into-the-desert/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 15:55:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/into-the-desert/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on a bus heading from Cairo to a town in the White Desert. From there we will hop in a 4×4 with a Bedouin man who will guide us further. I’m part of a small party consisting of a German by way of Lebanon, a Canadian by way of Jordan, and an Iranian (-American) by way of Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bus is massive but largely empty. The seats are comfortable and recline. Both were unexpected, but super appreciated. There’s one mosquito flying around that no one seems to be able to kill. We just hit a parked car while backing out of our spot, but of course we did. We’re heading out on a six-hour journey to the middle of the Sahara.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the bus slows in the first town, reacting to traffic, a small boy hops on and starts dropping rolls of mints in everybody’s laps as he walks down the aisle. Then he returns to the front and tells each person, “Pay me,” in Arabic. That’s one way to sell a mint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wake up several hours in at a building that I have a hard time believing exists. It’s a small, but bustling restaurant, miles away from any civilization with nothing but stretcing sands in between. As the bus is refueling, we step inside to grab some water and stretch our legs. The place is full of people, all stopping in the middle of some journey to somewhere, eating and drinking. Outside, the desert crawls to the horizon in all directions.&lt;figure class="wp-block-image alignwide">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/20140615-171308-61988079-1024x233.jpg" alt="A panorama of a bus stop in the middle of the desert" class="wp-image-679 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/20140615-171308-61988079.jpg 1024w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/20140615-171308-61988079-300x68.jpg 300w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/20140615-171308-61988079-768x175.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wake up again and we’re near the end of the road. A small town where we’ll meet Abdul, our Bedouin guide, who will be driving us deeper into nowhere. A full day’s worth of travel and the adventure is just getting started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We pile into Abdul’s truck and we’re off. No talking, just driving. We whip through a few small villages and stretches of highway, then enter the Black Desert. There we come up to a building settled on a hill where we will be eating lunch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Outsider’s Guide to Driving in Egypt</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/driving-in-egypt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 02:47:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/driving-in-egypt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m writing this from the back seat of cab heading from downtown Cairo to Zamalek.  My driver just smashed a side view mirror off another cab. This isn’t the first time I’ve experienced this. In fact, my record so far in one cab ride is three accidents. But I’m getting ahead of myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The traffic in Cairo is a truly amazing site. It’s either a complete jam, or wide open. I’ve yet to experience anything in between, nor to learn how to anticipate which it will be. I’m already 20 minutes late for a lunch meeting (sorry, Farida!), but I’ve been assured that by “Egyptian time” standards I’m quite alright. I initially thought the lack of promptness here was an artifact of the generally laid-back culture, now I see it as more of a psychological survival tactic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic. Is. Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last night I was told that fatalities by car here are in the top per capita worldwide (Number one! Number one! Number one!). I haven’t fact-checked this, nor do I plan on it, but I have little doubt in my mind that it is true. Here are a few reasons why that might be:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Landing in Egypt, Slammed with Culture</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/egypt-culture-shock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 12:16:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/egypt-culture-shock/</guid><description>&lt;p>I arrive in the airport in Cairo at 2am on Thursday. I’ve been traveling since 9am Tuesday. Three hours to Houston, ten or so to Amsterdam, layover for the day there (Pancakes! Walking the canals! Coffee shops!), then a four hour flight to Cairo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaving the airport, I get hailed into a cab that I thought was occupied. In the front two seats are the driver, his wife, and two children. In the back seat is a third child. The kids all have paint on their faces, red and black for the boy, red and white for the two little girls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Do you speak English?” I ask. I try in Arabic. “Bititkallim ingileezi?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes, yes. Taxi? Get in.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m going to Dina’s Hostel. Know it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes, yes, hotel. Get in. Welcome.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we start driving. We’re flying through what little traffic there is. To the right there is a moped that has three men riding on it. I’m impressed. To the left there’s another moped with three men riding and one is holding a suitcase. Now I’m disappointed in the first moped.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Me + Egypt = June</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/egypt-june/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 07:29:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/egypt-june/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past several years I’ve been social justice comeding. And I’ve been going &lt;a href="http://media.giphy.com/media/UIZs6DDbFuUj6/giphy.gif">H.A.M.&lt;/a> I’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE">made&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://gamersagainstbigotry.org">a&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://thesafezoneproject.com">bunch&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://letstalkaboutgender.com">of&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/3030395/how-to-design-signs-for-the-gender-neutral-toilet-of-the-future">different&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com">things&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="http://guidetogender.com">And&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://haveyouseensex.com">more&lt;/a>. And I haven’t taken a day off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the time has come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m the perfect combination of completely excited, completely exhausted, thrilled, depleted, optimistic, and completely-lost-hope-in-humanity-because-of-Buzzfeed for a change of pace. I need a refresher. A break. A time to breathe. A time away from this god-forsaken laptop (kidding, &lt;a href="//macbook-creed/" title="MacBooker’s Creed">I love my laptop&lt;/a>). But I am going to abandon it for a month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do, Reflect, Tweak, Do: From Thought/Day to Dear World</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first started this project several months ago, I was &lt;a href="//welcome/" title="Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day">pretty clear&lt;/a> about what my goal was with the writing here: in short, nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted a space to explore new ideas, to reflect, to write, to share, but without any particular “goal.” So much of the writing I do is extremely goal-oriented. I wanted to see what would happen if I created a space that was less structured. I wasn’t sure what I’d end up writing about, what shape this site would take, and was happy to follow my fingers on an adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was fun. I wrote a lot of things I’d’ve never written otherwise, found that I have thoughts about seemingly random things that others find value in reading. I only got a few pieces of hatemail compared to a pile of encouragemail — this was new. I started with only one real rule, but I broke it after about 100 days. I was planning on writing once a day, and when I started traveling a lot at the beginning of this year, I missed one day. And that’s the funny thing about &lt;a href="//protecting-good-habits/">habits&lt;/a> — one missed day is alarmingly similar to one missed month, then you’re only a hop &amp;amp; skip away from a &lt;em>never happening again ever.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After missing a few days, I experienced stress related to this project that I hadn’t experienced, and decided that it was time to take a break from it, reflect, and see if it still has a healthy place in my life. I’ve done that now, and I’m happy to say that it does. &lt;em>Kinda.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gone is &lt;em>Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day&lt;/em>. Welcome _Dear World, _a much more fitting title for what’s going to be happening here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Sick With Career</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/sick-with-career/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 05:59:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/sick-with-career/</guid><description>When I came to Austin a few years ago I had nothing, at least relative to what I “have” now. I’ve achieved much and gained a lot in a short amount of time, which are all good things. Well, mostly good.</description></item><item><title>Be Bored</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 05:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</guid><description>&lt;p>Be bored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop. Whatever else you’re doing. Stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn off your music. Turn off the TV, Netflix Instant Streaming, Hulu+, Amazon Prime, all the things you use to fill your time. Not forever, not for long, but for right now, this moment, stop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protecting Good Habits</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 05:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</guid><description>We’ve heard it a million times: “old habits die hard.” But that’s not true. Truly, “bad habits die hard.” I can attest to this, using this Thought/Day project as an example.
Up until last week, I was 81 for 81 days in a row of writing and publishing a thought each day.</description></item><item><title>I’m Not Going To Teach You Anything New</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 05:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</guid><description>That’s something one of my professors in grad school would lead off with in the first class of the semester. The class was about the effect of environments on people’s ability to learn, develop, and grow. After sixteen weeks, hours of discussion, papers, and reading an entire textbook, he was right.</description></item><item><title>Remembering What You Do</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/remembering-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 04:59:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/remembering-what-you-do/</guid><description>What do you do?
No matter your answer, if you’re anything like me you probably have an iceberg-esque situation on your hands, with 10% of your time spent doing what you do and 90% of your time doing maintenance to allow that 10% to happen.</description></item><item><title>This Flowchart Will Change Your Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</guid><description>Hahaha — oh headlines. But seriously. You need no flowchart beyond this flowchart. View. Share. Love. Life.</description></item><item><title>My Pre-Trip Insomnia</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/pre-trip-insomnia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/pre-trip-insomnia/</guid><description>I’m flying to Seattle in a couple hours to speak at a conference for teen citizen lobbyists. Social justice advocate teen citizen lobbyists… pretty amazing, right?
As usual, I’m wide awake with no real hope of that changing. It’s been a few years now, and I haven’t outgrown this pre-trip insomnia.</description></item><item><title>Treating Old Friends Like New Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 05:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</guid><description>I made a new friend (not bragging) who is so awesome (totally bragging) she makes me seem boring (humble bragging). I love making new friends. I love the adventure, the mystery, toeing and pushing the line, oversharing with whimsy — I love every step of the way.</description></item><item><title>“What is the meaning of life?”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 05:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</guid><description>“What’s the meaning of life?” he asked earnestly, as if he actually wanted the answer.
“To live true, to be honest, to experience spiritual connection, to give, to be…” he replied, rambling on platitudes. The same niceties he found himself saying on a regular basis — a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Social Justice in 2014: Three Things to Do LESS</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/social-justice-in-2014/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 04:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/social-justice-in-2014/</guid><description>There are some wonderful things happening right now. All last year, I said it again and again, we&amp;#8217;re on the cusp of something great. Sites trying to create positive change in the world dominate my social media feeds. I was getting my hair cut today and I said I do &amp;#8220;social justice work&amp;#8221; and the hairdresser actually [kinda] knew what that meant.</description></item><item><title>Many Lenses Construct Reality</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 04:19:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>We don’t live in the same world, you and I. But I’d love for you to try to show me yours, if I try to show you mine.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re an artist, you see line and shape wherever you look. You take note of the cues that create perspective, and imagine mixing the colors you see. You wonder how the reality you’re looking at might appear in pastels, oil, and acrylic, and how you might recreate that reality later, and how you might alter it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a comedian, you see humor between every line. Every word you hear, every thing you see, is passed through an algorithm in your head. [q:] Would that make people laugh on stage? [if no:] What do I need to change/tweak? [if yes:] Write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a photographer, you see light and the absence of light in everything. You know that everything you’re looking at, and everything you can’t see, is being translated to your eyes through myriad reflections and refractions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing to Love Instead of Allowing Ourselves to Hate</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:13:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</guid><description>It’s gotten far easier to allow ourselves to hate than it is to choose to love.
We’re getting it from all sides. Controversy sells better than sex, and when you combine the two you have pretty much every magazine you see in the grocery store check-out line.</description></item><item><title>My List of 100 Dreams</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 06:03:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</guid><description>Have y’all heard of Laura Vanderkam’s “List of 100 Dreams” idea? I hadn’t, but I have now, and I love it.
To me, it feels like a bucket list, but better: the items don’t have to feel realistic, or things you can only do if you put the time aside.</description></item><item><title>Four Different Versions of Me</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/four-mes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:40:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/four-mes/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s weird, ya know, waking up to emails from four different people I don’t know, who don’t know me, but think they do. Depicting four vastly different mes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who hates families, Christians, and Christian families. Who is dedicated to “destroying Western Civilization” and will be promptly burning in Hell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who is saintlike in his love and compassion for others, who is “a glimpse of light in a world that’s gotten dark.” Whose work “literally saved my life.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who is motivated solely by ulterior motives, greed, and who would “best serve the LGBT community by killing yourself.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>The National Organization for Marriage Attempted to Write a Hate Piece About Me</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/national-organization-for-marriage-against-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/national-organization-for-marriage-against-me/</guid><description>Hey NOM,
Sam Killermann here. Or, as I’m being described on your Facebook Page, “Sin with Colored Pencils” here. I read the “blog post” you wrote about me and my “Genderbread Person.” To be “honest,” I couldn’t put together exactly what you were “trying” to say.</description></item><item><title>Let’s Be Honest: We’re Already Dating Our Phones</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 05:58:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yo. I just saw &lt;em>Her.&lt;/em> It’s cray. It’s powerfully well-written and brings up a lot of thoughts about how we might relate to technology and one another in the future. But it also made me think a lot about how we relate to technology and one another right now. If you have a smart phone and you’ve seen &lt;em>Her&lt;/em>, you’ve likely had a lot of these thoughts already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to convince myself that we’re not already dating our phones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Work on the Internet (In 5 Easy Steps)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I work on the internet. Even now, in The Year Two-Thousand Fourteen, I have to describe what I do with those five words. A talk I heard recently by Heather Corinna, another person who works &lt;a title="So Good." href="http://scarleteen.com" target="_blank">on the internet&lt;/a>, who spoke about working on the internet, was a reminder of this for me, as I found myself relating to everything she said. Five words still when it should really be two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“On the internet” means a ton of things to a ton of different people. “That’s so techy” or “my, how quickly things change!” often translates to me as “ARE YOU FROM THE FUTURE?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some people “on the internet” undoes the “I work” part: “Oh, neat, yeah, but what’s your real job?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my real job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We live in the future, people. There are no flying cars (&lt;a href="http://www.irishmirror.ie/news/world-news/terrafugia-flying-cars-could-sale-2998745" target="_blank">soon&lt;/a>! wanna go halfsies?), but there are shabbily-dressed people working on laptops in coffee shops. The future is here, and it’s unshaven. The only reason we’re still making the “on the internet” distinction is because of the [sometimes willful] ignorance about what the world looks like and how much things have changed in a short amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play catch up (please, do not think any of what I’m suggesting here is anywhere near the cutting edge), let me share with you a few starter steps for working on the internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Guitar is My Pacifier. What’s yours?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 05:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, I wake up spooning my guitar. This comforts me, then I realize I could have destroyed it so it terrifies me, then I realize I didn’t destroy it so I’m comforted again. It’s a roller coaster. Other days, my guitar is the first thing I reach for in the morning. I’m still rubbing sleepies out of my eyes while I fingerpick a few notes and think about what I’m going to do with my day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I’m having a tumultuous day, or I’m feeling particularly down, or I feel like the world is broken, or if I run out of hummus ingredients, I’ll pick it up, pick some strings, and it will immediately pick me up. Sometimes I only need a few minutes, sometimes I need a couple of hours, but it always works. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guitar is my pacifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Insulted When You Call Me Ambitious</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 04:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading a blog post someone wrote about me (I know. Let’s move on.) and they described me as “incredibly ambitious.” This was meant to be a compliment. Cool. Nice of you. But I don’t see it that way. I get upset when people describe me or think of me as ambitious. In general, I discourage ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many ways, ambition is the opposite of who I am, want to be, and what I want for others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 Ways The Top Ten Most Mind Blowing Facts You Would Never Expect About Jennifer Lawrence Absolutely Kinda Restored Our Faith In Humanity And Crushed Our Souls</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 05:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Sorry, Internet, but my mind isn’t, has never been, and will likely remain unblown. But every time you trick me into clicking on one of your linkbaity lists or videos I die a &lt;/span>little inside. Because I want to care. I do care. A lot. But there’s only so much someone can _actually _care, let’s call it the Caring Tolerance™. I’m starting to worry that you’re abusing people’s attention and increasing our Caring Tolerance™ the way a college student treats their liver first semester.&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">&lt;br /> &lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t tell you how many times I’ve rage-read “my last” Buzzfeed article swearing I’d never go back to the site for anything but good ol’ fashioned America’s Funniest Home Videos style laughs. But then I see an article with “faith in humanity” in the title and my mouse hand moves faster than my brain. Then I’m back to rage-reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many times can I read THIS WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE and have it do absolutely nothing, before I start to think nothing will? Or, worse, how much empathy can I be coerced into experiencing by over-the-top, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gspElv1yvc">SPCA Sara McLachlan&lt;/a> wannabe videos on Upworthy before I can’t experience genuine empathy for the people in my immediate life (who aren’t soon-to-be-executed dogs, but still need love)?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBooker’s Creed</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my MacBook. There are many like it, but this one is mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook is my best friend. It is my life. I must master it as I must master my life.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook, without me, is still pretty shiny. Without my MacBook, I am useless and not at all shiny and can’t watch Netflix in bed (which I love). I must type words into Pages. I must type words into email correctly or autocorrect may ruin my life. I must send that email before I receive another email or email overload may ruin my life. I will…&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Should Watch the Movie “About Time”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 05:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hadn’t really heard much about &lt;em>About Time&lt;/em>, the newest Love-Actually-Notting-Hill-Brit-Rom-Com-warm-fuzzy delight. And, to be honest, while I love watching feel-good movies (because they, you know, make me &lt;a href="//new-years-resolutions-happy-world/" title="If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier">feel good&lt;/a>), I don’t generally have high expectations for them. They tend to be rather empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one is not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being Sick is a Good Time For Catching Up</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/being-sick-catching-up/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 05:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/being-sick-catching-up/</guid><description>I don’t often get sick, but when I do, I get sick. While I was in New Orleans I came down with a wicked case of Swamp Flu. Or maybe it’s the Bayou Bug. I just hope it’s not Crawfish Sickness.</description></item><item><title>Single-Serving Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</guid><description>Edward Norton’s character in _Fight Club _introduced me to the term “single-serving friend,” a person who is your friend for a short period in time. In the movie, he’s talking about the people he meets on flights (“everything on a plane is single-serving”).</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Thoughts of 2013</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-favorite-thoughts-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 23:59:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-favorite-thoughts-of-2013/</guid><description>When I set out on this project, I was as clear as I could be about what this is. What it’s become, however, is one of my favorite parts of my day, every day for the past 62. While there is no goal to this project beyond to write more — nothing I’m trying to accomplish with the articles — there have been a few thoughts that have stuck out.</description></item><item><title>Man High on Meth Fights Off 15 Police Officers While Masturbating.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/man-high-on-meth-fights-of-15-police-officers-while-masturbating/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 01:28:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/man-high-on-meth-fights-of-15-police-officers-while-masturbating/</guid><description>Yep. That’s a real headline. I was gonna write a thought today. I think it was going to be about traveling and New Orleans and friendship and adventures, but after reading that headline/article I realized I have nothing to add to the internet today.</description></item><item><title>An Open Letter to the Disney Channel</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/open-letter-to-disney-channel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 10:14:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/open-letter-to-disney-channel/</guid><description>Dear Disney Channel,
Please stop ruining today’s children.
I would love to stop there, because I think the sassiness of one sentence is an appropriate response to the hollowness of your programming, but I refuse to stoop to your level. Earlier tonight, while at a laundromat, I was subjected to an hour of your work, a show called _Jessie.</description></item><item><title>Genital Xenophobia and Genital Wanderlust: Show Me Yours and I’ll Show You Mine</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</guid><description>I remember the first time I played Show Me Yours I’ll Show You Mine. Some people call it Doctor. If you’ve never played, worry not: the rules are the simple. Show me yours. Then I show you mine. And who is the winner?</description></item><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>Spend a day lost in your thoughts.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/spend-a-day-lost-in-your-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 05:47:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/spend-a-day-lost-in-your-thoughts/</guid><description>Spend a day lost in your thoughts.
It’s not the way it’s normally done.
Days are full of things, and led with a compass.
You go places and see things and places and things see you.
The World. You must be a part of the world.</description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>Scrapping and Starting Fresh: The Hawthorne Effect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 05:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</guid><description>A couple months ago I ventured into the land of the podcast. A couple weeks ago I roped my friend Ian in and “Thought of the Week” became “The Hawthorne Effect.” The whole thing has been a huge learning process. After doing a number of different podcast approaches by myself, and trying a few different things out with Ian, he and I sat down tonight to reflect on what we think has worked, what hasn’t, and set a clear plan for what we’ll do in the future.</description></item><item><title>If Passion Can Be Portrayed in Film</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/dark-side-of-the-lens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 05:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/dark-side-of-the-lens/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is what it might look like:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Abusive Relationship We’re All In That Most of Us Never Think About</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 03:17:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</guid><description>I saw this wonderful commercial earlier today and shared it on Facebook immediately. Watch it, then let’s talk about it.
 Obviously, these aren’t new ideas to me. I talk a lot about the proverbial boxes we are all smushed into.</description></item><item><title>100+ Tips for Minimalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 01:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</guid><description>Kidding. 100 would be a bit excessive, and likely more than a bit counterintuitive, wouldn’t it? It’s easy for us to be seduced by a lot, and to think that more is better, but we rarely need more than a little.</description></item><item><title>“Proud” and “Humbled”: I do not think it means what you think it means</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 21:19:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</guid><description>There’s an epidemic happening, people. It’s in my Facebook newsfeed and my Twitter tweetsfeed and my Google+ hahakiddingIdon’tcheckthatfeed. I believe it’s evolved from the fairly harmless confusion of their/they’re/there into the now dangerous misuse of “proud” and “humbled.”
The short version: people are saying they’re “proud” when they are really affirmingly excited, and they’re saying they’re “humbled” when they are really proud.</description></item><item><title>50 Thoughts, New Site, Checking in on What I’ve Learned</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 05:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</guid><description>This will be my fifty-first post on this site. It’s been a fun fifty-one days of this experiment.
When I set out on this adventure I was hoping to accomplish several things, a couple in particular: to learn more about myself and get the ideas that rattle around in my head out into words.</description></item><item><title>Why I’ve Never Been a Fan of “Self Help” Books</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 05:37:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</guid><description>I’ve only ever read one, maybe two, “self help” books (depending on how strict your definition is). Not for me. And I wouldn’t want to foist them on anyone else. Might seem odd, considering what I write here. That’s one of the reasons I’ve been so reluctant to write about the things I write about here: because I don’t like the idea of “self help” coming from another person.</description></item><item><title>Be Your Own Friend First</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 05:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</guid><description>Everything you need to know about relationships you can learn from watching _Dexter _and _Scrubs. _Okay, that’s probably not true. But I really dig both shows, and I like what I’ve gleaned from both character’s approaches to life.
Dexter, the sociopath who lives a life of lies, is amazingly good at self care.</description></item><item><title>20+ Simple Tips for Living Mindfully</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 04:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</guid><description>Mindfulness is happiness. But you already know that. But what is mindfulness, beyond the abstract definition of “attentive, aware, or careful” that I gave in that other article? Being more mindful means tapping into all of your senses. If you’re more of a concrete person, here are a bunch of examples of how you can live a more mindful life.</description></item><item><title>The Three Rs of Saw Sharpening</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 04:48:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</guid><description>As I mentioned a couple days ago, I’ve got a bit of a break before I head back on the road for my next gig. This is important time for me, because it’s the time that I set aside every year to sharpen my saw.</description></item><item><title>Asking For Help</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</guid><description>I have a hard time asking for help, likely mostly because I’m a dude. You might freak out reading this if you’re familiar with my other work, but let me write a few more words before we start sounding any alarms.</description></item><item><title>For Me, It’s About the People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-me-its-about-the-people/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 02:45:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-me-its-about-the-people/</guid><description>After the second day of this conference, thinking about why I’ve had such a great experience, and why I find myself so connected to this world that a few days ago I was anything but, the answer is clear.
Ultimately, for me, it matters more who you are, and how you do something, than what you are actually doing.</description></item><item><title>The Most Wild Year of My Life Ended in One Moment</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-my-year-ended/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 04:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-my-year-ended/</guid><description>Earlier tonight I gave the opening keynote for the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference. It was an hour that I’ve spent the last 6 months mulling, refining, trashing, rebuilding, trashing, reconceiving, and then, tonight, finally talking. I’ve never given a talk like that — not even close.</description></item><item><title>Positivity in the Face of So Much Negativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/positivity-amidst-negativity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 05:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/positivity-amidst-negativity/</guid><description>I got an email with the above title and the following snippets, from a wonderful person who’s struggling with something I struggle with every day.
In following your blogs and talks, I’ve been impressed with the positivity and humor that you project.</description></item><item><title>Three Days Computerless</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/three-days-computerless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 05:16:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/three-days-computerless/</guid><description>I should have my computer back tomorrow. Living without it these past few days has been odd, in some ways more expected than others.
I’ve realized how generally worthless I am to the world without a computer to mash myself through, like how you mash flour and water through a pasta press then voila!</description></item><item><title>These 6 Videos will Change the Way You Look at Unregulated Capitalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 23:49:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</guid><description>RSA Animate: The Crises of Capitalism Wealth Inequality in America Naomi Klein: Addicted to Risk Alain de Botton: A Kinder, Gentler Philosophy of Success The Overview Effect Nic Marks: The Happy Planet Index</description></item><item><title>My Computer Died, but that’s Good</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 01:14:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</guid><description>&lt;p>I woke up this morning to my computer not working. It’s not been in great shape these past few months, and has occasionally tossed a surprise my way. It’s several years old, and I’ve put it through plenty of hell with all my traveling (and general clumsiness). I’d already been investigating new options, and weighing the pros and cons. I knew its time was drawing near.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of work on my plate right now, and a lot of it’s time sensitive. And chief thing on my mind is the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference next week, for which I’m excited to be one of the keynotes. I have a few pressing collaborations, plenty of more people who I’ve promised e-love to, and some big personal projects that are underway. Objectively, it’s not an ideal time for my computer to bail on me. But subjectively, I’m excited for a few days without my computer, amidst a few of the days this year I most crushingly want to feel like I _need _it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If Full-Scale Revolution Started, Where Would You Be?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/your-revolutionary-role/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 22:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/your-revolutionary-role/</guid><description>I want to start by letting the NSA know this is purely a thought experiment. We cool? Sweet. Thanks, bros.
Now let’s burn this place to the ground.
Imagine we were in the middle of a full-scale, government upheaving, tea dumping, enterprise leveling, building burning revolution.</description></item><item><title>Being Alone Isn’t the Same as Being Lonely</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</guid><description>My post about going to see a movie by yourself has stirred up some wonderful conversations. And the title of this post is the most interesting thought that’s come from it, and I want to dive right in.
Being alone isn’t a bad thing.</description></item><item><title>Go See a Movie By Yourself</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 17:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</guid><description>I just got back from watching the new _Hunger Games _flick. I cried 15+ times in 146 minutes and left the theatre fired up to burn down the establishment. You should see it. I also went alone. And that’s not how you’re supposed to do that thing.</description></item><item><title>“What do you do?” vs “Who are you?”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-do-you-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-do-you-do/</guid><description>What’s the first question you ask someone you meet at a dinner party? “Can you point me in the direction of the hummus platter?” Okay, but the second question? “What do you _mean _they don’t have a hummus platter?!” You’re clearly hungry.</description></item><item><title>Today is Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</guid><description>Nothing particularly special happened today. One could call it, for me, a fairly unremarkable Saturday. I woke up to some bad news, spent most of my day in a relatively lazy fashion behind my computer, didn’t experience many of my favorite things about Austin, and now, an hour before midnight, my day is winding down.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow Will Be Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 05:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</guid><description>I spent most of the day today horizontal. I slept a lot, napped a bit, and snoozed when I wasn’t doing one of those two things. Yesterday was the exact opposite. I was vertical, doing, and doing some more. Both days have been perfect.</description></item><item><title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happy-thanksgiving/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 05:33:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happy-thanksgiving/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FRIENDSGIVING: My Island for Misfit Toys</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 01:56:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>I loved Thanksgiving growing up. As a kid, Thanksgiving is a wonderful event. You get a couple days off school, you eat too much, sleep too much, eat too much again, sleep again, repeat, then it’s Monday. Loved it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an adult, it can be fun, but it also tends to be a bit more stressful. Either you’re part of the shopping and prepping and cooking tornado, or you’re a worthless obstruction that gets caught up in its path (like those cows in &lt;em>Twister&lt;/em>). Throw in a bunch of people who don’t see each other often, starve them for a few hours, add two servings of booze, a sprinkling of reticent drama, and you’ve got Thanksgiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’d be okay with a revolution.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 19:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</guid><description>I wrote a Facebook status and Tweet last week that were meant to be a joke. A sarcastic, I want more out of the world, parody-type joke. But nobody laughed.
Post by Sam Killermann.  I’m not mad.</description></item><item><title>My Gratitude Challenge</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</guid><description>My momma taught me to say please and thank you, to keep my elbows off the table, and to never chew with my mouth full. As a near grown-up Sam, these all feel as natural as breathing, blinking, or eating peanut butter directly from the jar with a spoon (sorry, Momma).</description></item><item><title>At What Point Do We Stop Thinking of Celebrities as People?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/celebrities-as-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 01:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/celebrities-as-people/</guid><description>Miley Cyrus hasn’t been a person for long time. She used to be a person, then she was Hannah Montana, and now she’s a punchline. Kanye West is a punchline that has tried to fight for his personhood, and as a result become a punchline within a punchline.</description></item><item><title>Living in the Undefined</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</guid><description>It’s in our nature to define things. We like boxes, categories. A few thousand years ago, this was incredibly helpful. Don’t eat things that look like this: you will die. Eat things that look like this: they are delicious.
But nowadays, I find that my compulsion to define things is incredibly unhelpful.</description></item><item><title>Uncopyright</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/uncopyright/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 05:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/uncopyright/</guid><description>On Tuesday I was sitting in my favorite coffee shop in Austin and I felt inspired to record my podcast. I grabbed my fancy microphone out of my bag and started to set it up to record when I noticed something: Tom’s had the Beatles playing.</description></item><item><title>The 3 Ingredients to a Happy Existence</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intentionality, Mindfulness, and Minimalism are all you need, beyond basic biological requirements (clean water, nutritious food, human touch, etc.), to live a happy existence. This is what I’ve come to believe. I’ll define what I mean by all three, and talk about their relationship to one another, but first I want to talk about “happiness.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t aspire toward being happy all the time, nor do I recommend it. I don’t think of happiness as existing at the opposite end of sadness, nor do I think that sadness is inherently bad. All emotions have value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think of happiness on a continuum with lack of happiness on the other end, sadness on a continuum with lack of sadness on the other end, and so forth. Experiencing happiness doesn’t necessarily make you less sad — The Barenaked Ladies kew this: “I’m the kind of guy who laughs at a funeral.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.5 Weeks and 15,000 Words in, How Am I Feeling About Thought / Day?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 05:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</guid><description>I’ve written a lot in these past few weeks of this new experiment. When I launched this site I shared a few of my reasons why, but I have also been aware from the start that I really didn’t know where this project would go, and I still don’t.</description></item><item><title>Reasons I Know My Heart is in Austin, Texas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-heart-in-austin-texas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 04:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-heart-in-austin-texas/</guid><description>I travel a lot for work. As anyone who travels for work will know, people always say, “You get to travel a lot? That must be nice!” And it is nice. It’s fun to see all the different nooks and crannies of the United States, and I love meeting people from all the different walks of life I do.</description></item><item><title>My Gaming Community</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-gaming-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 04:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-gaming-community/</guid><description>With what I do with Gamers Against Bigotry, and with being a long time video game lover, I tend to use the phrase “the gaming community” a lot. Generally more than once a day. It’s a term we all toss around, and we generally use it to mean “everyone who plays video games.</description></item><item><title>Catalytic Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/catalytic-friends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 04:55:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/catalytic-friends/</guid><description>It’s rare that it’s a good thing to be in a coffee shop, slurping coffee, at 11:30 pm. But last night, boisterously laughing throughout an otherwise intense philosophical conversation, slurping coffee until midnight was exactly a good thing.
I spent the night working and talking with a close friend of mine, in what’s become a routine of ours: late night “cofficing,” a term he coined, that sometimes is more work than conversation, and other times more conversation than work, but is always exactly what we need.</description></item><item><title>Trying to Overcome the Numbers that Rule My Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 20:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never considered myself a “numbers” person. I don’t mean I wasn’t good at math (Mathlete, y’all!), but I care more about stories than stats. On the Myers-Briggs Typology Instrument, for example, my F to T (Feeling to Thinking) ratio is the most unbalanced, and I’m a _strong _F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I do — every &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> I do — while seemingly disparate, is all connected by that trait. Every little project or endeavor I undertake is driven by my goal of making the world a safer place for all people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it’s as surprising to me as it might be to you how numbers-driven my day-to-day life is, and how much I find myself trying to turn that part of my brain off so I can focus on the present. The numbers eat at me, often glaring at me from within little red circles, screaming “Click me! Make me go away!” Others are tucked away within more complex websites or spreadsheets, whispering more gently, but still persuasively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a small taste of the numbers that are almost always whizzing around my brain, attempting to distract me from the task at hand. Every one of these things pops into my head at once when I wake up every morning, then attempts to suckle my brainjuice every minute of every hour I’m awake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a Bigger “Us” and a Smaller “Them”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 03:53:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</guid><description>Today I read a fantastic interview with Bills Clinton and Gates on _Wired. _I highly recommend reading the whole thing, because a lot of great things were said. These are two people who lived incredible, noteworthy lives, retired, then, for no other reason than because, proceeded to start second incredible, noteworthy lives.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m Glad Chivalry is Dead, From The Perspective of A Man Who Actually Likes Women</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 02:54:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</guid><description>There’s this article, “Why Chivalry is Dead, From a Man’s Perspective,” from John Picciuto on _Elite Daily _that’s popped up in my Facebook newsfeed a lot. It’s been shared by my friends of varying genders with captions like “Amen” and “FTW” and “Finally.</description></item><item><title>I Miss Wondering</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier tonight, I turned the burner on high and while I was waiting for my rice to come to a full boil I had a thought: “I wonder if rice cooked in beer would be good.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, I would have likely wondered that for quite a while. It may have been on my mind while I ate my boring water-based rice. It may have popped into my mind tomorrow, or the next day, when I next saw rice or beer. Visions of beer-based rice recipes might have danced in my belly. I may have wondered about it for a week (or ten) before I finally giving in, cooking it, and exiting Wonderland for Knowville.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of that happened, because Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the water (boring) in the pot began boiling I already knew if “beer rice” was a thing, what it would taste like (delicious), exactly how to make it, and what types of recipes it would be good in (ALL OF THEM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let Your Teacher Grade Your Test</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/let-your-teacher-grade-your-test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 04:38:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/let-your-teacher-grade-your-test/</guid><description>I did a show earlier today, which isn’t that odd, or thought-provoking. I do shows a lot. It’s what I do. But the show today was different from any show I’ve done, because it was over Skype. That was a first for me.</description></item><item><title>For One Week, Starting Now, I Will Tell No Lies</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 01:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</guid><description>I lie a lot. I didn’t realize that until I started following Sam Harris, the Author of Lying, on Twitter (I highly recommend following him, by the way — dude’s got a great first name). A few days ago one of my Twitter buds retweeted his challenge below, which is how I was introduced to Sam (great name, by the way) and his work.</description></item><item><title>Working to End Oppression Makes More Sense as a Republican Value than a Democratic One</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 18:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</guid><description>First, chill out. I promise I’ll make this make sense. Heck, if you can read this entire essay with an open mind before loading your mouth-canon for a bombardment my way, I’ll even wager you’ll agree with me. Disclosure: I’m not a member of either the Republican or Democratic Parties, but identify as a socially-conscious independent.</description></item><item><title>Reading the Fine Print</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/reading-the-fine-print/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 05:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/reading-the-fine-print/</guid><description>Sometimes1 we overlook what’s truly important2, and inadvertently focus far too much of our attention3 on things that are inconsequential4. We’re tricked5, by ourselves6, and by influences in our life7, into being mislead without even realizing we’re being mislead8. It’s the most dangerous form of dishonesty9, because it exploits our inherent want to trust10, and turns our own good faith against us11, like a knife with a sharp handle and a dull blade12.</description></item><item><title>Hiding Behind a Keyboard: The Terror of the Unknown</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 04:13:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</guid><description>I used to be terrified of any sort of public speaking. This terror was justified by my complete inability to speak to any group larger than 2 – 3. Before my first semester at Purdue, during orientation, we were always asked to introduce ourselves with our “Name, Hometown, Major” — something I couldn’t do without fumbling over my words and screwing something up.</description></item><item><title>Why I Ride the Bus</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-i-ride-the-bus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 15:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-i-ride-the-bus/</guid><description>I ride the bus.
I ride the bus because it’s good for the environment
&amp;amp; it makes for a smaller carbon footprint
&amp;amp; it helps me afford my month-to-month rent
But truly none of that is it.
I try to ride every day</description></item><item><title>I Don’t Believe in God, but I Do Believe in A Lot</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 17:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</guid><description>I don’t believe in God. Saying this is easier now than it was when I was a kid, because I was struggling equal parts internally with my lack of faith and externally with the reactions of people in my life when they found out.</description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Halloween, As Viewed Through Many Eyes</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/halloween-through-many-eyes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 19:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/halloween-through-many-eyes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Halloween has always been my favorite holiday. It is the one time of the year when it is acceptable — even encouraged — to be whoever, or whatever, you want to be — to pretend, to take chances, to wear gaudy lipstick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing up, crafting costumes and living as someone else for a night was something I looked forward to the entire year — far more than the punch-you-in-your-pancreas sugar overdose, though who doesn’t prefer their apples covered in a gravy of melted sugar and butter, the way God intended. As an adult (or at least as “adult” as I ever plan on getting), so much of my time and work is focused on helping people understand identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The irony is not lost on me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 19:26:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I created this because it’s been a long time coming, and I decided to stop letting time slip away.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People have asked again and again if I have a personal blog. I do not. Well, I _did _not. I do now. And I will keep it up for at least one year. 365 days. 12 months. And probably about 500,000 words.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>