<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intentionality on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/intentionality/</link><description>Recent content in Intentionality on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/intentionality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>Gender Expression vs. Cueing, &amp; How Sometimes They’re One-in-the-Same</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</guid><description>Last week I gave three back-to-back shows at the Fashion Institute of Technology in New York. I was their “Diversity Speaker” for orientation, a product of some of the orientation leaders seeing me speak at a conference. I’ve said this a bunch: I loved doing those shows, and I heart FIT.</description></item><item><title>How I Keep Track of 50 Projects at Once (&amp; Maintain Some Sanity)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 02:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</guid><description>I’m currently in the process of finishing two books, starting another, publishing two new sexuality models, three new live social justice comedy shows, running half a dozen volunteer-based initiatives, building I’m-not-even-sure-how-many websites, and the list goes on. It’s a lot. And as I type that, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>Choosing to Love Instead of Allowing Ourselves to Hate</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:13:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</guid><description>It’s gotten far easier to allow ourselves to hate than it is to choose to love.
We’re getting it from all sides. Controversy sells better than sex, and when you combine the two you have pretty much every magazine you see in the grocery store check-out line.</description></item><item><title>The 3 Ingredients to a Happy Existence</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intentionality, Mindfulness, and Minimalism are all you need, beyond basic biological requirements (clean water, nutritious food, human touch, etc.), to live a happy existence. This is what I’ve come to believe. I’ll define what I mean by all three, and talk about their relationship to one another, but first I want to talk about “happiness.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t aspire toward being happy all the time, nor do I recommend it. I don’t think of happiness as existing at the opposite end of sadness, nor do I think that sadness is inherently bad. All emotions have value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think of happiness on a continuum with lack of happiness on the other end, sadness on a continuum with lack of sadness on the other end, and so forth. Experiencing happiness doesn’t necessarily make you less sad — The Barenaked Ladies kew this: “I’m the kind of guy who laughs at a funeral.”&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>