<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/</link><description>Learn about gender, sexuality, &amp; social justice with Sam Killermann. Your free online resource for everything from genderbread people to LGBTQ vocabulary.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 9:3:1 Learning Rule</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/aditya-vyas-786151-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>When you’re trying to learn a new thing — a skill, talent, instrument, sport, language, anything — there are a million things that can derail you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard not to become fatigued, discouraged, frustrated, lose sight of your goal, or become distracted by a brighter light in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even assuming you get everything else right, and none of those detours push you off path, it’s still common to plateau early and stop making progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rule is to prevent that from happening: &lt;strong>say hello to the 9:3:1 Rule, a guide for how to allocate your time while learning a new thing.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="three-ways-to-learn-spectating-studying-and-practicing">Three ways to learn: Spectating, Studying, and Practicing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The premise that I based this rule on is that there are three distinct ways to learn a new thing, and that you need to be intentional about how much time you spend doing each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, here’s how we’re going to think about these three different learning methods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spectating&lt;/strong> is the time you spend watching the pros, the savants, the experts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Studying&lt;/strong> is the time you spend reading how-tos, theory, technical guides, and watching walk-throughs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Practicing&lt;/strong> is the time you spend actually doing the thing, going through the motions, regardless of how clumsy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It’s easy to blur the lines between these ideas. And doing so easily fuels procrastination (or allows you to give into &lt;a href="https://stevenpressfield.com/2013/11/resistance-and-self-loathing/">Resistance&lt;/a>). So we’re not going to. We’re going to create a hard, indelible line between these in our minds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are not practicing while you’re studying. You’re not studying while you’re spectating. And you’re not spectating while you’re practicing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is this important? Because of how we’re going to be structuring our learning time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="optimal-learning-requires-three-times-as-much-studying-as-spectating-and-three-times-as-much-practicing-as-studying">Optimal learning requires three times as much studying as spectating. And three times as much practicing as studying.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is the gist of the 9:3:1 rule, where…&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>9 is the proportion of time spent practicing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 is the proportion of time spent studying&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 is the proportion of time spent spectating&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So if you spectate a pro for 10 minutes, you should spend 30 studying the theory/concepts behind what you watched, and another 90 practicing the the techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tripling the time spectating with your studying will help you better understand what you’re seeing. You’ll notice experts doing things you otherwise wouldn’t have &lt;em>been able&lt;/em> to notice. Things that were invisible to the untrained eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tripling the time studying with your practicing will make sure that you don’t get bogged down with lots of theory and conceptual knowledge that you can’t put into, well, &lt;em>practice&lt;/em>. You need to develop the muscle memory, dexterity, strength, and endurance to act on what you see an expert doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it possible to learn guitar solos from watching a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PbwUH_eJ2fk">60 minute Jimi Hendrix live concert video&lt;/a>? If you spend another three hours studying (e.g., techniques used, musical scales) and nine hours practicing what you spectated. Minimum. Sure! You can absolutely learn from spectating Jimi Hendrix.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="you-still-have-to-do-all-three-well">You still have to do all three well.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Maintaining the right proportions of time isn’t enough to get you to excel at a new skill, and to continue improving through plateaus. We might say it’s necessary, but not sufficient. You still have to use that time well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Practicing well, studying well, and spectating well are three skills in their own right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not going to get into the specifics on that in this post, because I want to keep this focused on the 9:3:1 rule. And it’s hard to make generalities on how to do these things well that would apply to all skills or domains of learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here are some ways to do each one poorly:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Poor spectating&lt;/strong> would be time spent watching people who (1) aren’t amazing at the thing you’re trying to learn, or (2) people who are able to do it in ways that would never be attainable by you (e.g., spectating Michael Phelps swimming if you don’t also have the wingspan of a pterodactyl and webbed feat);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Poor studying&lt;/strong> would be (1) learning about concepts that are at a higher level than you’re ready to practice, for which you don’t already have the foundational learning, or (2) learning from sources that aren’t directed toward practice, that are too theoretical or foundational to be applied (e.g., reading a book about quantum physics because you know that gravity plays a big role in bocce);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Poor practicing&lt;/strong> would be (1) jumping right to the end, and trying to do the completed skill instead of breaking it into smaller skills, or (2) spending all of your time repeating something easy and simple instead of challenging yourself (e.g., repeating the cyrilic alphabet over and over won’t get you to speaking Russian, no matter how beautiful your &lt;strong>Ж&lt;/strong> sounds).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="tweak-the-ratio-to-overcome-your-particular-plateau">Tweak the Ratio to Overcome your Particular Plateau&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is the 9:3:1 ratio perfect? Handed down the by gods? &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_ratio">Golden&lt;/a>? It is not. It’s a ratio that I made up and enforce for myself as I’m learning new things because it’s helped me break through countless plateaus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while I’ve tried other ratios (e.g., 4:2:1), the 9:3:1 has applied nicely to 90% of the things I’ve tried to learn intentionally over the years, so its what I default to. (Is that 90% made up? I’ll give you two guesses.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I would suggest that you go with it until you are sure that it’s the ratio that is slowing you down, not quality of your learning from each method. Because enforcing this ratio helps automatically prevent a bunch of common stalls to learning that result in plateaus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 9:3:1 ratio helps you prevent spending too much time spectating pros (because it’s fun), or studying (because it requires zero vulnerability).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also prevents you from spending too much time &lt;em>only&lt;/em> practicing and beating a dead horse, making no headway (because you’re missing some crucial knowledge, or don’t have a clear role model for what the next level looks like).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That all said, there are certainly times when I have to mix things up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There might be a point, for example, where you no longer need any spectating or studying to break through a plateau because it’s purely a physical constraint (&lt;em>no amount of book readin’ is gonna get you to bend like that — you just gotta bend&lt;/em>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ask yourself the following questions and use the answers to guide your adjustment to the ratio to break through any particular plateau:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Am I stuck because I don’t have a clear enough idea in my head of what the next level of proficiency would look like? (If so, you need more time spectating)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Am I stuck because I don’t have necessary conceptual knowledge, or a working understanding of a skill or technique I need? (If so, you need more time studying)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Am I stuck because I don’t have the muscle memory, dexterity, strength, endurance, or flexibility (physical or mental) that I need? (If so, you need more time practicing)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The most important thing about this ratio isn’t the relative proportions, but the truth it imparts and reinforces: you need to do all three of these things — spectating, studying, and practicing — to increasing degrees in order to continue improving at a skill.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="and-remember-that-learning-also-requires-recovery-and-celebration">And remember that learning also requires recovery and celebration.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Learning isn’t — and cannot be — a constant, unceasing pursuit. You need to take breaks to do at least two other things: recover (when you’re fatigued) and celebrate (when you reach milestones).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like to think of these like summer breaks and graduations. Take time to rest, do other things, drink water, allow your brain and your body to bounce back. And also make sure you’re noting how far you’ve come. Show off to friends, keep a journal, record videos, or set up fun milestone challenges (like enrolling in competitions) — whatever works for you and the thing you’re learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just make sure you’re structuring both recovery and celebration into your learning, as well as being intentional about the time you spend spectating, studying, and practicing — and &lt;a href="https://slate.com/culture/2016/05/oh-the-places-youll-go-is-the-top-selling-book-for-graduation-season-but-it-doesn-t-actually-offer-great-advice.html">oh, the places you’ll go&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rage du Jour</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rage-du-jour.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>How many things have you been mad about in the past week? How many meltdown-level shares have you seen in your social feeds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every day there’s something new that my entire social bubble is furious about (at least if feels that way). The &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the backlash for some stupid thing a politician did. Or the horrible take a celebrity had in response to a current event. Or a current event that isn’t getting the right coverage from the news. Or, sometimes, it’s rage about rage: the fact that people are mad about something become the thing other people are mad about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In special cases the rage will last more than a day. But that requires a really sticky subject. Something that can keep our focus amidst the barrage of incoming candidates of rageworthiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to stay genuinely mad about something for a long time. It takes energy, effort, fuel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s easy to get mad about a new thing if the conditions are right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on social media the conditions are prime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social networks aren’t neutral when it comes to sentimentality. They’re &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@tobiasrose/the-enemy-in-our-feeds-e86511488de">tuned for the spreading of fear and outrage&lt;/a>. It’s where the dollars are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it feels like &lt;em>everyone is mad about this&lt;/em>, but in reality it’s just that Facebook is surfacing the angry shares. The rants. The &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/">cancelations&lt;/a>. Because Facebook knows you’re more likely to engage with that. Pile on. Click the link, like, or comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Because we think everyone is mad about something, everyone gets mad about something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this isn’t to say that Facebook (or Supreme Leader Zuck) are doing this because they &lt;em>want you to be mad.&lt;/em> They don’t. They don’t really care. That’s not the conspiracy. This is a far more mundane dystopia: they just want you to show up and click.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Facebook needs to bring you back every day, dozens of times a day. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44640959">It needs you addicted.&lt;/a> What better way to do that than a new rage every day?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The algorithm doesn’t even need to know &lt;em>what&lt;/em> it’s showing you. It’s not programmed to show you the latest political dustup, celebrity misstep, corporate ethics breach, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s just listening for what gets the most reactions, and showing that to as many people as it can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rXaENvEzKTY?t=23">It’s Lloyd in &lt;em>Dumb and Dumber&lt;/em> asking&lt;/a>, “What’s the soup du jour?” and getting “It’s the soup-of-the-day” as a reply, then saying “Mmm. That sounds good. I’ll have that.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’re more items on the menu, we just don’t get to see them. The menu is off limits. It’s hidden. You can only order from what the server offers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the more often you order the &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>, the more it’ll be offered to you. “Want the usual?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can try to decline. By not clicking on the link, liking the post, replying with a comment, or weighing in with a little red rage face. Just scroll on by after you read the post and realize it’s today’s &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>. Opt out. Right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, even that won’t work. Facebook &lt;a href="https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2015/06/news-feed-fyi-taking-into-account-time-spent-on-stories/">doesn’t need you to click anything to know what you’re reading and what’s truly engaging you&lt;/a>. Spend a few seconds looking at a post before scrolling past it and consider your order placed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just paying attention to the &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em> is enough to get the next plate fired up in the kitchen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, participating in it will get you more of it. Jumping on the pile will give you an unlimited supply of piles to jump on. Sharing your own &lt;em>Rage du Jours&lt;/em>, becoming a tastemaker, will create a social media experience that is defined by anger.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are what you eat. And I know that I don’t want to be an embodiment of rage. Keeping up with the latest &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em> is exhausting, it’s empty, it’s never-ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But opting out from active participation isn’t enough for you to have a &lt;em>Jour&lt;/em> free from &lt;em>Rage.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Want to guarantee something more nourishing makes it to your table? There’s really only one way:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to a different restaurant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancel Debts Not People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/anthony-delanoix-492581-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Elizabeth Warren has thrown her hat in on a bold idea that’s been in the air for a long time: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@teamwarren/im-calling-for-something-truly-transformational-universal-free-public-college-and-cancellation-of-a246cd0f910f">cancel student loan debt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not interest rate decreases, or refinancing, or other half-measures, but an all out cancelation of up to $50K in student loan debt for anyone whose income is $100K or less. Combined with universal free public higher education going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was first introduced to this idea back in the early 2010s the &lt;a href="https://rollingjubilee.org/">Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a>, a project by &lt;a href="https://strikedebt.org/">Strike Debt&lt;/a>, which has now evolved into &lt;a href="https://debtcollective.org/">The Debt Collective&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their project leveraged one of the most dysfunctional aspects of student loan debt: the fact that the debts get bundled and resold, over and over, for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling Jubilee raised $701,317 dollars (a few of which were mine, even as a broke post-grad student living under a pile of debt) and bought bundles of debt worth a total of $31,982,455.76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, instead of trying to collect those debts, they abolished them. Poof. Gone. No more debt for the people whose loans were part of those bundles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those numbers highlight how broken, and at this point imaginary, the entire debt-debtor relationship is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what world does $700K buy $31M?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The broken world we currently live in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The organizers of Rolling Jubilee were clear that their project was intended to be a spark — “&lt;a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/rolling-jubilee-spark-not-solution/">not a solution to the debt crisis&lt;/a>.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years later, it looks like that idea is ready to catch fire. Our world might be on the verge of transition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As Elizabeth Warren raises the progressive bar for any would-be Democratic nominee for the 2020 US general election, other candidates — and their supporters — will have to come down on one side or the other of this issue. All this in a primary that is shaping up to have social justice issues as central platform points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I can’t help but celebrate this as a potential material social justice gain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Incurring debt in order to pursue higher education is a barrier to accessing many currently-elitist dimensions of society. Requiring a college degree (and, increasingly, a graduate degree of some kind) is an effective way to keep historically disenfranchised people disenfranchised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it’s a barrier that disproportionately affects poor and lower-middle-class people, first generation (or generationally poor) people, undocumented people, and people of color. &lt;a href="https://studentloanhero.com/featured/study-student-loans-weigh-heaviest-black-hispanic/">“Student loan debt weighs more heavily on students of color than on their white counterparts.”&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re in a moment when a lot of social justice advocates, activists, and educators — myself included — are struggling to articulate exactly what policy, or change, we seek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of social justice action that is dominating the mainstream right now can be summed up as “&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cancel_culture">cancel culture&lt;/a>.” At least in online activism, it is the zeitgeist many of us are currently swept up in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can’t know how effective “canceling” people for bigoted, oppressive, or problematic behaviors will be in the long run for advancing the goals of social justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s clear that &lt;em>if&lt;/em> the tactic is effective, it can only be through a series of indirect, convoluted events — one thing leading to another, a butterfly effect of culture change and mindset shifting. And its success will mean an astronomical body count of lives derailed. This alone, for many of us, makes it unappealing as a tactic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abolishing student loan debt paints a picture in sharp contrast to the tactic of canceling people in the name of social justice. The distance between cause and effect is one signature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Canceling student loan debt would have an immediate effect on people’s lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits are obvious, intersectional, and massive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abolishing debt recognizes people’s humanity, instead of denying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The organizing principles surrounding canceling student debt foster solidarity, instead of undermining it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can serve as a concrete answer to “What do you mean by social justice?” A rallying cry for social justice that invigorates a jaded, disinterested, and disengaged majority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m here for that. And I’ll happily wear it on my chest.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator" />
&lt;p>&lt;em>This post, &lt;a href="https://everyshirtispolitical.com/cancel-debts-not-people/" title="Cancel Debts Not People" rel="canonical">Cancel Debts Not People&lt;/a>, originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://everyshirtispolitical.com" title="Every Shirt is Political">Every Shirt is Political&lt;/a>, where I created a shirt, print, and stencil based on this idea.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Problem of Progressivism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/jcob-nasyr-baby-sea-turtle.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>With more and more people talking about “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;oq=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.4775j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">the left cannibalizing itself&lt;/a>” and “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;oq=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2521j1j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">liberals eating their own&lt;/a>,” or how “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;oq=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5472j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">democrats need to unite to defeat Trump&lt;/a>,” we need to keep reminding ourselves and others about the problem of progressivism — instead of just beating the dead horse that is the problems &lt;em>within&lt;/em> progressivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start with the second one, because that’s what everyone won’t stop yelling about, and I’m afraid if I don’t do a little yelling you won’t hear me out on the part of this that I think is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here it is, me jumping on the dogpile: the left has some problems, and we’re getting in our own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that is true for the “right,” the “center,” liberals, progressives, leftists, Libertarians, Republicans, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally every political camp has problems. Any collection of humans with a count greater than 0 has problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, why is the trope of “liberals eat their own” so pervasive?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a ton of answers to that. Pick your favorite: fear that truly progressive policies are popular, deep-seated White supremacy combined with “demographic shifts,” people repeat things they hear on TV, “but identity politics!” All of those likely carry some-to-a-lot of truth, depending the person spreading the trope in any given moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of those are are the true Why. The one Why to Rule them All.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Why of Power is the explanation that won’t change — regardless of trends in policy, activism, and culture — and will forever be relevant. And it’s the thing that makes progressivism distinct from conservatism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It’s the problem&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>of&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>progressivism.&lt;/strong> Namely, the problem that progressivism exists to solve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That problem is simply this: How do we create a future that improves upon our present and our past, without repeating old mistakes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“How do we go forward?” Not back. Not stay here. &lt;em>Forward&lt;/em>. Somewhere different. Somewhere we’ve never been.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do that, we need new ideas. That’s not just an empty cliché. There is tautologically no way around it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New ideas are like baby sea turtles born on a wide stretch of beach: vulnerable, easy to attack, and unlikely to survive, but numerous enough that the ones that do survive are enough to help the species flourish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The turtles who make it to the ocean do so &lt;em>because&lt;/em> their siblings die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe the turtle who made it was slightly faster, slightly better camouflaged, or just luckier than the turtles scuffling around who didn’t. From our view, it would be hard to see them apart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For every progressive idea-turned-reality that we take for granted now, there were a multitude of ideas that were up against it — an attitudinal race across the beach. And defeating those ideas was &lt;em>necessary&lt;/em> for the new idea to survive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we talk about “progressive infighting” we’re talking about the very mechanism that makes progress happen.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most ideas aren’t great ideas. So it’s beneficial that they don’t all make it into the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of great ideas get shut down because they’re too early, too scary, or delivered by the wrong messenger. This is the penalty we pay by challenging ideas at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We forget about the turtles who didn’t make it. Call it &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias">survivorship bias&lt;/a>, or blame it on a form of socio-political homeostasis: we quickly adjust to new normals, take things for granted, and forget about the struggle required to birth them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look around your world right now. The device you’re reading this on, the place you’re reading it, and everything surrounding you are the byproduct of the ideas that survived. The technology, relative safety, access, agency, and more that are central to your life are gifts of historical progressivism. They’re the turtles that survived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every progressive idea that we take for granted now was impossibly naïve, impractical, and — if you were just going by the odds — really &lt;em>shouldn’t&lt;/em> exist. &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/">Take public libraries for an example&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why isn’t conservatism afflicted with the same problems as progressivism? Why aren’t we always hearing about “the right eating its own”?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because modern conservatism is trying to solve a different problem. “How do we &lt;em>not&lt;/em> go forward?” Or, in more extreme cases, the problem of “How do we revert back to how things were?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Progressivism is an external display of vulnerability, while conservatism is a rejection of the vulnerable.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s not meant to be an appraisal of progressivism or slam of conservatism. It’s just a characterization of how the two ideologies diverge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Want to see the difference between these two mentalities play out in a non-political, non-sea-turtle sacrificing way?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ask a parent of multiple kids what it’s like picking a restaurant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Progressivism is the parent listing a bunch of different places the family might go for dinner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conservatism is the arms-folded, indignant children repeating, “No.” And when asked where they want to go, the one kid who says, “I don’t care, just none of those places,” and the other says, “I want chicken nuggets again.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a parent and that example makes you feel worse than a newborn sea turtle, sorry for highlighting your daily trauma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a conservative and that example feels like a slam, pick a new restaurant. We’re sick of chicken nuggets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updated my /Now: Working on Social Justice, Minus Dogma + Facilitator Cards</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/now-april-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 23:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/now-april-2019/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><description>&lt;p>I updated samuelkillermann.com/now with the two main projects I’m working on right meow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read all about the the &lt;a href="https://www.samuelkillermann.com/now/2019-april/">SJMD Course &amp;amp; Community and Facilitator Cards here&lt;/a>. I explain what’s my goals are, how I’m (co-)creating them, and roughly when you can expect to see them in the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public Libraries Shouldn’t Exist</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:37:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-rooftop-by-sam-killermann.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Usually, when I’m at home in Austin, I work in coffee shops. Today, I’m working from our gobsmackingly beautiful public library. And I can’t help but repeatedly ask myself “What would happen if someone pitched the idea of a public library today?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a broken record in my brain. An audio loop. It plays every time I turn a corner in this space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What would it sound like to argue for the idea of a public library in 2019?”&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-window-by-sam-killermann-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1375 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-window-by-sam-killermann-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-window-by-sam-killermann-225x300.jpg 225w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-window-by-sam-killermann.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally try to spend $10 – $15 whenever I set up camp to work for a few hours in a coffee shop. To pay my share. To ensure my favorite local haunts can compete with Starbucks. To not feel like a burden. I have a monthly “cofficing” budget dedicated to this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here it’s different. I came in, found a perfect working space, connected to the wifi, and didn’t spend a dollar.&lt;figure class="wp-block-image alignwide">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-garden-by-sam-killermann-1024x669.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1374 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-garden-by-sam-killermann-1024x669.jpg 1024w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-garden-by-sam-killermann-300x196.jpg 300w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-garden-by-sam-killermann-768x501.jpg 768w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-garden-by-sam-killermann.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that’s where the dissonance hits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One one hand, &lt;em>of course&lt;/em> I didn’t pay. This is a public library. It would be weird to have to pay. But it’s only weird because we’ve accepted the idea of a public library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, the public library, as an idea, today, in modern political discourse, is anything but an &lt;em>of course&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, the idea of a public library would be a radical idea. One that would be labeled as “socialist” (with the scary, fear-invoking pronunciation of socialist). Support of public libraries would be a “far left” litmus test — used by supporters and opposers to assess candidates. It would be risky. Even &lt;a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/most-democratic-2020-candidates-reject-socialist-label-but-back-socialist-agenda_2836286.html">politicians who are advancing socialist causes&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/posteverything/wp/2018/07/02/democrats-have-run-from-socialism-while-embracing-socialist-policies/?utm_term=.fd718d68f89d">don’t want to be called “socialists.”&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s so hard to find a place where you can exist without paying money in 2019.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The phrase “cost of living” comes to mind. We often gloss over how literal it is, how expensive it is to simply be alive. Everywhere I go I need a credit card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile here, in this library — in &lt;em>my&lt;/em> library — my wallet has stayed in my pocket. I haven’t even seen a place where I &lt;em>could&lt;/em> spend money.&lt;figure class="wp-block-image alignwide">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-entrance-by-sam-killermann-1-1024x628.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1377 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-entrance-by-sam-killermann-1-1024x628.jpg 1024w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-entrance-by-sam-killermann-1-300x184.jpg 300w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-entrance-by-sam-killermann-1-768x471.jpg 768w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-entrance-by-sam-killermann-1.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />&lt;/figure> &lt;figure class="wp-block-image alignwide">&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-seating-by-sam-killermann-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1376 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-seating-by-sam-killermann-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-seating-by-sam-killermann-300x225.jpg 300w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-seating-by-sam-killermann-768x576.jpg 768w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/austin-public-library-seating-by-sam-killermann.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Money mediating every aspect of our life is one of the byproducts of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neoliberalism">neoliberalism&lt;/a>, the political &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8CrOL-ydFMI">water&lt;/a> in which all of us have been swimming for a few decades now (also a buzzy-type word that a lot of people use to mean different things).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neoliberalism is why it makes sense to pay for childcare, a ride to the airport, help moving your stuff to your new apartment, and more. And why it would now feel weird to expect any of those things to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> cost money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So many parts of our life that a few years or decades ago would have been provided by the commons — you’d ask a neighbor, or a friend — are now things we pay for. And every day new aspects of humanity, relationships, and interpersonal life are being capitalized, commodified, added to our gross domestic product.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not sure what’s more innovative: the apps we use to pay for things we used to count on as communal, or the magic that leads to so many of us applauding it. And forgetting there was ever another way. Forgetting that we didn’t used to pay for this particular dimension of human connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so it’s neoliberalism, at least in part, that makes the idea of a public library feel so insane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine the idea of a public library hadn’t been invented yet. Or, to make this case even stronger, it had been proposed in the past, but shot down (“Socialism!” “Boot straps!” “Etcetera!”).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, in this world we live in (where it’s weirder to ask a friend for a ride to the airport than it is to hire a temporary friend with our phone to drive us), bask in the impossibility of the idea of a public library. I bet you can play it all out in your head. Who would be for it? Who against? What would the debate sound like? What would Fox News say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not trying to over-emphasize the uniqueness of our current political climate. It’s easier to imagine public libraries never having been invented or normalized at any point in history than it is to imagine them becoming a thing — that is, but for the fact that they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is true for almost every good part of society that we take for granted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We forget, or are entirely unaware of, the fight that took place to secure it for us. The alternatives. The failed experiments. The 1 in whatever-large-number odds that landed us where we are now. A thousand times over, at a thousand different points in history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clean water. Electricity. The internet. Plumbing. Roads. Safe food. Vaccinations. The list goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>None of what’s good was guaranteed. It all happened against great odds. Even you being born — yes, &lt;em>you&lt;/em> — was an unlikely chance (&lt;a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/probability-being-born_n_877853">about 1 in 400 trillion&lt;/a>, if you’re counting). And I think it’s good that you were born. &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/">I hope you do, too&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, against the odds, here I am. In this space. This beautiful public space. Working at a table that shouldn’t exist, in a building that shouldn’t exist, surrounded by publicly-shared books and technology that shouldn’t exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m filled with &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/">wonder&lt;/a> that public libraries exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that there exists so many other artifacts of some past struggle, ideas and works that add beauty to our commons, improving all of our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially because they shouldn’t exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because they’d be borderline impossible to defend or rationalize or make sense of. Because they fly in the face of political convention, feasibility, “human nature,” and “the market.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are proof that we’re better than we allow ourselves to know. That we can be better than we allow ourselves to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public libraries are miracles. And with that thought, my mind starts spinning with two new questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What else shouldn’t exist, but does?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What else shouldn’t exist, that we need to create?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When Ambition is Hiding</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/verne-ho-23882-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Consider a few alternatives. Let’s say I told you:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>I want to remove every unhealthy habit, food, and mindset from my life, and I&amp;#8217;m going to start tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>I&amp;#8217;m going to eat less sugar, starting tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When tomorrow comes, which one are you likely to hold me accountable to? Which might you help me excuse when I fall short? Which are you actually expecting me to do? Or even realistically try?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do a few more with those questions in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I say:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my country to 100% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my local school district to 50% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Or:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to end racism, globally.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to help local people of color, and other disenfranchised people, register to vote and get to the polls.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s plenty to get the point I’m going to make, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But first, here’s what I’m not about to say:&lt;/strong> that any of the As above — the lofty, admirable, pie-in-the-sky ambitions — are in any way bad, undesirable, or something I’m advocating against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want all of those things. I have, at different points in my life, said all of those things, in some way or another. And I don’t even like &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/">thinking of myself as ambitious&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here’s all I want to point out:&lt;/strong> sometime we set the bar so high because it gives us an excuse when we can’t clear it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody will blame you if you don’t fully turn around your life and become the epitome of all things healthy. Nobody will blame you if you don’t revolutionize the energy system of your country. Nobody will blame you if you don’t dismantle a global system of oppression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone will understand. They’ll help you list all the forces you were up against. They’ll give you a hug for your good intentions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you can’t eat a little less sugar; or change some policies at the school in your neighborhood; or register a few previously-non-voters and get them to the polls — well, now we’re in a different world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, you’re not going to get as much understanding. They might instead list a bunch of actions you could have taken, but didn’t. They’ll say intentions aren’t enough, we need outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this way, lofty ambitions give us a great place to hide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They shield us from specific actions that we could do today. From the accountability, compromises, and personal discomforts the goal would necessitate. From the pointed finger that says we failed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being specific, staking a claim, arguing for a step forward — anything you might be held to — is vulnerable. And vulnerability is scary. It’s also necessary if you want to accomplish anything real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This goes for changing yourself as much as changing the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss, you’ll land among the stars.” is a quote that someone might share with us, to comfort us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But we didn’t actually shoot for the moon. We didn’t even build a rocket. Or draw up the blueprints for the rocket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All we &lt;em>did&lt;/em> was we &lt;em>said&lt;/em> we were going to shoot for the moon. And we said it a lot, over and over, and got a lot of people excited for us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And not just our moon, but every moon in our solar system. Hell — why not every moon in the galaxy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we’re going to not do this, we might as well not do something worth talking about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Simple Things You Can Do to Curb Your Phone Addiction Right Now</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/rawpixel-236143-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>A lot of us are addicted to our phones. If you’ve started to see why this might not be the best thing ever, and want to ween yourself off of that tantalizingly non-nourishing blue glow, you’re in good company. This is something I’ve been thinking about, and experimenting with, for a few years now. Following are three things you knock out in about 15 minutes, that will benefit you for weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I get into those, I want to be clear: I’m talking about the colloquial, not clinical, usage of the term “addiction.” In this post, I’m not staking my flag in the hill that “phone addiction” is (or isn’t) real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’m talking about here, as addiction, is the compulsive use of our phones. That we’re spending more time poking around our phones than we want to, picking them up and checking the screen before we realize we’re doing it, and that our phones aren’t adding quality to our lives, and might be distracting us from the things we’d actually care about enjoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m talking about how we’re &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/">already dating our phones&lt;/a>, and how &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">little red numbers are trying to rule our lives&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="first-acknowledge-the-problem">First, Acknowledge the Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Maybe you’re not actually dependent upon your phone. Maybe, for you, it’s not something that’s getting in the way of your life, or impinging on your quality time with others. Maybe it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s find out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On iOS, built into the operating system, there’s a feature called Screen Time (Settings –&amp;gt; Screen Time). Before, you had to install an app for this (&lt;a href="https://inthemoment.io/">Moment&lt;/a> was a popular one). This shows you how you’re using your phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Before you open Screen Time or install moment, answer two questions for yourself&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>How much time do you &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to be looking at your phone every day? (In minutes. A range is totally okay.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What apps or functions of your phone do you &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to be spending time using? (e.g., Spotify, Text Messaging, or GPS)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Now, write those two answers down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not going to push for any specific numbers here, nor do I really think that’s a thing that should be applied universally. I just want you to know, for yourself, what &lt;em>you&lt;/em> want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’ve heard from lots of people is they had no idea how much time they were spending on their phone (generally, they were thinking it was &lt;em>much&lt;/em> less than reality), and they also didn’t have a good sense of where the time went. Both of these were true for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Answering these questions before you see the numbers will help you prevent rationalizing away anything you see that you’re not happy about, and also from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moving_the_goalposts">moving the goal posts&lt;/a> when you decide what you’ll do about the numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you didn’t answer those questions first, and then see a number, you might just say “that’s not that bad,” or “everyone uses their phone that much.” Or, you might think, “Okay, I’ll just try to use 10 minutes per day less, and that will be a win.” Neither of those are honest appraisals of the situation. Working against the time or apps you wrote down as your &lt;em>wants&lt;/em>, however, is a great starting place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="second-make-it-less-magical">Second, Make it Less Magical&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Steve Jobs called the iPhone a “revolutionary and magical product.” He couldn’t have been more right. It magically absorbs attention and time without you realizing it, while revolutionizing your life into one of empty multi-tasking, where you can’t focus on and enjoy any one thing at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still see the benefits of having a smartphone, but want to release yourself from its spell? Make it less magical.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="delete-apps-use-the-browser">Delete apps, use the browser.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Most of your most time-sucking apps probably have a mobile-friendly website alternative. It won’t be nearly as easy to use as the app, and might not have as many features, and that’s great!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you’ve found that you’re spending an hour scrolling through your Facebook app every day, and you’re not happy about that, delete the app and start checking your Facebook by opening up your browser and manually typing in &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com">www.facebook.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This small hurdle will give you enough pause to think “Do I really want to be checking Facebook right now?” And the lack of bells and whistles, and inconvenience of not having Facebook one touch and one second away on your home screen, will make it less appealing overall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can do this for most social networking apps, news apps, and other things that are consumption-focused. It won’t work that well for the apps that are interactive or feature-focused like Google Maps, but I’m guessing you’re not feeling like you’re wasting a lot of time pinching and zooming around Google Maps.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="notifications-be-gone">Notifications be gone!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Notifications (from the banners to the beeps) are one of the ways app designers conspire to rob you of your time and attention. And it works. Unless you don’t let it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Start by disabling all of of your notifications, for every app&lt;/strong> (even messaging). To do this, go to: Settings -&amp;gt; Notifications, then set each app to “Off.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(The fewer apps you have, or the more you’ve deleted, the easier this process will be)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Answer this question: “If I’m in the middle of enjoying something deeply, what app or feature on my phone do I want to give permission to ruin that?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, &lt;strong>re-enable notifications only for those few things&lt;/strong> you are giving permission to interrupt your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-more-steps">Add more steps.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Everything in your smartphone is just a few mindless taps and swipes away. Then, before you know it, 45 minutes have passed and you haven’t been doing that thing you wanted to be doing. Adding more steps, more taps, more swipes — and making as many of these &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/mindfulness/">mindful&lt;/a>, instead of mindless — can make a huge difference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you wanted to keep an app, because you want to use it a couple times a day, or once a week, or whatever, but you don’t want to be tempted by it, put it three screens deep within a subfolder. (e.g., I have Instagram on my last page of apps within a folder called “Time Wasting” — I still use it, but not often, and almost never mindlessly)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know that you’ll still check Facebook a ton, even if it’s via your browser, don’t allow Facebook to stay logged in or remember your password, or use incognito mode (e.g., in Chrome) so you have to type in your email and password every time you check it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your problem is that you open your phone too much to check on what’s new, remove the badges (the little red numbers) from your apps, and make it more difficult to open your phone (a 6 digit code instead of 4, a code instead of fingerprint, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally, just take a good look at your habitual patterns that you’re not happy with (notice the ways they are finely oiled machines, where one thing smoothly leads into the next), then throw a few wrenches into the works.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="third-take-away-the-candy">Third, Take Away the Candy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you’ve uninstalled your time-suck apps and disabled attention-sucking features, there’s a more general, all-purpose move that I’ve found really helpful: &lt;strong>change your screen from color to grayscale.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In iOS, here is the path that will allow you to change this setting: Settings –&amp;gt; General –&amp;gt; Accessibility –&amp;gt; Display Accommodations –&amp;gt; Color Filters –&amp;gt; Grayscale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does this do? It takes the eye candy away, and makes using your phone feel more like eating your vegetables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does it work? It helps! It’s not a panacea, but used in conjunction with the above step, it can really help turn down the temptation of picking up your phone every few seconds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like adding additional steps, changing your screen settings doubles as a &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/mindfulness/">mindfulness&lt;/a> trigger, at least for the first few weeks until you get used to it. When you look at your phone, you’ll &lt;em>notice&lt;/em> the grayscale screen, which can prompt you to take a step back and decide “Do I want to be using my phone right now? Or was I just on autopilot?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you absolutely need color for some uses (e.g., for airline tickets), you can turn on an accessibility shortcut for color filters (for iOS: Settings –&amp;gt; General –&amp;gt; Accessibility –&amp;gt; Accessibility Shortcut –&amp;gt; Color Filters), which will allow you to toggle the setting with three quick home button presses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lather-rinse-repeat">Lather, Rinse, Repeat&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Maybe you’re like me. You’ve decided that you need a smartphone in your life (at least right now), but you don’t want it to take over your life. If so, then all of this is going to be an ongoing process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The phones keep getting better, and the apps keep getting better at making you want to use your phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are entire schools of thought and fields of research that are working against you on this front. Ultimately, you’re overpowered, outnumbered, out-funded, and if you keep using your phone you’re going to lose sometimes (if not most times).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still use my phone more than I want to. And I notice that feeling, while it’s happening, more than I used to. That’s my small victory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That prompts me to take a step back, and rethink about ways I might add some positive habits to obstruct my current negative ones, new apps I should delete, and other ways I can tweak my relationship to my phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end goal being for me to be in control of my phone, not the other way around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Creative March</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 23:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/james-forbes-191-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>My last few weeks have been marked by creativity. I love that feeling. I want to make it happen more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bill Gates is frequently quoted for saying, “Most people overestimate what they can do in one year and underestimate what they can do in ten years.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel this contrast more intensely on a smaller scale: &lt;strong>we overestimate what we can do in a day, and underestimate what we can do in a year.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s so easy for me to think of myself as a creative person — a writer, a doodler, a designer, a coder — even when I don’t create anything in a given day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I’m not really a writer when I’m not writing. I’m a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/">reader of political news&lt;/a>, or a dog walker, or a cook, or a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">compulsively rechecking my email because it triggers a dopamine response-er&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been “working on a book for three years” now, but I haven’t truly been &lt;em>working&lt;/em> on that book for three years. I’ve barely worked on it at all. A few minutes here, an hour there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creativity is an act, and one that is so easily sidelined by other actions — anything that feels safer, simpler, easier, or fulfills a shortsighted desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many people do you know who are “working” on things that never get any creative time dedicated to them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many projects are you “working” on that you haven’t sat down in front of for over a week? A month? A year? Ever?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week, I finished and published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/">a book&lt;/a>. The week before I co-created and published a massive &lt;a href="https://thesafezoneproject.com/introducing-safe-zone-train-the-trainer-retreat-guide/">Train-the-Trainer Retreat Guide&lt;/a>. The week before that I wrote a new comedy show. And in between all of that I’ve made major strides in starting two new (secret, for now) projects. And I’ve only checked my email two thousand times (a made up number down from what I assume is my normal two million times per month).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the weeks before that, I was mostly just slogging through administrative stuff. Checking in on old things, closing out 2018. Not really making progress on anything, with only a few essays and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">one edugraphic&lt;/a> to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of that got me reflecting on the ebbs and flows of my own creativity, and wanting to come up with some personal &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/challenge/">challenge&lt;/a> or strategy to get a better grasp on that part of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t want to spend most of my time on tasks that amount to nothing, but feel good in the moment (or at least don’t feel terrifying, like creativity often does).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to spend most of my time creating things that I share with the world, that are durable, that might exist when I’m gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As luck would have it, listening to &lt;a href="https://tim.blog/2019/02/18/jim-collins/">a podcast interview&lt;/a> today with &lt;a href="https://www.jimcollins.com">Jim Collins&lt;/a> gave me an exciting challenge that I’m going to start tonight.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="counting-1000-creative-hours-per-year">Counting 1,000 Creative Hours Per Year&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the interview, Jim talks about a standard that he’s been holding to himself for years. In any given “365 day cycle” (e.g., from Jan 1 to Jan 1, or September 18 to September 18), he needs to be spending at least 1,000 on creative work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He cites this as a creative equivalent to his concept of the &lt;a href="https://www.jimcollins.com/concepts/twenty-mile-march.html">corporate “20 Mile March.”&lt;/a> It’s hard to wrap your mind around the idea of walking across the country. But you might be able to, with intention and determination, march 20 miles. Do that enough times in a row, day-by-day, keeping the pace, and you’ll find yourself on the other coast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The connection being that it’s as hard grasp the idea of your “lifetime of creativity” on any given day as it is to imagine walking from the Pacific Ocean to the Atlantic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of the creative accomplishments that people aspire to (e.g., publishing a book, an art installation in a certain gallery, a column in a magazine) are multi-year endeavors, the culmination of a long march of creativity. If you can keep marching at a pace of 1,000 hours per year, there aren’t many creative goals that are out of reach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The way he keeps track? A simple spreadsheet with three columns:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>A quick review of the day’s events (keywords, things that happened)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The number hours spent on creativity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How he felt, overall/emotionally, about the day on a scale of +2, +1, 0, -1, -2 (with +2 being an amazing day, -2 being a terrible day, and 0 being just an average/fine day)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Every night, before bed (or after he’s finished his work), he recounts the day’s activities, creative hours, and his mood in the spreadsheet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The point? To be able to know, on any given day, whether he’s keeping to that 1,000 hours / year standard. By viewing the aggregates of the past 365 days, past six months (x2), or past three months (x4), he can quickly get a sense of his creative pace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the interview, he said he keeps these running totals displayed in his office for daily motivation and accountability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This idea hit me like a lightning bolt, and I immediately decided I would give it a shot for at least the next 3 months.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-i8217ll-be-attempting-the-challenge">How I’ll Be Attempting the Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every day, for the next 90, I will be logging a brief account of the day, the number of hours I spent on creative work, and my overall mood. While this might sound simple (and might &lt;em>be&lt;/em> simple for a lot of you), I anticipate it being anything but.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally speaking, I’m not a huge fan of “quantified self” type behaviors, and am all around terrible at daily, regimented tasks (I don’t even eat some days). Jim emphasized the importance of this being a real-time, night-by-night assessment (not a hindsight reflection), and I don’t doubt his wisdom there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, if I’m going to stick to this, I need it to be easy-peasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I believe this challenge is worth the friction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Completing this daily log for the next 3 months will give me a solid sense of how much time I’m giving myself to create, what factors contribute to (or correlate with) creative days, and how my overall mood is affected by creative output. All of those are things that, right now, I’m either (a) oblivious about, or (b) harboring intuitions that are likely flat wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-i-created-a-google-form">1. I created a Google Form.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Spreadsheets are already more common in my life than I like. I’d rather not have one be the last thing I look at before I go to sleep every night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, I created a mega simple Google Form (you can &lt;a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="click this link to make a copy of it to your own Google Drive (opens in a new tab)" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1ze5Rzr5yHKfuot4oQn8Ov7P_d8HaCI7YuQgU91Z6pug/copy" target="_blank">click this link to make a copy of it to your own Google Drive&lt;/a>) that I’ll be able to quickly fill out every night.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-i-added-the-form-to-my-phone8217s-home-screen">2. I added the form to my phone’s home screen.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On Safari, you can create an app-like button to any website really easily (sorry Android / other OS people — you’re on your own to search for this). Here’s how:&lt;figure class="wp-block-image alignwide">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/adding-creative-march-form-to-home-screen-1024x585.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1329 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/adding-creative-march-form-to-home-screen-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/adding-creative-march-form-to-home-screen-300x171.jpg 300w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/adding-creative-march-form-to-home-screen-768x439.jpg 768w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/adding-creative-march-form-to-home-screen.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />&lt;figcaption>Tap the “share” icon (the box with the arrow shooting out), tap “add to home screen” (or, if you don’t see it, swipe until you see “more” and tap that), then name it.&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I take my phone’s home screen very seriously, and value a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/">minimalist&lt;/a> welcome every time I greet it. So this will be a little reminder every time I pick up my phone. Perfect!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-i8217ll-fill-it-out-every-night-before-bed">3. I’ll fill it out every night before bed.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Having this form and the home screen link will make it easy for me to spend 1 – 2 minutes every night (max!) filling it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="in-text--mailing-list chameleon-border">
&lt;div class="mailing-list">
&lt;h3 class="chameleon-color">
Fear of Missing Out?
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Join the mailing list&lt;/strong>, get posts in your inbox, or subscribe in other ways to get the latest &amp;amp; greatest.&lt;/p>
&lt;a title="View Subscription Options" class="button" href="https://www.samkillermann.com/subscribe">Show me options.&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
As a bonus, I already have a night time ceremony for my phone (I charge it in a different room from my bedroom) that I can easily co-opt for this task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my &lt;strong>Description of the Day&lt;/strong> I’ll be doing short phrases and keywords including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>meetings / phone calls I had (because my hunch is that these are creativity killers);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>where I worked (from home, coffee shop, airplane, etc.);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>what I was working on;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a snapshot of the flow (all at once, 2 or 3 big chunks, sporadically throughout the day, etc.);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>diet stuff that sticks out (because I’m always experimenting with what I eat/don’t); and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>anything else that I feel like including that day (a long walk with &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BkgEtu2no8W/">Chewie&lt;/a>, a beer with a friend, quality time with bae, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For my &lt;strong>Total Creative Hours&lt;/strong>, I’ll be counting:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Time spent on creating new things (writing, doodling, designing, coding, etc.);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plus the necessary set-up and break-down time (researching, installing software, cleaning paint brushes, etc.);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rounded to the nearest hour (up or down — billing my creativity like a fancy lawyer).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>More importantly, I &lt;em>won’t be counting&lt;/em>: time spent in email, on checking numbers or analytics of things, on social media, doing spontaneous FreshBooks accounting, or all the other things I do to procrastinate the real stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, for my &lt;strong>Overall Mood&lt;/strong>, I’ll be using a similar metric as Jim, with a +2 being reserved for those amazing days that really stick out, -2 being reserved for dumpster fires, and most days landing somewhere in between.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="it-begins-tonight-i8217ll-keep-you-posted">It Begins Tonight (I’ll keep you posted)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Like with some of my other challenges, I’ll update this post or write a follow-up if I hit roadblocks, take a detour, or stumble upon something that I find really beneficial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re marching along with me, &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/contact/">let me know&lt;/a>! I’d love to hear about any tips you’ve found useful for the trip.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator" />
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 1:&lt;/strong> I’m two weeks in, and have a few tips (for those of you who are Creative Marching with me):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enter 0-hour days&lt;/strong> so that you have one entry in the spreadsheet for every day in the year (with or without a description and mood — your call, I’m doing it).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>View your 7-day pace&lt;/strong> to get a snapshot of how the past week contributes to your year of creativity. Paste this function in your spreadsheet in cell E15, then you can copy/paste it to the right of whatever day you want to measure (&lt;strong>If you’re not using my spreadsheet template, you’ll need to customize the range&lt;/strong>):
&lt;pre>=SUM(C8:C15)*52.143&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Learn For a Project, Not the Sake of Learning</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fischer-twins-397334-unsplash.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Because I’m self-taught in most things I do — from programming to design to animation — a lot of my friends ask me for tips on how to learn a particular thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I want to learn how to make websites,” a friend will ask. “Where do you think I should start?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, I’ve given a lot of different responses. Pointing people to free online resources for learning, like &lt;a href="https://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/">Khan Academy&lt;/a>. Or telling them to join a local workshop or meet-up. Or both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not how I learned, but it’s easier to point someone to a resource than it is to give an autobiography for how I learned something myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, seeing that advice fail again and again prompted me to rethink my rationale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What would it look like, if I advised people to learn things how I’ve learned them?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I dug to the bottom, I realized that there was a common foundation that was the basis for all the things I’ve learned. From programming languages and design software to spoken languages and hobbies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In every case where I learned something that really stuck, a skill that I could later put into practice in my work and life, I was learning for a project, not for the sake of learning itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning for a project looks like identifying a specific goal, something that you’ll be able to check a “done” box on when it’s finished, and acquiring the of the knowledge and skills necessary to accomplish it. And only that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s impossible to “learn how to make websites.” You can never check that box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are hundreds of frameworks and programming languages, and new ones pop up every day. Not to mention browser standards, support, and the ways people visit and use websites are all changing more quickly than you could finish that stack of computer science textbooks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of trying to “learn how to make websites,” create a project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That might be something like “learn how to make a WordPress website customized with my own colors and logos.” Or “a resume website with examples of all of my work.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project can also be a feature, like “learn how to make a website that has a shopping cart.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you have your project, start googling, or asking friends specific questions. Look for “how to” and keywords related to the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this investigation, you’ll start to get a sense of all the mini-projects within your overall projects (e.g., setting up an &lt;a href="https://www.codewall.co.uk/some-of-the-best-ides-to-use-in-2018-2019/">IDE&lt;/a>, using an &lt;a href="https://www.wpblog.com/best-ftp-clients-for-wordpress-users/">FTP client&lt;/a>). You’ll follow along tutorials, constantly applying things you’ve learned while recognizing new things you need to figure out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether you realize it or not, you’re creating a syllabus for your project. And it will be something that, every time you do it for a new project, or a new thing to learn, becomes more second nature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this doesn’t just apply to making websites, but everything you might want to learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can’t “learn Portuguese.” It’s completely unfeasible. I’ve been speaking and learning English my entire life and I still haven’t checked that box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you can “learn how to introduce yourself to others in Portuguese.” Then you can learn “how to ask for your favorite food.” And eventually work yourself up to something like “learn enough Portuguese to watch &lt;em>Blood of My Blood&lt;/em>” and enjoy the international sensation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can’t “learn Photoshop,” but you can “learn how to remove the background from a photo.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also works beautifully for learning more physical, or less abstract things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I turned 30, as a half joke, half life-stage-initiation-ceremony, a friend of mine took me golfing. The idea being that I can’t keep playing pick-up soccer forever, but if I picked up golf it would be a fun thing for me into my later years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being the obsessive learner that I am, I quickly turned golf into a series of projects. But I never “learned how to golf.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I learned “how to have a consistent golf swing,” which Ben Hogan taught me in his short book &lt;em>Modern Fundamentals&lt;/em>. Then I learned, “How to practice golf effectively” on the driving range and putting greens. Finally, I learned “How to consistently score below 110,” then “below 100,” then “below 90,” all of which were just a google away from a syllabus of YouTube videos and blogs. Trying to complete those projects created new projects for me, like “learning how to make all of my short putts,” “how to hit out of sand traps,” and “how to plan a round.” Finally, the last thing I learned was “how to score below 80.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In learning all that, and completing all of those projects, the list of things I don’t know towers high above what I do. Every time I learned something, I learned two things I didn’t know, that I didn’t know I didn’t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I still wouldn’t say “I know how to play golf.” I never learned how to play golf. But I do know how to swing consistently, practice effectively, plan a round, make most of my short putts, hit out of sand, and score below 80.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that’s plenty for me. Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On to the next project.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>