<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Activism on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/activism/</link><description>Recent content in Activism on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/activism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cancel Debts Not People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elizabeth Warren has thrown her hat in on a bold idea that’s been in the air for a long time: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@teamwarren/im-calling-for-something-truly-transformational-universal-free-public-college-and-cancellation-of-a246cd0f910f">cancel student loan debt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not interest rate decreases, or refinancing, or other half-measures, but an all out cancelation of up to $50K in student loan debt for anyone whose income is $100K or less. Combined with universal free public higher education going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was first introduced to this idea back in the early 2010s the &lt;a href="https://rollingjubilee.org/">Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a>, a project by &lt;a href="https://strikedebt.org/">Strike Debt&lt;/a>, which has now evolved into &lt;a href="https://debtcollective.org/">The Debt Collective&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their project leveraged one of the most dysfunctional aspects of student loan debt: the fact that the debts get bundled and resold, over and over, for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling Jubilee raised $701,317 dollars (a few of which were mine, even as a broke post-grad student living under a pile of debt) and bought bundles of debt worth a total of $31,982,455.76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, instead of trying to collect those debts, they abolished them. Poof. Gone. No more debt for the people whose loans were part of those bundles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those numbers highlight how broken, and at this point imaginary, the entire debt-debtor relationship is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what world does $700K buy $31M?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When Ambition is Hiding</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consider a few alternatives. Let’s say I told you:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>I want to remove every unhealthy habit, food, and mindset from my life, and I&amp;#8217;m going to start tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>I&amp;#8217;m going to eat less sugar, starting tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When tomorrow comes, which one are you likely to hold me accountable to? Which might you help me excuse when I fall short? Which are you actually expecting me to do? Or even realistically try?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do a few more with those questions in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I say:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my country to 100% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my local school district to 50% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Or:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to end racism, globally.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to help local people of color, and other disenfranchised people, register to vote and get to the polls.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s plenty to get the point I’m going to make, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But first, here’s what I’m not about to say:&lt;/strong> that any of the As above — the lofty, admirable, pie-in-the-sky ambitions — are in any way bad, undesirable, or something I’m advocating against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want all of those things. I have, at different points in my life, said all of those things, in some way or another. And I don’t even like &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/">thinking of myself as ambitious&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here’s all I want to point out:&lt;/strong> sometime we set the bar so high because it gives us an excuse when we can’t clear it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Fix: Politics Not Reminiscent of Sports</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</guid><description>&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Political discourse is at a place where it’s hard — if not impossible — to see it as productive. Most times, it doesn’t even seem like folks who are arguing have a vision for anything being accomplished by that argument, other than hearing words yelled.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Facts have been weaponized and are lobbed as projectiles, not used as tools to build a bridge from one perspective to another. Opinions are worn like armor, used to protect ourselves from the bombardment of facts. We scream for our ideas to drown out the screams of others for theirs.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
If sports are modeled after war, as many people say, our political discourse has taken a form modeled after the way we talk about sports.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet FacilitatingXYZ: A Free Online Resource for ALL Facilitators</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 13:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</guid><description>&lt;address>
&lt;strong>Updated September 12, 2016:&lt;/strong>&amp;nbsp;we&amp;nbsp;officially launched this project, after about 11 months in development, production, and ideation. Woohoo!
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz">FacilitatingXYZ&lt;/a> is everything I wish I had when I got started as a facilitator — and &lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz/manifesto">together&lt;/a>, we can build it into something that helps us continue to learn, develop, and grow. It’s a free online resource with videos, articles, downloads and (soon!) community to help all facilitators improve their craft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Me + Thailand = August ’15</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m excited for Thailand. I’ve heard so many amazing things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spoken with people who have immersed themselves in the culture, and had opportunities to reflect on things that were previously invisible in their lives. I know a couple people who have gone and never returned. That says a lot about a place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve talked with activists who are doing tremendous things in the worlds of gender liberation, sex worker advocacy, and social justice education. I’ve learned so much from them already, from afar, from email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Justice in 2014: Three Things to Do LESS</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/social-justice-in-2014/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 04:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/social-justice-in-2014/</guid><description>There are some wonderful things happening right now. All last year, I said it again and again, we&amp;#8217;re on the cusp of something great. Sites trying to create positive change in the world dominate my social media feeds. I was getting my hair cut today and I said I do &amp;#8220;social justice work&amp;#8221; and the hairdresser actually [kinda] knew what that meant.</description></item><item><title>30 Ways The Top Ten Most Mind Blowing Facts You Would Never Expect About Jennifer Lawrence Absolutely Kinda Restored Our Faith In Humanity And Crushed Our Souls</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 05:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Sorry, Internet, but my mind isn’t, has never been, and will likely remain unblown. But every time you trick me into clicking on one of your linkbaity lists or videos I die a &lt;/span>little inside. Because I want to care. I do care. A lot. But there’s only so much someone can _actually _care, let’s call it the Caring Tolerance™. I’m starting to worry that you’re abusing people’s attention and increasing our Caring Tolerance™ the way a college student treats their liver first semester.&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">&lt;br /> &lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t tell you how many times I’ve rage-read “my last” Buzzfeed article swearing I’d never go back to the site for anything but good ol’ fashioned America’s Funniest Home Videos style laughs. But then I see an article with “faith in humanity” in the title and my mouse hand moves faster than my brain. Then I’m back to rage-reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many times can I read THIS WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE and have it do absolutely nothing, before I start to think nothing will? Or, worse, how much empathy can I be coerced into experiencing by over-the-top, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gspElv1yvc">SPCA Sara McLachlan&lt;/a> wannabe videos on Upworthy before I can’t experience genuine empathy for the people in my immediate life (who aren’t soon-to-be-executed dogs, but still need love)?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genital Xenophobia and Genital Wanderlust: Show Me Yours and I’ll Show You Mine</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</guid><description>I remember the first time I played Show Me Yours I’ll Show You Mine. Some people call it Doctor. If you’ve never played, worry not: the rules are the simple. Show me yours. Then I show you mine. And who is the winner?</description></item><item><title>I’d be okay with a revolution.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 19:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</guid><description>I wrote a Facebook status and Tweet last week that were meant to be a joke. A sarcastic, I want more out of the world, parody-type joke. But nobody laughed.
Post by Sam Killermann.  I’m not mad.</description></item></channel></rss>