<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncertainty on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/uncertainty/</link><description>Recent content in Uncertainty on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 01:45:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/uncertainty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loving the Uncertainty of Travel: From Bangkok to Chiang Mai</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/loving-the-uncertainty-of-travel-from-bangkok-to-chiang-mai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 01:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/loving-the-uncertainty-of-travel-from-bangkok-to-chiang-mai/</guid><description>&lt;p>We pile our bags on a little side street in downtown Bangkok. It’s 8pm, the city’s lights are waking up, and busses fill the street. A double-decker bus drives by, inside on the top level a man is singing karaoke to the rest of the travelers. We’re waiting for bus #3, our nine-hour overnight ride to Chiang Mai, a rural town in northern Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can’t find our bus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mike and I are sitting on the stoop of a closed shop, the dozen pieces of luggage and gear scattered around us. We are drinking a beer and appreciating the calamity of the moment: unsure of where we’ll be in the moments that come, what it will feel like, and how we will be getting there. It’s one of the best things about traveling — the constant uncertainty, the focus on the moment, the near-to-nothing being granted — if you can learn to appreciate it. Admittedly, it’s an acquired taste. It’s my coffee. It’s my wine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some confusion and stress, we learn our bus has already arrived. It’s been waiting for us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We don’t know what to expect inside. The conditions of the bus, the seats, the air, the noise. We’re hoping to sleep, but first we’re hoping the seat recline functions. I can’t help but think back to the bus I rode from Cairo into the middle of the White Desert (the half-day of one-hundred degree sun, the broken air conditioning, the overcramped seating, the failing engine).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We pile into the bus and find that we have a private room in the front half of the lower level. Eight seats all to ourselves. I wouldn’t have hoped for anything better. The seats recline. It does get better. And there’s air conditioning. I could die happy on this bus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bus jerks into gear. A strange smell sweeps through our cabin. &lt;em>We might die on this bus.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>