<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Challenge on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/challenge/</link><description>Recent content in Challenge on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 23:31:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Creative March</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 23:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last few weeks have been marked by creativity. I love that feeling. I want to make it happen more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bill Gates is frequently quoted for saying, “Most people overestimate what they can do in one year and underestimate what they can do in ten years.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel this contrast more intensely on a smaller scale: &lt;strong>we overestimate what we can do in a day, and underestimate what we can do in a year.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s so easy for me to think of myself as a creative person — a writer, a doodler, a designer, a coder — even when I don’t create anything in a given day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I’m not really a writer when I’m not writing. I’m a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/">reader of political news&lt;/a>, or a dog walker, or a cook, or a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">compulsively rechecking my email because it triggers a dopamine response-er&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been “working on a book for three years” now, but I haven’t truly been &lt;em>working&lt;/em> on that book for three years. I’ve barely worked on it at all. A few minutes here, an hour there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creativity is an act, and one that is so easily sidelined by other actions — anything that feels safer, simpler, easier, or fulfills a shortsighted desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many people do you know who are “working” on things that never get any creative time dedicated to them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many projects are you “working” on that you haven’t sat down in front of for over a week? A month? A year? Ever?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week, I finished and published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/">a book&lt;/a>. The week before I co-created and published a massive &lt;a href="https://thesafezoneproject.com/introducing-safe-zone-train-the-trainer-retreat-guide/">Train-the-Trainer Retreat Guide&lt;/a>. The week before that I wrote a new comedy show. And in between all of that I’ve made major strides in starting two new (secret, for now) projects. And I’ve only checked my email two thousand times (a made up number down from what I assume is my normal two million times per month).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the weeks before that, I was mostly just slogging through administrative stuff. Checking in on old things, closing out 2018. Not really making progress on anything, with only a few essays and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">one edugraphic&lt;/a> to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of that got me reflecting on the ebbs and flows of my own creativity, and wanting to come up with some personal &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/challenge/">challenge&lt;/a> or strategy to get a better grasp on that part of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t want to spend most of my time on tasks that amount to nothing, but feel good in the moment (or at least don’t feel terrifying, like creativity often does).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to spend most of my time creating things that I share with the world, that are durable, that might exist when I’m gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As luck would have it, listening to &lt;a href="https://tim.blog/2019/02/18/jim-collins/">a podcast interview&lt;/a> today with &lt;a href="https://www.jimcollins.com">Jim Collins&lt;/a> gave me an exciting challenge that I’m going to start tonight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Hadn’t Funded My Work with Patreon</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 23:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</guid><description>&lt;p>For several years, my “day job” (the one paying my bills) has been performing comedy shows. Meanwhile, my hobby has been creating online resources, tools, and organizations for justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that’s a weird combo, you’re not alone. I’m with you: it’s hard to wrap my mind around the truth that the way I make money is comedy, then I use that money to &lt;em>pay to&lt;/em> do administrative-paperwork-email-non-profit-type stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, it’s the other way around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What’s even weirder? Switching things up — and starting to fund my online advocacy work directly, not via comedy shows — seems less likely to succeed than continuing to be a working comedian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes — I’ve heard of &lt;a href="https://patreon.com">Patreon&lt;/a>. People have told me about it hundreds of times, for years and years, every time I made that point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of the work I do is a great fit for Patreon. But I’ve been resistant to the idea of funding it that way. The reasons are a mix of ethics and personal discomforts, and are all tied directly to my work, and the change I hope it effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why haven’t I done it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I committed to writing on this site every day for 100 days in a row. Today, I’m committing to something similar and different: I’m going to start meditating every day, for at least the next 100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me explain why, and how I plan to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had an inconsistent meditation practice for about a decade now. At its best, I meditate every day for a streak of a week or two. At its worst, I meditate once a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here’s the thing: I know that meditation makes me happier, calmer, work better, think clearer — it makes me &lt;em>better.&lt;/em> Every time. I can even verify this for myself with some [obviously slanted] data: looking back at my journal, and comparing that against the records from the meditation app I use (Calm), I can see that on days I meditate I almost always finish every task I set out to do in the morning. I’m also more gracious, thoughtful, and patient in my responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the days I don’t meditate, well, I get by, but I’m a bit messier. And sometimes those days turn into weeks into months. That’s what’s happened these past few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the science backs this up, right? We all know this, if we exist even a little on the internet. Just google “&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=the+scientific+benefits+of+meditation">the scientific benefits of meditation&lt;/a>” and bask in the bazillion hits of glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Rationalize Being So Hard on Myself, &amp; How I’m Going to Stop</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</guid><description>I’m my own worst critic. A lot of us are. I don’t like this about myself. A lot of us don’t. But I finally have a strategy to make it stop happening.
Of course we’re our own worst critics: we know better than anyone else our abilities, capacities, our “should”s — we know our potential, so we know when we fall short.</description></item><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>Asking For Help</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</guid><description>I have a hard time asking for help, likely mostly because I’m a dude. You might freak out reading this if you’re familiar with my other work, but let me write a few more words before we start sounding any alarms.</description></item><item><title>Go See a Movie By Yourself</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 17:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</guid><description>I just got back from watching the new _Hunger Games _flick. I cried 15+ times in 146 minutes and left the theatre fired up to burn down the establishment. You should see it. I also went alone. And that’s not how you’re supposed to do that thing.</description></item><item><title>My Gratitude Challenge</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</guid><description>My momma taught me to say please and thank you, to keep my elbows off the table, and to never chew with my mouth full. As a near grown-up Sam, these all feel as natural as breathing, blinking, or eating peanut butter directly from the jar with a spoon (sorry, Momma).</description></item><item><title>For One Week, Starting Now, I Will Tell No Lies</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 01:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</guid><description>I lie a lot. I didn’t realize that until I started following Sam Harris, the Author of Lying, on Twitter (I highly recommend following him, by the way — dude’s got a great first name). A few days ago one of my Twitter buds retweeted his challenge below, which is how I was introduced to Sam (great name, by the way) and his work.</description></item></channel></rss>