<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in Learning on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 9:3:1 Learning Rule</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you’re trying to learn a new thing — a skill, talent, instrument, sport, language, anything — there are a million things that can derail you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard not to become fatigued, discouraged, frustrated, lose sight of your goal, or become distracted by a brighter light in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even assuming you get everything else right, and none of those detours push you off path, it’s still common to plateau early and stop making progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rule is to prevent that from happening: &lt;strong>say hello to the 9:3:1 Rule, a guide for how to allocate your time while learning a new thing.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn For a Project, Not the Sake of Learning</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because I’m self-taught in most things I do — from programming to design to animation — a lot of my friends ask me for tips on how to learn a particular thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I want to learn how to make websites,” a friend will ask. “Where do you think I should start?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, I’ve given a lot of different responses. Pointing people to free online resources for learning, like &lt;a href="https://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/">Khan Academy&lt;/a>. Or telling them to join a local workshop or meet-up. Or both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not how I learned, but it’s easier to point someone to a resource than it is to give an autobiography for how I learned something myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, seeing that advice fail again and again prompted me to rethink my rationale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What would it look like, if I advised people to learn things how I’ve learned them?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Can Stop Saying “They Should Make A…”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something I see all the time on the internet is people saying “They should have a…” or “They should make a…” and then sharing some idea, platform, service, movement, or cause that the commenter wants, and believes “they” should create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, this made sense. The request was legitimate and necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were gatekeepers in every industry — from arts to activism to commerce to community-building — who were the “They.” It was They who had to approve our appeal to create a new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You couldn’t just make that thing, or build that platform, or create that movement, release that show, or host that community yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You needed Their permission. You needed Them to make it for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning from Mistakes Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</guid><description>Mistakes don’t guarantee learning, but learning requires mistakes.</description></item><item><title>What I Miss About Grad School</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 06:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-i-miss-about-grad-school/</guid><description>Earlier tonight, my friend texted me “I’m over this whole constantly chasing the homework train business.”
She was talking about grad school, and sharing a sentiment I shared back when I was earning my master’s. But, a bit to my surprise, I replied, “I miss grad school.</description></item><item><title>Scrapping and Starting Fresh: The Hawthorne Effect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 05:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/scrapping-and-starting-fresh/</guid><description>A couple months ago I ventured into the land of the podcast. A couple weeks ago I roped my friend Ian in and “Thought of the Week” became “The Hawthorne Effect.” The whole thing has been a huge learning process. After doing a number of different podcast approaches by myself, and trying a few different things out with Ian, he and I sat down tonight to reflect on what we think has worked, what hasn’t, and set a clear plan for what we’ll do in the future.</description></item></channel></rss>