<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technolophizing on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/technolophizing/</link><description>Recent content in Technolophizing on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/technolophizing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rage du Jour</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rage-du-jour/</guid><description>&lt;p>How many things have you been mad about in the past week? How many meltdown-level shares have you seen in your social feeds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every day there’s something new that my entire social bubble is furious about (at least if feels that way). The &lt;em>Rage du Jour&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the backlash for some stupid thing a politician did. Or the horrible take a celebrity had in response to a current event. Or a current event that isn’t getting the right coverage from the news. Or, sometimes, it’s rage about rage: the fact that people are mad about something become the thing other people are mad about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In special cases the rage will last more than a day. But that requires a really sticky subject. Something that can keep our focus amidst the barrage of incoming candidates of rageworthiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to stay genuinely mad about something for a long time. It takes energy, effort, fuel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s easy to get mad about a new thing if the conditions are right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on social media the conditions are prime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Simple Things You Can Do to Curb Your Phone Addiction Right Now</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of us are addicted to our phones. If you’ve started to see why this might not be the best thing ever, and want to ween yourself off of that tantalizingly non-nourishing blue glow, you’re in good company. This is something I’ve been thinking about, and experimenting with, for a few years now. Following are three things you knock out in about 15 minutes, that will benefit you for weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I get into those, I want to be clear: I’m talking about the colloquial, not clinical, usage of the term “addiction.” In this post, I’m not staking my flag in the hill that “phone addiction” is (or isn’t) real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’m talking about here, as addiction, is the compulsive use of our phones. That we’re spending more time poking around our phones than we want to, picking them up and checking the screen before we realize we’re doing it, and that our phones aren’t adding quality to our lives, and might be distracting us from the things we’d actually care about enjoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m talking about how we’re &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/">already dating our phones&lt;/a>, and how &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">little red numbers are trying to rule our lives&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Can Stop Saying “They Should Make A…”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/they-should-make/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something I see all the time on the internet is people saying “They should have a…” or “They should make a…” and then sharing some idea, platform, service, movement, or cause that the commenter wants, and believes “they” should create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, this made sense. The request was legitimate and necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were gatekeepers in every industry — from arts to activism to commerce to community-building — who were the “They.” It was They who had to approve our appeal to create a new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You couldn’t just make that thing, or build that platform, or create that movement, release that show, or host that community yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You needed Their permission. You needed Them to make it for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Checklist to Work Through Before Creating Any New Website, Blog, or App</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:20:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you thinking about creating a website? Or a blog? Or an app? Do you want to be “in the cloud,” but you’re not really sure what that is? Have you been talking with colleagues about this idea, or received direction from your boss, and started figuring out how to do it yourself, or looking into hiring a designer/developer to build it for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great! Good on you. Making things is really exciting, and it’s really fun to hit the ground running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The natural next step you might make is to start price shopping around, looking for an agency or creative you can afford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not great! But no fault to you: this is what most people do next. And it’s something that results in a lot of wasted money in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you start designing or building something that you have in mind, and &lt;em>definitely&lt;/em> before you start paying someone else to, there are a few things you need to figure out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Hadn’t Funded My Work with Patreon</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 23:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-not-patreon/</guid><description>&lt;p>For several years, my “day job” (the one paying my bills) has been performing comedy shows. Meanwhile, my hobby has been creating online resources, tools, and organizations for justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that’s a weird combo, you’re not alone. I’m with you: it’s hard to wrap my mind around the truth that the way I make money is comedy, then I use that money to &lt;em>pay to&lt;/em> do administrative-paperwork-email-non-profit-type stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, it’s the other way around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What’s even weirder? Switching things up — and starting to fund my online advocacy work directly, not via comedy shows — seems less likely to succeed than continuing to be a working comedian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes — I’ve heard of &lt;a href="https://patreon.com">Patreon&lt;/a>. People have told me about it hundreds of times, for years and years, every time I made that point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of the work I do is a great fit for Patreon. But I’ve been resistant to the idea of funding it that way. The reasons are a mix of ethics and personal discomforts, and are all tied directly to my work, and the change I hope it effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why haven’t I done it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Made A WordPress Site with a 100 Score on Google Pagespeed Insights</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-i-made-a-wordpress-site-with-a-100-score-on-google-pagespeed-insights/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:21:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-i-made-a-wordpress-site-with-a-100-score-on-google-pagespeed-insights/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m really thrilled about this. As a poor person who creates tons of websites that have a ton of traffic but are totally free and make negative dollars, I feel like I’ve found the Holy Grail. But before I get into the details, two quick things:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One, &lt;strong>none of the following links are affiliates/sponsored&lt;/strong> (I don’t abide that sort of thing here).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two, &lt;strong>this path isn’t for everyone&lt;/strong>, but I’m going to lay it out for those of you who want to walk it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just wanted to get that out of the way, because I know that the excitement that’s bubbling out of me might be misread as a sales pitch or proselytizing. It’s not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We good? Good. Omg. Can I tell you how excited I am?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funding Online Work in 2018</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/funding-online-work-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 23:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/funding-online-work-in-2018/</guid><description>I wrote an unusual blog post (and designed an accompanying infographic) on my main site, It’s Pronounced Metrosexual, where I disclosed the numbers on the number of people who have contributed to the site, and the number who hasn’t. It’s reflective of all of my work, and an interesting (I think) take on the reality of creating stuff for the internet.</description></item><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>After 7 Years Doing this Work, I’m [Re-] Branding. Here’s how I’m making decisions.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got thrown into this. Two-fold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got thrown into the work I’ve been doing. And I got thrown into a situation that’s led me to question everything, rethink and restructure, and make decisions that feel like an overall “brand.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’m happy I’m here, one of the strongest forces that’s guiding what I do next is precisely avoiding how I got here: no more being thrown into stuff. Seem easy? Maybe. Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll get to that in a second, but first the back story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="//wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="//tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Keep Track of 50 Projects at Once (&amp; Maintain Some Sanity)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 02:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</guid><description>I’m currently in the process of finishing two books, starting another, publishing two new sexuality models, three new live social justice comedy shows, running half a dozen volunteer-based initiatives, building I’m-not-even-sure-how-many websites, and the list goes on. It’s a lot. And as I type that, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>Be Bored</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 05:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</guid><description>&lt;p>Be bored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop. Whatever else you’re doing. Stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn off your music. Turn off the TV, Netflix Instant Streaming, Hulu+, Amazon Prime, all the things you use to fill your time. Not forever, not for long, but for right now, this moment, stop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let’s Be Honest: We’re Already Dating Our Phones</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 05:58:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yo. I just saw &lt;em>Her.&lt;/em> It’s cray. It’s powerfully well-written and brings up a lot of thoughts about how we might relate to technology and one another in the future. But it also made me think a lot about how we relate to technology and one another right now. If you have a smart phone and you’ve seen &lt;em>Her&lt;/em>, you’ve likely had a lot of these thoughts already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to convince myself that we’re not already dating our phones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 Ways The Top Ten Most Mind Blowing Facts You Would Never Expect About Jennifer Lawrence Absolutely Kinda Restored Our Faith In Humanity And Crushed Our Souls</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 05:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/30-mind-blowing-facts-internet-is-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Sorry, Internet, but my mind isn’t, has never been, and will likely remain unblown. But every time you trick me into clicking on one of your linkbaity lists or videos I die a &lt;/span>little inside. Because I want to care. I do care. A lot. But there’s only so much someone can _actually _care, let’s call it the Caring Tolerance™. I’m starting to worry that you’re abusing people’s attention and increasing our Caring Tolerance™ the way a college student treats their liver first semester.&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">&lt;br /> &lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t tell you how many times I’ve rage-read “my last” Buzzfeed article swearing I’d never go back to the site for anything but good ol’ fashioned America’s Funniest Home Videos style laughs. But then I see an article with “faith in humanity” in the title and my mouse hand moves faster than my brain. Then I’m back to rage-reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many times can I read THIS WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE and have it do absolutely nothing, before I start to think nothing will? Or, worse, how much empathy can I be coerced into experiencing by over-the-top, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gspElv1yvc">SPCA Sara McLachlan&lt;/a> wannabe videos on Upworthy before I can’t experience genuine empathy for the people in my immediate life (who aren’t soon-to-be-executed dogs, but still need love)?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBooker’s Creed</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my MacBook. There are many like it, but this one is mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook is my best friend. It is my life. I must master it as I must master my life.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook, without me, is still pretty shiny. Without my MacBook, I am useless and not at all shiny and can’t watch Netflix in bed (which I love). I must type words into Pages. I must type words into email correctly or autocorrect may ruin my life. I must send that email before I receive another email or email overload may ruin my life. I will…&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Computer Died, but that’s Good</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 01:14:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</guid><description>&lt;p>I woke up this morning to my computer not working. It’s not been in great shape these past few months, and has occasionally tossed a surprise my way. It’s several years old, and I’ve put it through plenty of hell with all my traveling (and general clumsiness). I’d already been investigating new options, and weighing the pros and cons. I knew its time was drawing near.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of work on my plate right now, and a lot of it’s time sensitive. And chief thing on my mind is the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference next week, for which I’m excited to be one of the keynotes. I have a few pressing collaborations, plenty of more people who I’ve promised e-love to, and some big personal projects that are underway. Objectively, it’s not an ideal time for my computer to bail on me. But subjectively, I’m excited for a few days without my computer, amidst a few of the days this year I most crushingly want to feel like I _need _it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trying to Overcome the Numbers that Rule My Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 20:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never considered myself a “numbers” person. I don’t mean I wasn’t good at math (Mathlete, y’all!), but I care more about stories than stats. On the Myers-Briggs Typology Instrument, for example, my F to T (Feeling to Thinking) ratio is the most unbalanced, and I’m a _strong _F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I do — every &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> I do — while seemingly disparate, is all connected by that trait. Every little project or endeavor I undertake is driven by my goal of making the world a safer place for all people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it’s as surprising to me as it might be to you how numbers-driven my day-to-day life is, and how much I find myself trying to turn that part of my brain off so I can focus on the present. The numbers eat at me, often glaring at me from within little red circles, screaming “Click me! Make me go away!” Others are tucked away within more complex websites or spreadsheets, whispering more gently, but still persuasively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a small taste of the numbers that are almost always whizzing around my brain, attempting to distract me from the task at hand. Every one of these things pops into my head at once when I wake up every morning, then attempts to suckle my brainjuice every minute of every hour I’m awake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Miss Wondering</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier tonight, I turned the burner on high and while I was waiting for my rice to come to a full boil I had a thought: “I wonder if rice cooked in beer would be good.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, I would have likely wondered that for quite a while. It may have been on my mind while I ate my boring water-based rice. It may have popped into my mind tomorrow, or the next day, when I next saw rice or beer. Visions of beer-based rice recipes might have danced in my belly. I may have wondered about it for a week (or ten) before I finally giving in, cooking it, and exiting Wonderland for Knowville.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of that happened, because Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the water (boring) in the pot began boiling I already knew if “beer rice” was a thing, what it would taste like (delicious), exactly how to make it, and what types of recipes it would be good in (ALL OF THEM).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>