<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Friendship on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/friendship/</link><description>Recent content in Friendship on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/friendship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking the Chain of “Maybe”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a modern scourge upon us, and every get-together, plan, and social event is vulnerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know when it started, who’s to blame, or if it can be defeated, but I’ve begun vaccinating myself against it. And if you or your social circle have caught a case of the &lt;em>Maybes&lt;/em>, or you want to prevent an outbreak, here’s what you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step with any epidemic is understanding the problem: What is the Maybes, how does it spread, and why is it harmful?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Treating Old Friends Like New Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 05:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</guid><description>I made a new friend (not bragging) who is so awesome (totally bragging) she makes me seem boring (humble bragging). I love making new friends. I love the adventure, the mystery, toeing and pushing the line, oversharing with whimsy — I love every step of the way.</description></item><item><title>Single-Serving Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</guid><description>Edward Norton’s character in _Fight Club _introduced me to the term “single-serving friend,” a person who is your friend for a short period in time. In the movie, he’s talking about the people he meets on flights (“everything on a plane is single-serving”).</description></item><item><title>Be Your Own Friend First</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 05:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</guid><description>Everything you need to know about relationships you can learn from watching _Dexter _and _Scrubs. _Okay, that’s probably not true. But I really dig both shows, and I like what I’ve gleaned from both character’s approaches to life.
Dexter, the sociopath who lives a life of lies, is amazingly good at self care.</description></item><item><title>My Gaming Community</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-gaming-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 04:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-gaming-community/</guid><description>With what I do with Gamers Against Bigotry, and with being a long time video game lover, I tend to use the phrase “the gaming community” a lot. Generally more than once a day. It’s a term we all toss around, and we generally use it to mean “everyone who plays video games.</description></item><item><title>Catalytic Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/catalytic-friends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 04:55:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/catalytic-friends/</guid><description>It’s rare that it’s a good thing to be in a coffee shop, slurping coffee, at 11:30 pm. But last night, boisterously laughing throughout an otherwise intense philosophical conversation, slurping coffee until midnight was exactly a good thing.
I spent the night working and talking with a close friend of mine, in what’s become a routine of ours: late night “cofficing,” a term he coined, that sometimes is more work than conversation, and other times more conversation than work, but is always exactly what we need.</description></item></channel></rss>