<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fear on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/fear/</link><description>Recent content in Fear on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 22:12:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/fear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I’m terrified. I’m a professional performer, but in 90 minutes I’ll be sitting down to my first ever singing lesson.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/singing-lesson-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 22:12:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/singing-lesson-anxiety/</guid><description>&lt;p>The lesson will be private. One-on-one. And the instructor, Mady, is, by all accounts, an incredibly delightful, non-intimidating person. I’ve performed on stages in front of 5000+ person crowds. I’ve spoken to hundreds of thousands of people around the US. I’ve done stand-up comedy on a stage in a country where the material I was performing could have landed me in jail, or worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why am I so nervous about this?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a Bigger “Us” and a Smaller “Them”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 03:53:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</guid><description>Today I read a fantastic interview with Bills Clinton and Gates on _Wired. _I highly recommend reading the whole thing, because a lot of great things were said. These are two people who lived incredible, noteworthy lives, retired, then, for no other reason than because, proceeded to start second incredible, noteworthy lives.</description></item><item><title>Hiding Behind a Keyboard: The Terror of the Unknown</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 04:13:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</guid><description>I used to be terrified of any sort of public speaking. This terror was justified by my complete inability to speak to any group larger than 2 – 3. Before my first semester at Purdue, during orientation, we were always asked to introduce ourselves with our “Name, Hometown, Major” — something I couldn’t do without fumbling over my words and screwing something up.</description></item></channel></rss>