<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:45:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I’m Publishing A Book</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m writing from a rooftop in Austin, taking a break from my break — which was part Naomi Klein and part Real Ale — to share a reflection that just sunk in: I’m about to publish my first book, and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to be clear: this isn’t me publishing the first book I wrote (that happened a couple years ago, and still hasn’t sunk in); this is me, under the auspices of &lt;a href="http://impetus.pw">Impetus Books&lt;/a>, publishing my first book someone else wrote (in this case, I’m glowingly happy to say that someone else is Karen Rayne).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>“What is the meaning of life?”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 05:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</guid><description>“What’s the meaning of life?” he asked earnestly, as if he actually wanted the answer.
“To live true, to be honest, to experience spiritual connection, to give, to be…” he replied, rambling on platitudes. The same niceties he found himself saying on a regular basis — a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Why I’ve Never Been a Fan of “Self Help” Books</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 05:37:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-help-books/</guid><description>I’ve only ever read one, maybe two, “self help” books (depending on how strict your definition is). Not for me. And I wouldn’t want to foist them on anyone else. Might seem odd, considering what I write here. That’s one of the reasons I’ve been so reluctant to write about the things I write about here: because I don’t like the idea of “self help” coming from another person.</description></item><item><title>Uncopyright</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/uncopyright/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 05:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/uncopyright/</guid><description>On Tuesday I was sitting in my favorite coffee shop in Austin and I felt inspired to record my podcast. I grabbed my fancy microphone out of my bag and started to set it up to record when I noticed something: Tom’s had the Beatles playing.</description></item><item><title>Hiding Behind a Keyboard: The Terror of the Unknown</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 04:13:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/hiding-behind-a-keyboard/</guid><description>I used to be terrified of any sort of public speaking. This terror was justified by my complete inability to speak to any group larger than 2 – 3. Before my first semester at Purdue, during orientation, we were always asked to introduce ourselves with our “Name, Hometown, Major” — something I couldn’t do without fumbling over my words and screwing something up.</description></item></channel></rss>