<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Happiness on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/happiness/</link><description>Recent content in Happiness on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Falling Off the Daily Meditation Path</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven’t meditated in over a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve become increasingly aware of this every day that passes. It’s become so big in my day, that, right now, Not Meditating feels like all I’ve accomplished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, here I am writing this instead of doing the damn thing. What is wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that I’ll appreciate my time sitting — both while it’s happening (even if I know it’ll be more fitful than usual) and after. It’ll give my day more focus, give me a breath between the world and my reactions to it, and I’ll feel happier, healthier, calmer, and whole-er.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of meditating, when I haven’t been, are always more obvious to me in the negative: the list of things I’ve been doing, thinking, eating, etc. that were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mindful, but were instead short-sighted comforts that led to longer-term pains. The things I &lt;em>wouldn’t&lt;/em> be doing if I &lt;em>had been&lt;/em> meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my recent memory is full of such things. My body and mind are weighed down with their aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet here I am, still Not Meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that all that’s standing between me getting back on that path or me continuing to flounder is a few minutes on the cushion. I’ve known that every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet I didn’t. I still haven’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what’s getting in my way? If you’ve ever experienced this — or currently are — what’s getting in our way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Rationalize Being So Hard on Myself, &amp; How I’m Going to Stop</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</guid><description>I’m my own worst critic. A lot of us are. I don’t like this about myself. A lot of us don’t. But I finally have a strategy to make it stop happening.
Of course we’re our own worst critics: we know better than anyone else our abilities, capacities, our “should”s — we know our potential, so we know when we fall short.</description></item><item><title>I’m Insulted When You Call Me Ambitious</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 04:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading a blog post someone wrote about me (I know. Let’s move on.) and they described me as “incredibly ambitious.” This was meant to be a compliment. Cool. Nice of you. But I don’t see it that way. I get upset when people describe me or think of me as ambitious. In general, I discourage ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many ways, ambition is the opposite of who I am, want to be, and what I want for others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>My Computer Died, but that’s Good</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 01:14:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</guid><description>&lt;p>I woke up this morning to my computer not working. It’s not been in great shape these past few months, and has occasionally tossed a surprise my way. It’s several years old, and I’ve put it through plenty of hell with all my traveling (and general clumsiness). I’d already been investigating new options, and weighing the pros and cons. I knew its time was drawing near.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of work on my plate right now, and a lot of it’s time sensitive. And chief thing on my mind is the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference next week, for which I’m excited to be one of the keynotes. I have a few pressing collaborations, plenty of more people who I’ve promised e-love to, and some big personal projects that are underway. Objectively, it’s not an ideal time for my computer to bail on me. But subjectively, I’m excited for a few days without my computer, amidst a few of the days this year I most crushingly want to feel like I _need _it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>