<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minimalism on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/minimalism/</link><description>Recent content in Minimalism on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/minimalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Insulted When You Call Me Ambitious</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 04:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading a blog post someone wrote about me (I know. Let’s move on.) and they described me as “incredibly ambitious.” This was meant to be a compliment. Cool. Nice of you. But I don’t see it that way. I get upset when people describe me or think of me as ambitious. In general, I discourage ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many ways, ambition is the opposite of who I am, want to be, and what I want for others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100+ Tips for Minimalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 01:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</guid><description>Kidding. 100 would be a bit excessive, and likely more than a bit counterintuitive, wouldn’t it? It’s easy for us to be seduced by a lot, and to think that more is better, but we rarely need more than a little.</description></item><item><title>The 3 Ingredients to a Happy Existence</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intentionality, Mindfulness, and Minimalism are all you need, beyond basic biological requirements (clean water, nutritious food, human touch, etc.), to live a happy existence. This is what I’ve come to believe. I’ll define what I mean by all three, and talk about their relationship to one another, but first I want to talk about “happiness.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t aspire toward being happy all the time, nor do I recommend it. I don’t think of happiness as existing at the opposite end of sadness, nor do I think that sadness is inherently bad. All emotions have value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think of happiness on a continuum with lack of happiness on the other end, sadness on a continuum with lack of sadness on the other end, and so forth. Experiencing happiness doesn’t necessarily make you less sad — The Barenaked Ladies kew this: “I’m the kind of guy who laughs at a funeral.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trying to Overcome the Numbers that Rule My Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 20:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never considered myself a “numbers” person. I don’t mean I wasn’t good at math (Mathlete, y’all!), but I care more about stories than stats. On the Myers-Briggs Typology Instrument, for example, my F to T (Feeling to Thinking) ratio is the most unbalanced, and I’m a _strong _F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I do — every &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> I do — while seemingly disparate, is all connected by that trait. Every little project or endeavor I undertake is driven by my goal of making the world a safer place for all people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it’s as surprising to me as it might be to you how numbers-driven my day-to-day life is, and how much I find myself trying to turn that part of my brain off so I can focus on the present. The numbers eat at me, often glaring at me from within little red circles, screaming “Click me! Make me go away!” Others are tucked away within more complex websites or spreadsheets, whispering more gently, but still persuasively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a small taste of the numbers that are almost always whizzing around my brain, attempting to distract me from the task at hand. Every one of these things pops into my head at once when I wake up every morning, then attempts to suckle my brainjuice every minute of every hour I’m awake.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>