<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Justice Dogma on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/</link><description>Recent content in Social Justice Dogma on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 21:42:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 21:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</guid><description>&lt;p id="e3e7" class="graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf-after--figure">
Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I’m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word “lifestyle”). But this trip was different.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="28ff" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
In years past, the ideas I was presenting (i.e., social justice and anti-oppression concepts, centered around gender) were mostly received as new. And the questions aligned with that. But this year, a lot of the questions I was hearing weren’t responding to what I was saying on stage, as much as they were addressing things that were already bouncing around students’ minds before I got there. I just became the first “spokesperson” for social justice they were able to confront IRL.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5116" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
For example, in years past I got a lot of questions about things like “What do you mean gender and sexuality aren’t the same?” Or “What do you mean a woman can’t ‘oppress’ a man?”
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="b2a7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
But this year, a &lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em">bunch &lt;/em>of times (double digits) during Q&amp;As I was asked something that amounted to “So gender is a social construct, and so is race, so why are we accepting of &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner">Caitlyn Jenner&lt;/a> but not &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal">Rachel Dolezal&lt;/a>?” By high schoolers. In rural Texas Ontario.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5bb9" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
Hold that thought. I’ll return to it, but first I want to take a step back.</description></item></channel></rss>