<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Politics on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cancel Debts Not People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elizabeth Warren has thrown her hat in on a bold idea that’s been in the air for a long time: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@teamwarren/im-calling-for-something-truly-transformational-universal-free-public-college-and-cancellation-of-a246cd0f910f">cancel student loan debt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not interest rate decreases, or refinancing, or other half-measures, but an all out cancelation of up to $50K in student loan debt for anyone whose income is $100K or less. Combined with universal free public higher education going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was first introduced to this idea back in the early 2010s the &lt;a href="https://rollingjubilee.org/">Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a>, a project by &lt;a href="https://strikedebt.org/">Strike Debt&lt;/a>, which has now evolved into &lt;a href="https://debtcollective.org/">The Debt Collective&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their project leveraged one of the most dysfunctional aspects of student loan debt: the fact that the debts get bundled and resold, over and over, for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling Jubilee raised $701,317 dollars (a few of which were mine, even as a broke post-grad student living under a pile of debt) and bought bundles of debt worth a total of $31,982,455.76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, instead of trying to collect those debts, they abolished them. Poof. Gone. No more debt for the people whose loans were part of those bundles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those numbers highlight how broken, and at this point imaginary, the entire debt-debtor relationship is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what world does $700K buy $31M?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Problem of Progressivism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>With more and more people talking about “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;oq=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.4775j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">the left cannibalizing itself&lt;/a>” and “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;oq=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2521j1j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">liberals eating their own&lt;/a>,” or how “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;oq=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5472j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">democrats need to unite to defeat Trump&lt;/a>,” we need to keep reminding ourselves and others about the problem of progressivism — instead of just beating the dead horse that is the problems &lt;em>within&lt;/em> progressivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start with the second one, because that’s what everyone won’t stop yelling about, and I’m afraid if I don’t do a little yelling you won’t hear me out on the part of this that I think is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here it is, me jumping on the dogpile: the left has some problems, and we’re getting in our own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that is true for the “right,” the “center,” liberals, progressives, leftists, Libertarians, Republicans, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally every political camp has problems. Any collection of humans with a count greater than 0 has problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, why is the trope of “liberals eat their own” so pervasive?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public Libraries Shouldn’t Exist</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:37:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Usually, when I’m at home in Austin, I work in coffee shops. Today, I’m working from our gobsmackingly beautiful public library. And I can’t help but repeatedly ask myself “What would happen if someone pitched the idea of a public library today?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a broken record in my brain. An audio loop. It plays every time I turn a corner in this space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What would it sound like to argue for the idea of a public library in 2019?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Big Thing Being Bedridden with the Flu for a Week Made Me Realize</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 20:56:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past 7 days, my life was consumed by the flu. Technically, I was more couch-ridden than bedridden, but I was decidedly &lt;em>horizontal&lt;/em>. Luckily, I had a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bs61eifhyh-/">faithful guardian&lt;/a> who didn’t leave my side, so I survived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first time I’ve had the flu in as long as I can remember. I don’t get sick often. The last time I was even “take a day off work” sick was over a year ago (and I don’t even have to get a doctor’s note to call in — I have &lt;a href="https://patreon.com/killermann">lenient bosses&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday, as I was catching up on the &lt;a href="https://www.nbc.com/saturday-night-live/video/january-26-james-mcavoy/3867402">SNL I missed&lt;/a>, I realized I didn’t get most of the jokes because I hadn’t been keeping up with politics or the news (or even trying).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, something else hit me, as I started to dive back into work and catch up with life, that I can attribute entirely to the flu:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Policing Voting vs. Nuance</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</guid><description>You can complain about politics if you don’t vote.
You’re not a bad human if you don’t vote.
You can still be my friend if you don’t vote.
And voting is an exceptional way to complain.
And it’s a perfect way to stake a claim in your humanity.</description></item><item><title>A Fix: Politics Not Reminiscent of Sports</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</guid><description>&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Political discourse is at a place where it’s hard — if not impossible — to see it as productive. Most times, it doesn’t even seem like folks who are arguing have a vision for anything being accomplished by that argument, other than hearing words yelled.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Facts have been weaponized and are lobbed as projectiles, not used as tools to build a bridge from one perspective to another. Opinions are worn like armor, used to protect ourselves from the bombardment of facts. We scream for our ideas to drown out the screams of others for theirs.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
If sports are modeled after war, as many people say, our political discourse has taken a form modeled after the way we talk about sports.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>These 6 Videos will Change the Way You Look at Unregulated Capitalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 23:49:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</guid><description>RSA Animate: The Crises of Capitalism Wealth Inequality in America Naomi Klein: Addicted to Risk Alain de Botton: A Kinder, Gentler Philosophy of Success The Overview Effect Nic Marks: The Happy Planet Index</description></item><item><title>Working to End Oppression Makes More Sense as a Republican Value than a Democratic One</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 18:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</guid><description>First, chill out. I promise I’ll make this make sense. Heck, if you can read this entire essay with an open mind before loading your mouth-canon for a bombardment my way, I’ll even wager you’ll agree with me. Disclosure: I’m not a member of either the Republican or Democratic Parties, but identify as a socially-conscious independent.</description></item></channel></rss>