<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Simple Productivity Hack: Leave your charger at home</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 21:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-productivity-forget-charger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to keep this short, because I only have 56 minutes of battery left on my laptop and still have about 100 emails I want to write today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get work done, and are having a hard time controlling your focus (Facebook), keeping yourself from being distracted (Twitter), or hurdling any of the other hurdles between you and what you need to do today (Taylor Swift’s instagram account), take your laptop to a coffee shop and leave your charger at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Three Rs of Saw Sharpening</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 04:48:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</guid><description>As I mentioned a couple days ago, I’ve got a bit of a break before I head back on the road for my next gig. This is important time for me, because it’s the time that I set aside every year to sharpen my saw.</description></item></channel></rss>