<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Better Humaning on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/better-humaning/</link><description>Recent content in Better Humaning on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/categories/better-humaning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 9:3:1 Learning Rule</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 19:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-9-3-1-learning-rule/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you’re trying to learn a new thing — a skill, talent, instrument, sport, language, anything — there are a million things that can derail you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard not to become fatigued, discouraged, frustrated, lose sight of your goal, or become distracted by a brighter light in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even assuming you get everything else right, and none of those detours push you off path, it’s still common to plateau early and stop making progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rule is to prevent that from happening: &lt;strong>say hello to the 9:3:1 Rule, a guide for how to allocate your time while learning a new thing.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancel Debts Not People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cancel-debts-not-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elizabeth Warren has thrown her hat in on a bold idea that’s been in the air for a long time: &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@teamwarren/im-calling-for-something-truly-transformational-universal-free-public-college-and-cancellation-of-a246cd0f910f">cancel student loan debt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not interest rate decreases, or refinancing, or other half-measures, but an all out cancelation of up to $50K in student loan debt for anyone whose income is $100K or less. Combined with universal free public higher education going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was first introduced to this idea back in the early 2010s the &lt;a href="https://rollingjubilee.org/">Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a>, a project by &lt;a href="https://strikedebt.org/">Strike Debt&lt;/a>, which has now evolved into &lt;a href="https://debtcollective.org/">The Debt Collective&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their project leveraged one of the most dysfunctional aspects of student loan debt: the fact that the debts get bundled and resold, over and over, for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling Jubilee raised $701,317 dollars (a few of which were mine, even as a broke post-grad student living under a pile of debt) and bought bundles of debt worth a total of $31,982,455.76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, instead of trying to collect those debts, they abolished them. Poof. Gone. No more debt for the people whose loans were part of those bundles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those numbers highlight how broken, and at this point imaginary, the entire debt-debtor relationship is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what world does $700K buy $31M?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Problem of Progressivism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:01:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/progressivism-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>With more and more people talking about “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;oq=left+cannibalizing+itself&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.4775j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">the left cannibalizing itself&lt;/a>” and “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;oq=liberals+eating+their+own&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2521j1j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">liberals eating their own&lt;/a>,” or how “&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;oq=democrats+need+to+unite+to+defeat+trump&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.5472j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8">democrats need to unite to defeat Trump&lt;/a>,” we need to keep reminding ourselves and others about the problem of progressivism — instead of just beating the dead horse that is the problems &lt;em>within&lt;/em> progressivism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll start with the second one, because that’s what everyone won’t stop yelling about, and I’m afraid if I don’t do a little yelling you won’t hear me out on the part of this that I think is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here it is, me jumping on the dogpile: the left has some problems, and we’re getting in our own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that is true for the “right,” the “center,” liberals, progressives, leftists, Libertarians, Republicans, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally every political camp has problems. Any collection of humans with a count greater than 0 has problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, why is the trope of “liberals eat their own” so pervasive?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public Libraries Shouldn’t Exist</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:37:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Usually, when I’m at home in Austin, I work in coffee shops. Today, I’m working from our gobsmackingly beautiful public library. And I can’t help but repeatedly ask myself “What would happen if someone pitched the idea of a public library today?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a broken record in my brain. An audio loop. It plays every time I turn a corner in this space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What would it sound like to argue for the idea of a public library in 2019?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When Ambition is Hiding</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/ambition-hiding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consider a few alternatives. Let’s say I told you:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>I want to remove every unhealthy habit, food, and mindset from my life, and I&amp;#8217;m going to start tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>I&amp;#8217;m going to eat less sugar, starting tomorrow.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When tomorrow comes, which one are you likely to hold me accountable to? Which might you help me excuse when I fall short? Which are you actually expecting me to do? Or even realistically try?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do a few more with those questions in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I say:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my country to 100% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B. &lt;/strong>It&amp;#8217;s my goal to transform my local school district to 50% renewable energy.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Or:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>A.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to end racism, globally.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>B.&lt;/strong> My organization is going to help local people of color, and other disenfranchised people, register to vote and get to the polls.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s plenty to get the point I’m going to make, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But first, here’s what I’m not about to say:&lt;/strong> that any of the As above — the lofty, admirable, pie-in-the-sky ambitions — are in any way bad, undesirable, or something I’m advocating against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want all of those things. I have, at different points in my life, said all of those things, in some way or another. And I don’t even like &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/">thinking of myself as ambitious&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here’s all I want to point out:&lt;/strong> sometime we set the bar so high because it gives us an excuse when we can’t clear it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Creative March</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 23:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/the-creative-march/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last few weeks have been marked by creativity. I love that feeling. I want to make it happen more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bill Gates is frequently quoted for saying, “Most people overestimate what they can do in one year and underestimate what they can do in ten years.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel this contrast more intensely on a smaller scale: &lt;strong>we overestimate what we can do in a day, and underestimate what we can do in a year.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s so easy for me to think of myself as a creative person — a writer, a doodler, a designer, a coder — even when I don’t create anything in a given day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I’m not really a writer when I’m not writing. I’m a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/big-flu-no-news/">reader of political news&lt;/a>, or a dog walker, or a cook, or a &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">compulsively rechecking my email because it triggers a dopamine response-er&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been “working on a book for three years” now, but I haven’t truly been &lt;em>working&lt;/em> on that book for three years. I’ve barely worked on it at all. A few minutes here, an hour there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creativity is an act, and one that is so easily sidelined by other actions — anything that feels safer, simpler, easier, or fulfills a shortsighted desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many people do you know who are “working” on things that never get any creative time dedicated to them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How many projects are you “working” on that you haven’t sat down in front of for over a week? A month? A year? Ever?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week, I finished and published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/">a book&lt;/a>. The week before I co-created and published a massive &lt;a href="https://thesafezoneproject.com/introducing-safe-zone-train-the-trainer-retreat-guide/">Train-the-Trainer Retreat Guide&lt;/a>. The week before that I wrote a new comedy show. And in between all of that I’ve made major strides in starting two new (secret, for now) projects. And I’ve only checked my email two thousand times (a made up number down from what I assume is my normal two million times per month).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the weeks before that, I was mostly just slogging through administrative stuff. Checking in on old things, closing out 2018. Not really making progress on anything, with only a few essays and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">one edugraphic&lt;/a> to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of that got me reflecting on the ebbs and flows of my own creativity, and wanting to come up with some personal &lt;a href="https://www.samkillermann.com/tag/challenge/">challenge&lt;/a> or strategy to get a better grasp on that part of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t want to spend most of my time on tasks that amount to nothing, but feel good in the moment (or at least don’t feel terrifying, like creativity often does).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to spend most of my time creating things that I share with the world, that are durable, that might exist when I’m gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As luck would have it, listening to &lt;a href="https://tim.blog/2019/02/18/jim-collins/">a podcast interview&lt;/a> today with &lt;a href="https://www.jimcollins.com">Jim Collins&lt;/a> gave me an exciting challenge that I’m going to start tonight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn For a Project, Not the Sake of Learning</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/project-based-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because I’m self-taught in most things I do — from programming to design to animation — a lot of my friends ask me for tips on how to learn a particular thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I want to learn how to make websites,” a friend will ask. “Where do you think I should start?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, I’ve given a lot of different responses. Pointing people to free online resources for learning, like &lt;a href="https://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/">Khan Academy&lt;/a>. Or telling them to join a local workshop or meet-up. Or both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not how I learned, but it’s easier to point someone to a resource than it is to give an autobiography for how I learned something myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, seeing that advice fail again and again prompted me to rethink my rationale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What would it look like, if I advised people to learn things how I’ve learned them?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You’re Not “Self-Employed”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past almost-decade, I’ve checked the “self-employed” box lots of times: when opening bank accounts, on lease applications for apartments, and it’s how the IRS sees me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s a lie. I’m not “self-employed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breaking the Chain of “Maybe”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a modern scourge upon us, and every get-together, plan, and social event is vulnerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know when it started, who’s to blame, or if it can be defeated, but I’ve begun vaccinating myself against it. And if you or your social circle have caught a case of the &lt;em>Maybes&lt;/em>, or you want to prevent an outbreak, here’s what you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step with any epidemic is understanding the problem: What is the Maybes, how does it spread, and why is it harmful?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Falling Off the Daily Meditation Path</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven’t meditated in over a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve become increasingly aware of this every day that passes. It’s become so big in my day, that, right now, Not Meditating feels like all I’ve accomplished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, here I am writing this instead of doing the damn thing. What is wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that I’ll appreciate my time sitting — both while it’s happening (even if I know it’ll be more fitful than usual) and after. It’ll give my day more focus, give me a breath between the world and my reactions to it, and I’ll feel happier, healthier, calmer, and whole-er.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of meditating, when I haven’t been, are always more obvious to me in the negative: the list of things I’ve been doing, thinking, eating, etc. that were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mindful, but were instead short-sighted comforts that led to longer-term pains. The things I &lt;em>wouldn’t&lt;/em> be doing if I &lt;em>had been&lt;/em> meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my recent memory is full of such things. My body and mind are weighed down with their aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet here I am, still Not Meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that all that’s standing between me getting back on that path or me continuing to flounder is a few minutes on the cushion. I’ve known that every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet I didn’t. I still haven’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what’s getting in my way? If you’ve ever experienced this — or currently are — what’s getting in our way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overthinking Everything So You Don’t Have To</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a confession to make: I’m an Overthinker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ve always been this way, but my condition has worsened with age. And my chosen profession didn’t help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I overthink as a matter of work, often. And I always overthink my work. Not just the things I make themselves, but how to describe what I do, and what unites it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately, I’ve come to think that the best way to describe my job is “overthinking everything so you don’t have to.” That’s no surprise, I’m sure, if you’ve popped around this site, or read &lt;a href="https://www.indiebound.org/search/book?keys=author%3AKillermann%2C%20Sam">my books&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://samuelkillermann.com">seen anything else I’ve made&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, ironically, I’m also driven, fundamentally, to empower people to _not _need me, via my work. I always endeavor to remove myself from the picture. Making myself irrelevant is one of my primary goals in everything I make, and it’s often the question that leads to the improvements or further work: “How can I create something that is freely available to prevent a person from needing to hire me to do it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why, for example, I released my copyright on my work back in 2013: I didn’t want people to have to keep asking me to use it, license it, or reprint it. I removed myself from the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this creates a bit of a conundrum. No surprise: me finding a conundrum. That’s Overthinking 101.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been [over-]thinking about that conundrum a lot. And I’ve felt a growing urge to reconcile it, which brings us here. To the how-to I never suspected I would write: A list of ways that I overthink everything, for those of you who want to DIY (OIY?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is the process I generally follow as I overthink everything in my life and work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I apply it to everything I create, to the social justice and human rights advocacy I engage in, to how I organize and operate on a “business” level, and even to how I do things in my “personal” life (relationships, puppy training, cooking, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the not-so-secret sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I suggest you proceed with caution. Overthinking is addictive. &lt;em>I wonder why that is.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Policing Voting vs. Nuance</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/policing-voting-vs-nuance/</guid><description>You can complain about politics if you don’t vote.
You’re not a bad human if you don’t vote.
You can still be my friend if you don’t vote.
And voting is an exceptional way to complain.
And it’s a perfect way to stake a claim in your humanity.</description></item><item><title>Learning from Mistakes Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/learning-from-mistakes-quote/</guid><description>Mistakes don’t guarantee learning, but learning requires mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 21:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/cant-stop-thinking-social-justice-dogma-keeping-quiet/</guid><description>&lt;p id="e3e7" class="graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf-after--figure">
Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I’m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word “lifestyle”). But this trip was different.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="28ff" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
In years past, the ideas I was presenting (i.e., social justice and anti-oppression concepts, centered around gender) were mostly received as new. And the questions aligned with that. But this year, a lot of the questions I was hearing weren’t responding to what I was saying on stage, as much as they were addressing things that were already bouncing around students’ minds before I got there. I just became the first “spokesperson” for social justice they were able to confront IRL.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5116" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
For example, in years past I got a lot of questions about things like “What do you mean gender and sexuality aren’t the same?” Or “What do you mean a woman can’t ‘oppress’ a man?”
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="b2a7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
But this year, a &lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em">bunch &lt;/em>of times (double digits) during Q&amp;As I was asked something that amounted to “So gender is a social construct, and so is race, so why are we accepting of &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caitlyn_Jenner">Caitlyn Jenner&lt;/a> but not &lt;a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Dolezal">Rachel Dolezal&lt;/a>?” By high schoolers. In rural Texas Ontario.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p id="5bb9" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">
Hold that thought. I’ll return to it, but first I want to take a step back.</description></item><item><title>A Fix: Politics Not Reminiscent of Sports</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/politics-not-as-sports/</guid><description>&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Political discourse is at a place where it’s hard — if not impossible — to see it as productive. Most times, it doesn’t even seem like folks who are arguing have a vision for anything being accomplished by that argument, other than hearing words yelled.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
Facts have been weaponized and are lobbed as projectiles, not used as tools to build a bridge from one perspective to another. Opinions are worn like armor, used to protect ourselves from the bombardment of facts. We scream for our ideas to drown out the screams of others for theirs.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="graf graf--p">
If sports are modeled after war, as many people say, our political discourse has taken a form modeled after the way we talk about sports.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="//wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="//tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I committed to writing on this site every day for 100 days in a row. Today, I’m committing to something similar and different: I’m going to start meditating every day, for at least the next 100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me explain why, and how I plan to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had an inconsistent meditation practice for about a decade now. At its best, I meditate every day for a streak of a week or two. At its worst, I meditate once a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here’s the thing: I know that meditation makes me happier, calmer, work better, think clearer — it makes me &lt;em>better.&lt;/em> Every time. I can even verify this for myself with some [obviously slanted] data: looking back at my journal, and comparing that against the records from the meditation app I use (Calm), I can see that on days I meditate I almost always finish every task I set out to do in the morning. I’m also more gracious, thoughtful, and patient in my responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the days I don’t meditate, well, I get by, but I’m a bit messier. And sometimes those days turn into weeks into months. That’s what’s happened these past few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the science backs this up, right? We all know this, if we exist even a little on the internet. Just google “&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=the+scientific+benefits+of+meditation">the scientific benefits of meditation&lt;/a>” and bask in the bazillion hits of glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Rationalize Being So Hard on Myself, &amp; How I’m Going to Stop</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/stop-being-harder-on-self/</guid><description>I’m my own worst critic. A lot of us are. I don’t like this about myself. A lot of us don’t. But I finally have a strategy to make it stop happening.
Of course we’re our own worst critics: we know better than anyone else our abilities, capacities, our “should”s — we know our potential, so we know when we fall short.</description></item><item><title>Be Bored</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 05:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</guid><description>&lt;p>Be bored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop. Whatever else you’re doing. Stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn off your music. Turn off the TV, Netflix Instant Streaming, Hulu+, Amazon Prime, all the things you use to fill your time. Not forever, not for long, but for right now, this moment, stop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Flowchart Will Change Your Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</guid><description>Hahaha — oh headlines. But seriously. You need no flowchart beyond this flowchart. View. Share. Love. Life.</description></item><item><title>Treating Old Friends Like New Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 05:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treating-old-friends-like-new-friends/</guid><description>I made a new friend (not bragging) who is so awesome (totally bragging) she makes me seem boring (humble bragging). I love making new friends. I love the adventure, the mystery, toeing and pushing the line, oversharing with whimsy — I love every step of the way.</description></item><item><title>“What is the meaning of life?”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 05:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</guid><description>“What’s the meaning of life?” he asked earnestly, as if he actually wanted the answer.
“To live true, to be honest, to experience spiritual connection, to give, to be…” he replied, rambling on platitudes. The same niceties he found himself saying on a regular basis — a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Many Lenses Construct Reality</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 04:19:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/lenses-construct-reality/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>We don’t live in the same world, you and I. But I’d love for you to try to show me yours, if I try to show you mine.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re an artist, you see line and shape wherever you look. You take note of the cues that create perspective, and imagine mixing the colors you see. You wonder how the reality you’re looking at might appear in pastels, oil, and acrylic, and how you might recreate that reality later, and how you might alter it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a comedian, you see humor between every line. Every word you hear, every thing you see, is passed through an algorithm in your head. [q:] Would that make people laugh on stage? [if no:] What do I need to change/tweak? [if yes:] Write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re a photographer, you see light and the absence of light in everything. You know that everything you’re looking at, and everything you can’t see, is being translated to your eyes through myriad reflections and refractions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing to Love Instead of Allowing Ourselves to Hate</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:13:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</guid><description>It’s gotten far easier to allow ourselves to hate than it is to choose to love.
We’re getting it from all sides. Controversy sells better than sex, and when you combine the two you have pretty much every magazine you see in the grocery store check-out line.</description></item><item><title>My List of 100 Dreams</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 06:03:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-list-of-100-dreams/</guid><description>Have y’all heard of Laura Vanderkam’s “List of 100 Dreams” idea? I hadn’t, but I have now, and I love it.
To me, it feels like a bucket list, but better: the items don’t have to feel realistic, or things you can only do if you put the time aside.</description></item><item><title>My Guitar is My Pacifier. What’s yours?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 05:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, I wake up spooning my guitar. This comforts me, then I realize I could have destroyed it so it terrifies me, then I realize I didn’t destroy it so I’m comforted again. It’s a roller coaster. Other days, my guitar is the first thing I reach for in the morning. I’m still rubbing sleepies out of my eyes while I fingerpick a few notes and think about what I’m going to do with my day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I’m having a tumultuous day, or I’m feeling particularly down, or I feel like the world is broken, or if I run out of hummus ingredients, I’ll pick it up, pick some strings, and it will immediately pick me up. Sometimes I only need a few minutes, sometimes I need a couple of hours, but it always works. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guitar is my pacifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Insulted When You Call Me Ambitious</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 04:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/insulted-by-ambition/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading a blog post someone wrote about me (I know. Let’s move on.) and they described me as “incredibly ambitious.” This was meant to be a compliment. Cool. Nice of you. But I don’t see it that way. I get upset when people describe me or think of me as ambitious. In general, I discourage ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many ways, ambition is the opposite of who I am, want to be, and what I want for others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Should Watch the Movie “About Time”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 05:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/you-should-watch-the-movie-about-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hadn’t really heard much about &lt;em>About Time&lt;/em>, the newest Love-Actually-Notting-Hill-Brit-Rom-Com-warm-fuzzy delight. And, to be honest, while I love watching feel-good movies (because they, you know, make me &lt;a href="//new-years-resolutions-happy-world/" title="If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier">feel good&lt;/a>), I don’t generally have high expectations for them. They tend to be rather empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one is not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being Sick is a Good Time For Catching Up</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/being-sick-catching-up/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 05:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/being-sick-catching-up/</guid><description>I don’t often get sick, but when I do, I get sick. While I was in New Orleans I came down with a wicked case of Swamp Flu. Or maybe it’s the Bayou Bug. I just hope it’s not Crawfish Sickness.</description></item><item><title>Single-Serving Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</guid><description>Edward Norton’s character in _Fight Club _introduced me to the term “single-serving friend,” a person who is your friend for a short period in time. In the movie, he’s talking about the people he meets on flights (“everything on a plane is single-serving”).</description></item><item><title>Genital Xenophobia and Genital Wanderlust: Show Me Yours and I’ll Show You Mine</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</guid><description>I remember the first time I played Show Me Yours I’ll Show You Mine. Some people call it Doctor. If you’ve never played, worry not: the rules are the simple. Show me yours. Then I show you mine. And who is the winner?</description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>If Passion Can Be Portrayed in Film</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/dark-side-of-the-lens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 05:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/dark-side-of-the-lens/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is what it might look like:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Abusive Relationship We’re All In That Most of Us Never Think About</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 03:17:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</guid><description>I saw this wonderful commercial earlier today and shared it on Facebook immediately. Watch it, then let’s talk about it.
Obviously, these aren’t new ideas to me. I talk a lot about the proverbial boxes we are all smushed into.</description></item><item><title>“Proud” and “Humbled”: I do not think it means what you think it means</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 21:19:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</guid><description>There’s an epidemic happening, people. It’s in my Facebook newsfeed and my Twitter tweetsfeed and my Google+ hahakiddingIdon’tcheckthatfeed. I believe it’s evolved from the fairly harmless confusion of their/they’re/there into the now dangerous misuse of “proud” and “humbled.”
The short version: people are saying they’re “proud” when they are really affirmingly excited, and they’re saying they’re “humbled” when they are really proud.</description></item><item><title>Be Your Own Friend First</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 05:38:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-your-own-friend-first/</guid><description>Everything you need to know about relationships you can learn from watching _Dexter _and _Scrubs. _Okay, that’s probably not true. But I really dig both shows, and I like what I’ve gleaned from both character’s approaches to life.
Dexter, the sociopath who lives a life of lies, is amazingly good at self care.</description></item><item><title>20+ Simple Tips for Living Mindfully</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 04:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</guid><description>Mindfulness is happiness. But you already know that. But what is mindfulness, beyond the abstract definition of “attentive, aware, or careful” that I gave in that other article? Being more mindful means tapping into all of your senses. If you’re more of a concrete person, here are a bunch of examples of how you can live a more mindful life.</description></item><item><title>The Three Rs of Saw Sharpening</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 04:48:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/saw-sharpening/</guid><description>As I mentioned a couple days ago, I’ve got a bit of a break before I head back on the road for my next gig. This is important time for me, because it’s the time that I set aside every year to sharpen my saw.</description></item><item><title>Asking For Help</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/asking-for-help/</guid><description>I have a hard time asking for help, likely mostly because I’m a dude. You might freak out reading this if you’re familiar with my other work, but let me write a few more words before we start sounding any alarms.</description></item><item><title>For Me, It’s About the People</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-me-its-about-the-people/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 02:45:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/for-me-its-about-the-people/</guid><description>After the second day of this conference, thinking about why I’ve had such a great experience, and why I find myself so connected to this world that a few days ago I was anything but, the answer is clear.
Ultimately, for me, it matters more who you are, and how you do something, than what you are actually doing.</description></item><item><title>Positivity in the Face of So Much Negativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/positivity-amidst-negativity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 05:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/positivity-amidst-negativity/</guid><description>I got an email with the above title and the following snippets, from a wonderful person who’s struggling with something I struggle with every day.
In following your blogs and talks, I’ve been impressed with the positivity and humor that you project.</description></item><item><title>These 6 Videos will Change the Way You Look at Unregulated Capitalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 23:49:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-capitalism-videos/</guid><description>RSA Animate: The Crises of Capitalism Wealth Inequality in America Naomi Klein: Addicted to Risk Alain de Botton: A Kinder, Gentler Philosophy of Success The Overview Effect Nic Marks: The Happy Planet Index</description></item><item><title>Being Alone Isn’t the Same as Being Lonely</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</guid><description>My post about going to see a movie by yourself has stirred up some wonderful conversations. And the title of this post is the most interesting thought that’s come from it, and I want to dive right in.
Being alone isn’t a bad thing.</description></item><item><title>Go See a Movie By Yourself</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 17:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/see-movie-by-yourself/</guid><description>I just got back from watching the new _Hunger Games _flick. I cried 15+ times in 146 minutes and left the theatre fired up to burn down the establishment. You should see it. I also went alone. And that’s not how you’re supposed to do that thing.</description></item><item><title>“What do you do?” vs “Who are you?”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-do-you-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/what-do-you-do/</guid><description>What’s the first question you ask someone you meet at a dinner party? “Can you point me in the direction of the hummus platter?” Okay, but the second question? “What do you _mean _they don’t have a hummus platter?!” You’re clearly hungry.</description></item><item><title>Today is Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</guid><description>Nothing particularly special happened today. One could call it, for me, a fairly unremarkable Saturday. I woke up to some bad news, spent most of my day in a relatively lazy fashion behind my computer, didn’t experience many of my favorite things about Austin, and now, an hour before midnight, my day is winding down.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow Will Be Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 05:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</guid><description>I spent most of the day today horizontal. I slept a lot, napped a bit, and snoozed when I wasn’t doing one of those two things. Yesterday was the exact opposite. I was vertical, doing, and doing some more. Both days have been perfect.</description></item><item><title>FRIENDSGIVING: My Island for Misfit Toys</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 01:56:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>I loved Thanksgiving growing up. As a kid, Thanksgiving is a wonderful event. You get a couple days off school, you eat too much, sleep too much, eat too much again, sleep again, repeat, then it’s Monday. Loved it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an adult, it can be fun, but it also tends to be a bit more stressful. Either you’re part of the shopping and prepping and cooking tornado, or you’re a worthless obstruction that gets caught up in its path (like those cows in &lt;em>Twister&lt;/em>). Throw in a bunch of people who don’t see each other often, starve them for a few hours, add two servings of booze, a sprinkling of reticent drama, and you’ve got Thanksgiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’d be okay with a revolution.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 19:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/okay-with-revolution/</guid><description>I wrote a Facebook status and Tweet last week that were meant to be a joke. A sarcastic, I want more out of the world, parody-type joke. But nobody laughed.
Post by Sam Killermann. I’m not mad. It was a bit too subtle for me to expect folks to catch the jokiness, and it’s cool that people echoed the top-level sentiment.</description></item><item><title>My Gratitude Challenge</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gratitude-challenge/</guid><description>My momma taught me to say please and thank you, to keep my elbows off the table, and to never chew with my mouth full. As a near grown-up Sam, these all feel as natural as breathing, blinking, or eating peanut butter directly from the jar with a spoon (sorry, Momma).</description></item><item><title>At What Point Do We Stop Thinking of Celebrities as People?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/celebrities-as-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 01:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/celebrities-as-people/</guid><description>Miley Cyrus hasn’t been a person for long time. She used to be a person, then she was Hannah Montana, and now she’s a punchline. Kanye West is a punchline that has tried to fight for his personhood, and as a result become a punchline within a punchline.</description></item><item><title>Living in the Undefined</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/living-in-the-undefined/</guid><description>It’s in our nature to define things. We like boxes, categories. A few thousand years ago, this was incredibly helpful. Don’t eat things that look like this: you will die. Eat things that look like this: they are delicious.
But nowadays, I find that my compulsion to define things is incredibly unhelpful.</description></item><item><title>The 3 Ingredients to a Happy Existence</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:11:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intentionality, Mindfulness, and Minimalism are all you need, beyond basic biological requirements (clean water, nutritious food, human touch, etc.), to live a happy existence. This is what I’ve come to believe. I’ll define what I mean by all three, and talk about their relationship to one another, but first I want to talk about “happiness.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t aspire toward being happy all the time, nor do I recommend it. I don’t think of happiness as existing at the opposite end of sadness, nor do I think that sadness is inherently bad. All emotions have value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think of happiness on a continuum with lack of happiness on the other end, sadness on a continuum with lack of sadness on the other end, and so forth. Experiencing happiness doesn’t necessarily make you less sad — The Barenaked Ladies kew this: “I’m the kind of guy who laughs at a funeral.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reasons I Know My Heart is in Austin, Texas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-heart-in-austin-texas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 04:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-heart-in-austin-texas/</guid><description>I travel a lot for work. As anyone who travels for work will know, people always say, “You get to travel a lot? That must be nice!” And it is nice. It’s fun to see all the different nooks and crannies of the United States, and I love meeting people from all the different walks of life I do.</description></item><item><title>Making a Bigger “Us” and a Smaller “Them”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 03:53:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/us-vs-them/</guid><description>Today I read a fantastic interview with Bills Clinton and Gates on _Wired. _I highly recommend reading the whole thing, because a lot of great things were said. These are two people who lived incredible, noteworthy lives, retired, then, for no other reason than because, proceeded to start second incredible, noteworthy lives.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m Glad Chivalry is Dead, From The Perspective of A Man Who Actually Likes Women</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 02:54:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</guid><description>There’s this article, “Why Chivalry is Dead, From a Man’s Perspective,” from John Picciuto on _Elite Daily _that’s popped up in my Facebook newsfeed a lot. It’s been shared by my friends of varying genders with captions like “Amen” and “FTW” and “Finally.</description></item><item><title>I Miss Wondering</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier tonight, I turned the burner on high and while I was waiting for my rice to come to a full boil I had a thought: “I wonder if rice cooked in beer would be good.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, I would have likely wondered that for quite a while. It may have been on my mind while I ate my boring water-based rice. It may have popped into my mind tomorrow, or the next day, when I next saw rice or beer. Visions of beer-based rice recipes might have danced in my belly. I may have wondered about it for a week (or ten) before I finally giving in, cooking it, and exiting Wonderland for Knowville.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of that happened, because Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the water (boring) in the pot began boiling I already knew if “beer rice” was a thing, what it would taste like (delicious), exactly how to make it, and what types of recipes it would be good in (ALL OF THEM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For One Week, Starting Now, I Will Tell No Lies</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 01:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/no-lying-for-one-week/</guid><description>I lie a lot. I didn’t realize that until I started following Sam Harris, the Author of Lying, on Twitter (I highly recommend following him, by the way — dude’s got a great first name). A few days ago one of my Twitter buds retweeted his challenge below, which is how I was introduced to Sam (great name, by the way) and his work.</description></item><item><title>Working to End Oppression Makes More Sense as a Republican Value than a Democratic One</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 18:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/republican-values-against-oppression/</guid><description>First, chill out. I promise I’ll make this make sense. Heck, if you can read this entire essay with an open mind before loading your mouth-canon for a bombardment my way, I’ll even wager you’ll agree with me. Disclosure: I’m not a member of either the Republican or Democratic Parties, but identify as a socially-conscious independent.</description></item><item><title>I Don’t Believe in God, but I Do Believe in A Lot</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 17:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</guid><description>I don’t believe in God. Saying this is easier now than it was when I was a kid, because I was struggling equal parts internally with my lack of faith and externally with the reactions of people in my life when they found out.</description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>