<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Habits on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/habits/</link><description>Recent content in Habits on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 Simple Things You Can Do to Curb Your Phone Addiction Right Now</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of us are addicted to our phones. If you’ve started to see why this might not be the best thing ever, and want to ween yourself off of that tantalizingly non-nourishing blue glow, you’re in good company. This is something I’ve been thinking about, and experimenting with, for a few years now. Following are three things you knock out in about 15 minutes, that will benefit you for weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I get into those, I want to be clear: I’m talking about the colloquial, not clinical, usage of the term “addiction.” In this post, I’m not staking my flag in the hill that “phone addiction” is (or isn’t) real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’m talking about here, as addiction, is the compulsive use of our phones. That we’re spending more time poking around our phones than we want to, picking them up and checking the screen before we realize we’re doing it, and that our phones aren’t adding quality to our lives, and might be distracting us from the things we’d actually care about enjoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m talking about how we’re &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/">already dating our phones&lt;/a>, and how &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">little red numbers are trying to rule our lives&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Falling Off the Daily Meditation Path</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/falling-off-the-daily-meditation-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven’t meditated in over a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve become increasingly aware of this every day that passes. It’s become so big in my day, that, right now, Not Meditating feels like all I’ve accomplished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, here I am writing this instead of doing the damn thing. What is wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that I’ll appreciate my time sitting — both while it’s happening (even if I know it’ll be more fitful than usual) and after. It’ll give my day more focus, give me a breath between the world and my reactions to it, and I’ll feel happier, healthier, calmer, and whole-er.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of meditating, when I haven’t been, are always more obvious to me in the negative: the list of things I’ve been doing, thinking, eating, etc. that were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mindful, but were instead short-sighted comforts that led to longer-term pains. The things I &lt;em>wouldn’t&lt;/em> be doing if I &lt;em>had been&lt;/em> meditating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my recent memory is full of such things. My body and mind are weighed down with their aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet here I am, still Not Meditating. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that all that’s standing between me getting back on that path or me continuing to flounder is a few minutes on the cushion. I’ve known that every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet I didn’t. I still haven’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what’s getting in my way? If you’ve ever experienced this — or currently are — what’s getting in our way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Be the Wind or the Sail Quote</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 21:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-the-wind-or-the-sail-quote/</guid><description> Be the wind, or risk becoming the sail.</description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="//wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="//tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protecting Good Habits</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 05:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/protecting-good-habits/</guid><description>We’ve heard it a million times: “old habits die hard.” But that’s not true. Truly, “bad habits die hard.” I can attest to this, using this Thought/Day project as an example.
Up until last week, I was 81 for 81 days in a row of writing and publishing a thought each day.</description></item></channel></rss>