<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Progress Report on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/progress-report/</link><description>Recent content in Progress Report on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/progress-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>After 7 Years Doing this Work, I’m [Re-] Branding. Here’s how I’m making decisions.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 23:20:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/after-7-years-doing-this-work-im-re-branding-heres-how-im-making-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got thrown into this. Two-fold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got thrown into the work I’ve been doing. And I got thrown into a situation that’s led me to question everything, rethink and restructure, and make decisions that feel like an overall “brand.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’m happy I’m here, one of the strongest forces that’s guiding what I do next is precisely avoiding how I got here: no more being thrown into stuff. Seem easy? Maybe. Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll get to that in a second, but first the back story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Totally new site. Slightly new direction.</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/totally-new-site-slightly-new-direction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 04:52:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/totally-new-site-slightly-new-direction/</guid><description>Howdy! Today marks two turning points: the design of this site has changed (from this to this), and the name has changed (from “Dear World” to “Sam Killermann’s Blog”).
From here on, in addition to things I’ve been writing about before (like happiness &amp;amp; technology), I’ll also be writing about how I DIY (do it myself) in all things social good &amp;amp; online platform related, and posting more personal updates about my work/life.</description></item><item><title>2016, A Brief Review of Creativity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 02:08:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2016-brief-review-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 was, well, _quite _the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, I side with what appears to be the consensus that it was, if given only one descriptor, a dumpster fire. That said, it was also more than a dumpster fire, and I want to take a moment to reflect on some of the things I made this year — something I basically never do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that said, following is what I finished, published, and/or created in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet FacilitatingXYZ: A Free Online Resource for ALL Facilitators</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 13:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/why-im-so-excited-about-facilitatingxyz/</guid><description>&lt;address>
&lt;strong>Updated September 12, 2016:&lt;/strong> we officially launched this project, after about 11 months in development, production, and ideation. Woohoo!
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz">FacilitatingXYZ&lt;/a> is everything I wish I had when I got started as a facilitator — and &lt;a href="http://facilitating.xyz/manifesto">together&lt;/a>, we can build it into something that helps us continue to learn, develop, and grow. It’s a free online resource with videos, articles, downloads and (soon!) community to help all facilitators improve their craft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Publishing A Book</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-publishing-a-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m writing from a rooftop in Austin, taking a break from my break — which was part Naomi Klein and part Real Ale — to share a reflection that just sunk in: I’m about to publish my first book, and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to be clear: this isn’t me publishing the first book I wrote (that happened a couple years ago, and still hasn’t sunk in); this is me, under the auspices of &lt;a href="http://impetus.pw">Impetus Books&lt;/a>, publishing my first book someone else wrote (in this case, I’m glowingly happy to say that someone else is Karen Rayne).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>InTolerance: Why I’m Writing A New Show About Prejudice, Faith, and Identity</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 14:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-show-in-tolerance/</guid><description>In a few short days, I’ll be debuting a new show. To those who have followed my work, I understand that the topic (faith) and setting (a church) feel like they are coming out of left field. And that feeling couldn’t be more right — that’s why I’m doing this show.</description></item><item><title>How I Keep Track of 50 Projects at Once (&amp; Maintain Some Sanity)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 02:08:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/managing-ideas/</guid><description>I’m currently in the process of finishing two books, starting another, publishing two new sexuality models, three new live social justice comedy shows, running half a dozen volunteer-based initiatives, building I’m-not-even-sure-how-many websites, and the list goes on. It’s a lot. And as I type that, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>Do, Reflect, Tweak, Do: From Thought/Day to Dear World</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/rethinking-thought-per-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first started this project several months ago, I was &lt;a href="//welcome/" title="Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day">pretty clear&lt;/a> about what my goal was with the writing here: in short, nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted a space to explore new ideas, to reflect, to write, to share, but without any particular “goal.” So much of the writing I do is extremely goal-oriented. I wanted to see what would happen if I created a space that was less structured. I wasn’t sure what I’d end up writing about, what shape this site would take, and was happy to follow my fingers on an adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was fun. I wrote a lot of things I’d’ve never written otherwise, found that I have thoughts about seemingly random things that others find value in reading. I only got a few pieces of hatemail compared to a pile of encouragemail — this was new. I started with only one real rule, but I broke it after about 100 days. I was planning on writing once a day, and when I started traveling a lot at the beginning of this year, I missed one day. And that’s the funny thing about &lt;a href="//protecting-good-habits/">habits&lt;/a> — one missed day is alarmingly similar to one missed month, then you’re only a hop &amp;amp; skip away from a &lt;em>never happening again ever.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After missing a few days, I experienced stress related to this project that I hadn’t experienced, and decided that it was time to take a break from it, reflect, and see if it still has a healthy place in my life. I’ve done that now, and I’m happy to say that it does. &lt;em>Kinda.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gone is &lt;em>Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day&lt;/em>. Welcome _Dear World, _a much more fitting title for what’s going to be happening here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Be Bored</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 05:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/be-bored/</guid><description>&lt;p>Be bored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop. Whatever else you’re doing. Stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn off your music. Turn off the TV, Netflix Instant Streaming, Hulu+, Amazon Prime, all the things you use to fill your time. Not forever, not for long, but for right now, this moment, stop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Four Different Versions of Me</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/four-mes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:40:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/four-mes/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s weird, ya know, waking up to emails from four different people I don’t know, who don’t know me, but think they do. Depicting four vastly different mes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who hates families, Christians, and Christian families. Who is dedicated to “destroying Western Civilization” and will be promptly burning in Hell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who is saintlike in his love and compassion for others, who is “a glimpse of light in a world that’s gotten dark.” Whose work “literally saved my life.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Me who is motivated solely by ulterior motives, greed, and who would “best serve the LGBT community by killing yourself.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Let’s Be Honest: We’re Already Dating Our Phones</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 05:58:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yo. I just saw &lt;em>Her.&lt;/em> It’s cray. It’s powerfully well-written and brings up a lot of thoughts about how we might relate to technology and one another in the future. But it also made me think a lot about how we relate to technology and one another right now. If you have a smart phone and you’ve seen &lt;em>Her&lt;/em>, you’ve likely had a lot of these thoughts already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s hard to convince myself that we’re not already dating our phones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Work on the Internet (In 5 Easy Steps)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I work on the internet. Even now, in The Year Two-Thousand Fourteen, I have to describe what I do with those five words. A talk I heard recently by Heather Corinna, another person who works &lt;a title="So Good." href="http://scarleteen.com" target="_blank">on the internet&lt;/a>, who spoke about working on the internet, was a reminder of this for me, as I found myself relating to everything she said. Five words still when it should really be two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“On the internet” means a ton of things to a ton of different people. “That’s so techy” or “my, how quickly things change!” often translates to me as “ARE YOU FROM THE FUTURE?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some people “on the internet” undoes the “I work” part: “Oh, neat, yeah, but what’s your real job?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my real job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We live in the future, people. There are no flying cars (&lt;a href="http://www.irishmirror.ie/news/world-news/terrafugia-flying-cars-could-sale-2998745" target="_blank">soon&lt;/a>! wanna go halfsies?), but there are shabbily-dressed people working on laptops in coffee shops. The future is here, and it’s unshaven. The only reason we’re still making the “on the internet” distinction is because of the [sometimes willful] ignorance about what the world looks like and how much things have changed in a short amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play catch up (please, do not think any of what I’m suggesting here is anywhere near the cutting edge), let me share with you a few starter steps for working on the internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBooker’s Creed</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/macbook-creed/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my MacBook. There are many like it, but this one is mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook is my best friend. It is my life. I must master it as I must master my life.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="line-height: 1.5em;">My MacBook, without me, is still pretty shiny. Without my MacBook, I am useless and not at all shiny and can’t watch Netflix in bed (which I love). I must type words into Pages. I must type words into email correctly or autocorrect may ruin my life. I must send that email before I receive another email or email overload may ruin my life. I will…&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>50 Thoughts, New Site, Checking in on What I’ve Learned</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 05:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/50-thoughts-checking-in/</guid><description>This will be my fifty-first post on this site. It’s been a fun fifty-one days of this experiment.
When I set out on this adventure I was hoping to accomplish several things, a couple in particular: to learn more about myself and get the ideas that rattle around in my head out into words.</description></item><item><title>My Computer Died, but that’s Good</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 01:14:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-computer-died/</guid><description>&lt;p>I woke up this morning to my computer not working. It’s not been in great shape these past few months, and has occasionally tossed a surprise my way. It’s several years old, and I’ve put it through plenty of hell with all my traveling (and general clumsiness). I’d already been investigating new options, and weighing the pros and cons. I knew its time was drawing near.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of work on my plate right now, and a lot of it’s time sensitive. And chief thing on my mind is the Nat’l Sex Ed Conference next week, for which I’m excited to be one of the keynotes. I have a few pressing collaborations, plenty of more people who I’ve promised e-love to, and some big personal projects that are underway. Objectively, it’s not an ideal time for my computer to bail on me. But subjectively, I’m excited for a few days without my computer, amidst a few of the days this year I most crushingly want to feel like I _need _it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.5 Weeks and 15,000 Words in, How Am I Feeling About Thought / Day?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 05:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/2-5-weeks-and-15000-words/</guid><description>I’ve written a lot in these past few weeks of this new experiment. When I launched this site I shared a few of my reasons why, but I have also been aware from the start that I really didn’t know where this project would go, and I still don’t.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Sam Killermann’s Thought / Day</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 19:26:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I created this because it’s been a long time coming, and I decided to stop letting time slip away.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People have asked again and again if I have a personal blog. I do not. Well, I _did _not. I do now. And I will keep it up for at least one year. 365 days. 12 months. And probably about 500,000 words.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>