<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Feedback on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/feedback/</link><description>Recent content in Feedback on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 20:35:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/feedback/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying to Overcome the Numbers that Rule My Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 20:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never considered myself a “numbers” person. I don’t mean I wasn’t good at math (Mathlete, y’all!), but I care more about stories than stats. On the Myers-Briggs Typology Instrument, for example, my F to T (Feeling to Thinking) ratio is the most unbalanced, and I’m a _strong _F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I do — every &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> I do — while seemingly disparate, is all connected by that trait. Every little project or endeavor I undertake is driven by my goal of making the world a safer place for all people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it’s as surprising to me as it might be to you how numbers-driven my day-to-day life is, and how much I find myself trying to turn that part of my brain off so I can focus on the present. The numbers eat at me, often glaring at me from within little red circles, screaming “Click me! Make me go away!” Others are tucked away within more complex websites or spreadsheets, whispering more gently, but still persuasively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a small taste of the numbers that are almost always whizzing around my brain, attempting to distract me from the task at hand. Every one of these things pops into my head at once when I wake up every morning, then attempts to suckle my brainjuice every minute of every hour I’m awake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let Your Teacher Grade Your Test</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/let-your-teacher-grade-your-test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 04:38:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/let-your-teacher-grade-your-test/</guid><description>I did a show earlier today, which isn’t that odd, or thought-provoking. I do shows a lot. It’s what I do. But the show today was different from any show I’ve done, because it was over Skype. That was a first for me.</description></item></channel></rss>