<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophizin on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/philosophizin/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophizin on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:16:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/philosophizin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You’re Not “Self-Employed”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/self-employed/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past almost-decade, I’ve checked the “self-employed” box lots of times: when opening bank accounts, on lease applications for apartments, and it’s how the IRS sees me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s a lie. I’m not “self-employed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overthinking Everything So You Don’t Have To</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a confession to make: I’m an Overthinker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ve always been this way, but my condition has worsened with age. And my chosen profession didn’t help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I overthink as a matter of work, often. And I always overthink my work. Not just the things I make themselves, but how to describe what I do, and what unites it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately, I’ve come to think that the best way to describe my job is “overthinking everything so you don’t have to.” That’s no surprise, I’m sure, if you’ve popped around this site, or read &lt;a href="https://www.indiebound.org/search/book?keys=author%3AKillermann%2C%20Sam">my books&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://samuelkillermann.com">seen anything else I’ve made&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, ironically, I’m also driven, fundamentally, to empower people to _not _need me, via my work. I always endeavor to remove myself from the picture. Making myself irrelevant is one of my primary goals in everything I make, and it’s often the question that leads to the improvements or further work: “How can I create something that is freely available to prevent a person from needing to hire me to do it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why, for example, I released my copyright on my work back in 2013: I didn’t want people to have to keep asking me to use it, license it, or reprint it. I removed myself from the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this creates a bit of a conundrum. No surprise: me finding a conundrum. That’s Overthinking 101.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been [over-]thinking about that conundrum a lot. And I’ve felt a growing urge to reconcile it, which brings us here. To the how-to I never suspected I would write: A list of ways that I overthink everything, for those of you who want to DIY (OIY?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is the process I generally follow as I overthink everything in my life and work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I apply it to everything I create, to the social justice and human rights advocacy I engage in, to how I organize and operate on a “business” level, and even to how I do things in my “personal” life (relationships, puppy training, cooking, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the not-so-secret sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I suggest you proceed with caution. Overthinking is addictive. &lt;em>I wonder why that is.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Road Away From Email</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/road-away-from-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>I wish I never had to read another email.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve said thousands of times, aloud and in my head (mostly in my head). I’ve said it in anger after opening &lt;a href="http://itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/">another death threat&lt;/a>. I’ve said it in frustration when an email sent me down a rabbit hole that took me away from a project I had planned for the day. It’s been an underlying sentiment for years, but it wasn’t until recently that it turned into a concrete plan:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I am going to stop reading emails.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Flowchart Will Change Your Life</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/this-flowchart-will-change-your-life/</guid><description>Hahaha — oh headlines. But seriously. You need no flowchart beyond this flowchart. View. Share. Love. Life.</description></item><item><title>I Miss Wondering</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 05:41:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-miss-wondering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier tonight, I turned the burner on high and while I was waiting for my rice to come to a full boil I had a thought: “I wonder if rice cooked in beer would be good.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years ago, I would have likely wondered that for quite a while. It may have been on my mind while I ate my boring water-based rice. It may have popped into my mind tomorrow, or the next day, when I next saw rice or beer. Visions of beer-based rice recipes might have danced in my belly. I may have wondered about it for a week (or ten) before I finally giving in, cooking it, and exiting Wonderland for Knowville.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But none of that happened, because Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the water (boring) in the pot began boiling I already knew if “beer rice” was a thing, what it would taste like (delicious), exactly how to make it, and what types of recipes it would be good in (ALL OF THEM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Don’t Believe in God, but I Do Believe in A Lot</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 17:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/i-dont-believe-in-god/</guid><description>I don’t believe in God. Saying this is easier now than it was when I was a kid, because I was struggling equal parts internally with my lack of faith and externally with the reactions of people in my life when they found out.</description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>