<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Holidays on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/holidays/</link><description>Recent content in Holidays on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/holidays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>FRIENDSGIVING: My Island for Misfit Toys</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 01:56:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/friendsgiving-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>I loved Thanksgiving growing up. As a kid, Thanksgiving is a wonderful event. You get a couple days off school, you eat too much, sleep too much, eat too much again, sleep again, repeat, then it’s Monday. Loved it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an adult, it can be fun, but it also tends to be a bit more stressful. Either you’re part of the shopping and prepping and cooking tornado, or you’re a worthless obstruction that gets caught up in its path (like those cows in &lt;em>Twister&lt;/em>). Throw in a bunch of people who don’t see each other often, starve them for a few hours, add two servings of booze, a sprinkling of reticent drama, and you’ve got Thanksgiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Halloween, As Viewed Through Many Eyes</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/halloween-through-many-eyes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 19:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/halloween-through-many-eyes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Halloween has always been my favorite holiday. It is the one time of the year when it is acceptable — even encouraged — to be whoever, or whatever, you want to be — to pretend, to take chances, to wear gaudy lipstick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing up, crafting costumes and living as someone else for a night was something I looked forward to the entire year — far more than the punch-you-in-your-pancreas sugar overdose, though who doesn’t prefer their apples covered in a gravy of melted sugar and butter, the way God intended. As an adult (or at least as “adult” as I ever plan on getting), so much of my time and work is focused on helping people understand identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The irony is not lost on me.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>