<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cover Stories on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/cover-stories/</link><description>Recent content in Cover Stories on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/cover-stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking the Chain of “Maybe”</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maybes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a modern scourge upon us, and every get-together, plan, and social event is vulnerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know when it started, who’s to blame, or if it can be defeated, but I’ve begun vaccinating myself against it. And if you or your social circle have caught a case of the &lt;em>Maybes&lt;/em>, or you want to prevent an outbreak, here’s what you can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step with any epidemic is understanding the problem: What is the Maybes, how does it spread, and why is it harmful?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/building-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I committed to writing on this site every day for 100 days in a row. Today, I’m committing to something similar and different: I’m going to start meditating every day, for at least the next 100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me explain why, and how I plan to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had an inconsistent meditation practice for about a decade now. At its best, I meditate every day for a streak of a week or two. At its worst, I meditate once a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here’s the thing: I know that meditation makes me happier, calmer, work better, think clearer — it makes me &lt;em>better.&lt;/em> Every time. I can even verify this for myself with some [obviously slanted] data: looking back at my journal, and comparing that against the records from the meditation app I use (Calm), I can see that on days I meditate I almost always finish every task I set out to do in the morning. I’m also more gracious, thoughtful, and patient in my responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the days I don’t meditate, well, I get by, but I’m a bit messier. And sometimes those days turn into weeks into months. That’s what’s happened these past few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the science backs this up, right? We all know this, if we exist even a little on the internet. Just google “&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=the+scientific+benefits+of+meditation">the scientific benefits of meditation&lt;/a>” and bask in the bazillion hits of glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>“Proud” and “Humbled”: I do not think it means what you think it means</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 21:19:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/proud-humbled-misunderstanding/</guid><description>There’s an epidemic happening, people. It’s in my Facebook newsfeed and my Twitter tweetsfeed and my Google+ hahakiddingIdon’tcheckthatfeed. I believe it’s evolved from the fairly harmless confusion of their/they’re/there into the now dangerous misuse of “proud” and “humbled.”
The short version: people are saying they’re “proud” when they are really affirmingly excited, and they’re saying they’re “humbled” when they are really proud.</description></item><item><title>Being Alone Isn’t the Same as Being Lonely</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/alone-not-lonely/</guid><description>My post about going to see a movie by yourself has stirred up some wonderful conversations. And the title of this post is the most interesting thought that’s come from it, and I want to dive right in.
Being alone isn’t a bad thing.</description></item><item><title>We Fabricate the Obstacles that Stand Between Us and Happiness</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 04:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-fabricate-the-obstacles-to-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>You sit down in a restaurant, the server comes over and asks what’ll you have. “I would like a double bacon cheeseburger, please. I prefer my fermented milk on top of pig on top of cow on top of cow.” Then the server replies, “No problem, hun’. Just put together this 5,000 piece puzzle &lt;em>Minimalist Sand Dune&lt;/em> and I’ll have your order right out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That hopefully sounds absurd. You’d never stand for that. “I’ll eat my heart attack somewhere else!” you might yell. But we do stand for that. We put 5,000+ piece puzzles between ourselves and things we want every day, and we don’t even realize we’re doing it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>