<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How-To on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in How-To on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 Simple Things You Can Do to Curb Your Phone Addiction Right Now</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/anti-phone-addiction-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of us are addicted to our phones. If you’ve started to see why this might not be the best thing ever, and want to ween yourself off of that tantalizingly non-nourishing blue glow, you’re in good company. This is something I’ve been thinking about, and experimenting with, for a few years now. Following are three things you knock out in about 15 minutes, that will benefit you for weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I get into those, I want to be clear: I’m talking about the colloquial, not clinical, usage of the term “addiction.” In this post, I’m not staking my flag in the hill that “phone addiction” is (or isn’t) real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’m talking about here, as addiction, is the compulsive use of our phones. That we’re spending more time poking around our phones than we want to, picking them up and checking the screen before we realize we’re doing it, and that our phones aren’t adding quality to our lives, and might be distracting us from the things we’d actually care about enjoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m talking about how we’re &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/we-are-dating-our-phones/">already dating our phones&lt;/a>, and how &lt;a href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/numbers-rule-my-life/">little red numbers are trying to rule our lives&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Checklist to Work Through Before Creating Any New Website, Blog, or App</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:20:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/design-goals-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you thinking about creating a website? Or a blog? Or an app? Do you want to be “in the cloud,” but you’re not really sure what that is? Have you been talking with colleagues about this idea, or received direction from your boss, and started figuring out how to do it yourself, or looking into hiring a designer/developer to build it for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great! Good on you. Making things is really exciting, and it’s really fun to hit the ground running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The natural next step you might make is to start price shopping around, looking for an agency or creative you can afford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not great! But no fault to you: this is what most people do next. And it’s something that results in a lot of wasted money in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you start designing or building something that you have in mind, and &lt;em>definitely&lt;/em> before you start paying someone else to, there are a few things you need to figure out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overthinking Everything So You Don’t Have To</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 20:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/overthinking-everything-so-you-dont-have-to/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a confession to make: I’m an Overthinker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ve always been this way, but my condition has worsened with age. And my chosen profession didn’t help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I overthink as a matter of work, often. And I always overthink my work. Not just the things I make themselves, but how to describe what I do, and what unites it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately, I’ve come to think that the best way to describe my job is “overthinking everything so you don’t have to.” That’s no surprise, I’m sure, if you’ve popped around this site, or read &lt;a href="https://www.indiebound.org/search/book?keys=author%3AKillermann%2C%20Sam">my books&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://samuelkillermann.com">seen anything else I’ve made&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, ironically, I’m also driven, fundamentally, to empower people to _not _need me, via my work. I always endeavor to remove myself from the picture. Making myself irrelevant is one of my primary goals in everything I make, and it’s often the question that leads to the improvements or further work: “How can I create something that is freely available to prevent a person from needing to hire me to do it?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s why, for example, I released my copyright on my work back in 2013: I didn’t want people to have to keep asking me to use it, license it, or reprint it. I removed myself from the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this creates a bit of a conundrum. No surprise: me finding a conundrum. That’s Overthinking 101.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been [over-]thinking about that conundrum a lot. And I’ve felt a growing urge to reconcile it, which brings us here. To the how-to I never suspected I would write: A list of ways that I overthink everything, for those of you who want to DIY (OIY?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is the process I generally follow as I overthink everything in my life and work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I apply it to everything I create, to the social justice and human rights advocacy I engage in, to how I organize and operate on a “business” level, and even to how I do things in my “personal” life (relationships, puppy training, cooking, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the not-so-secret sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I suggest you proceed with caution. Overthinking is addictive. &lt;em>I wonder why that is.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Daily Meditation Habit</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/maintaining-daily-meditation-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m on day 9 of 100 in my quest to making meditation an integral part of my daily routine. At just shy of 10%, I have already learned a lot that will inform the next 90. I’m going to walk through what I’m planning to draw upon, from most concrete to most abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-tools-matter">1. Tools matter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="wp-block-image">
&lt;figure class="alignright">&lt;img data-src="http://samkillermann.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg" alt="meditation-progress-sam-killermann" class="wp-image-884 lazy-load" srcset="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429.jpg 350w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-150x150.jpg 150w, https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/meditation-progress-sam-killermann-e1474133301429-300x300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" />&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There’s this famous Audre Lorde quote that gets tossed around a lot in the social justice activism spaces I occupy: “For the master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks generally take it to mean that you can’t undo a harmful system using components that support that harmful system, or by working within that system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots and lots of debates about that quote, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=can+you+destroy+the+master's+house+using+the+master's+tools+audre+lorde+quote&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8">read them&lt;/a> (or we could get into them another time), but for now it’s the second part of the quote that I am appealing to (the part that is often omitted): “They may allow us to temporarily beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s this idea, that &lt;em>the master’s tools may temporarily allow us to be him at his own game&lt;/em>, that I’ve found to be particularly salient this past week. Indeed, I’ve managed to turn just about every thing in my life that led me to mindlessness into a tool to help me practice &lt;a href="http://samkillermann.wpengine.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/">mindfulness&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing to Love Instead of Allowing Ourselves to Hate</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:13:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/choose-to-love/</guid><description>It’s gotten far easier to allow ourselves to hate than it is to choose to love.
We’re getting it from all sides. Controversy sells better than sex, and when you combine the two you have pretty much every magazine you see in the grocery store check-out line.</description></item><item><title>How To Work on the Internet (In 5 Easy Steps)</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/how-to-work-on-the-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I work on the internet. Even now, in The Year Two-Thousand Fourteen, I have to describe what I do with those five words. A talk I heard recently by Heather Corinna, another person who works &lt;a title="So Good." href="http://scarleteen.com" target="_blank">on the internet&lt;/a>, who spoke about working on the internet, was a reminder of this for me, as I found myself relating to everything she said. Five words still when it should really be two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“On the internet” means a ton of things to a ton of different people. “That’s so techy” or “my, how quickly things change!” often translates to me as “ARE YOU FROM THE FUTURE?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some people “on the internet” undoes the “I work” part: “Oh, neat, yeah, but what’s your real job?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my real job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We live in the future, people. There are no flying cars (&lt;a href="http://www.irishmirror.ie/news/world-news/terrafugia-flying-cars-could-sale-2998745" target="_blank">soon&lt;/a>! wanna go halfsies?), but there are shabbily-dressed people working on laptops in coffee shops. The future is here, and it’s unshaven. The only reason we’re still making the “on the internet” distinction is because of the [sometimes willful] ignorance about what the world looks like and how much things have changed in a short amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play catch up (please, do not think any of what I’m suggesting here is anywhere near the cutting edge), let me share with you a few starter steps for working on the internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-Serving Friends</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/single-serving-friends/</guid><description>Edward Norton’s character in _Fight Club _introduced me to the term “single-serving friend,” a person who is your friend for a short period in time. In the movie, he’s talking about the people he meets on flights (“everything on a plane is single-serving”).</description></item><item><title>If Everyone Made these 12 New Year’s Resolutions, the World Would Be Happier</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 05:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/new-years-resolutions-happy-world/</guid><description>I’ve never been a fan of New Year’s resolutions. I’ve generally had the perspective of Mr. Twain. But that’s because resolutions are so commonly things that won’t actually improve someone’s life, or (and especially) the lives of others in their life.</description></item><item><title>14 Simple Ways to Treat Every Day More Like Christmas</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 05:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/treat-every-day-like-christmas/</guid><description>Christmas Time is a few days (or weeks, or months, at this point), when a lot of us change the ways we approach our life and the people in it.
There are a lot of positive changes that are part of that shift, things that would likely make the rest of us our year a bit more merry if we were intentional about them all twelve months.</description></item><item><title>100+ Tips for Minimalism</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 01:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/minimalism-tips/</guid><description>Kidding. 100 would be a bit excessive, and likely more than a bit counterintuitive, wouldn’t it? It’s easy for us to be seduced by a lot, and to think that more is better, but we rarely need more than a little.</description></item><item><title>20+ Simple Tips for Living Mindfully</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 04:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tips-for-living-mindfully/</guid><description>Mindfulness is happiness. But you already know that. But what is mindfulness, beyond the abstract definition of “attentive, aware, or careful” that I gave in that other article? Being more mindful means tapping into all of your senses. If you’re more of a concrete person, here are a bunch of examples of how you can live a more mindful life.</description></item></channel></rss>