<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Perfection on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/perfection/</link><description>Recent content in Perfection on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 05:10:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/perfection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Guitar is My Pacifier. What’s yours?</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 05:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/my-guitar-is-my-pacifier/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, I wake up spooning my guitar. This comforts me, then I realize I could have destroyed it so it terrifies me, then I realize I didn’t destroy it so I’m comforted again. It’s a roller coaster. Other days, my guitar is the first thing I reach for in the morning. I’m still rubbing sleepies out of my eyes while I fingerpick a few notes and think about what I’m going to do with my day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I’m having a tumultuous day, or I’m feeling particularly down, or I feel like the world is broken, or if I run out of hummus ingredients, I’ll pick it up, pick some strings, and it will immediately pick me up. Sometimes I only need a few minutes, sometimes I need a couple of hours, but it always works. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guitar is my pacifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Today is Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/today-is-perfect/</guid><description>Nothing particularly special happened today. One could call it, for me, a fairly unremarkable Saturday. I woke up to some bad news, spent most of my day in a relatively lazy fashion behind my computer, didn’t experience many of my favorite things about Austin, and now, an hour before midnight, my day is winding down.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow Will Be Perfect</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 05:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tomorrow-is-perfect/</guid><description>I spent most of the day today horizontal. I slept a lot, napped a bit, and snoozed when I wasn’t doing one of those two things. Yesterday was the exact opposite. I was vertical, doing, and doing some more. Both days have been perfect.</description></item></channel></rss>