<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gender on Sam Killermann's Blog</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/gender/</link><description>Recent content in Gender on Sam Killermann's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:53:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/tags/gender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Me + Thailand = August ’15</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/thailand-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m excited for Thailand. I’ve heard so many amazing things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spoken with people who have immersed themselves in the culture, and had opportunities to reflect on things that were previously invisible in their lives. I know a couple people who have gone and never returned. That says a lot about a place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve talked with activists who are doing tremendous things in the worlds of gender liberation, sex worker advocacy, and social justice education. I’ve learned so much from them already, from afar, from email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gender Expression vs. Cueing, &amp; How Sometimes They’re One-in-the-Same</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/gender-expression-vs-cueing/</guid><description>Last week I gave three back-to-back shows at the Fashion Institute of Technology in New York. I was their “Diversity Speaker” for orientation, a product of some of the orientation leaders seeing me speak at a conference. I’ve said this a bunch: I loved doing those shows, and I heart FIT.</description></item><item><title>I’m Not Going To Teach You Anything New</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 05:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-not-going-to-teach-you-anything/</guid><description>That’s something one of my professors in grad school would lead off with in the first class of the semester. The class was about the effect of environments on people’s ability to learn, develop, and grow. After sixteen weeks, hours of discussion, papers, and reading an entire textbook, he was right.</description></item><item><title>The National Organization for Marriage Attempted to Write a Hate Piece About Me</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/national-organization-for-marriage-against-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/national-organization-for-marriage-against-me/</guid><description>Hey NOM,
Sam Killermann here. Or, as I’m being described on your Facebook Page, “Sin with Colored Pencils” here. I read the “blog post” you wrote about me and my “Genderbread Person.” To be “honest,” I couldn’t put together exactly what you were “trying” to say.</description></item><item><title>Genital Xenophobia and Genital Wanderlust: Show Me Yours and I’ll Show You Mine</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/genital-xenophobia-vs-genital-wanderlust/</guid><description>I remember the first time I played Show Me Yours I’ll Show You Mine. Some people call it Doctor. If you’ve never played, worry not: the rules are the simple. Show me yours. Then I show you mine. And who is the winner?</description></item><item><title>The Abusive Relationship We’re All In That Most of Us Never Think About</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 03:17:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/abusive-gender-stereotypes/</guid><description>I saw this wonderful commercial earlier today and shared it on Facebook immediately. Watch it, then let’s talk about it.
Obviously, these aren’t new ideas to me. I talk a lot about the proverbial boxes we are all smushed into.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m Glad Chivalry is Dead, From The Perspective of A Man Who Actually Likes Women</title><link>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 02:54:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samkillermannblog.netlify.com/im-glad-chivalry-is-dead/</guid><description>There’s this article, “Why Chivalry is Dead, From a Man’s Perspective,” from John Picciuto on _Elite Daily _that’s popped up in my Facebook newsfeed a lot. It’s been shared by my friends of varying genders with captions like “Amen” and “FTW” and “Finally.</description></item></channel></rss>